<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Guanajuato on Vagabondians</title>
    <link>http://vagabondians.com/tags/guanajuato/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Guanajuato on Vagabondians</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright &amp;#169; by Glenn and Dixie Dixon</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vagabondians.com/tags/guanajuato/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>On The Road Again</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/on-the-road-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/on-the-road-again/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; title=&#34;Bus Terminal&#34; src=&#34;https://fbcdn-sphotos-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash3/600165_10151896098365437_1236436281_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;550&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And now, at long last, the next phase of our journey begins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last few weeks have been busy. Our homeowner dropped in for a two-week stay and initiated a flurry of activity! We ran around getting automobile repair estimates and looking for replacement kitchen sinks and cleaning the house in preparation for the new property managers to take pictures. We also showed the home to a potential renter and took both dogs and both cats to the vet. In addition to that, we picked up some utensils and cookware and a portable electric stove top. We also got the house ready for the new housesitter and went over all of the details with her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whew!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://fbcdn-sphotos-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash4/376442_10151896099480437_403310213_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;540&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So Tuesday morning we had a driver pick us up and deliver us to the main bus station in eastern Guadalajara, near Tonala. We rode in amazing comfort on a Primera Plus coach and stopped only once. The whole trip lasted just over four hours. The seats lean back twice as far as on the standard economy fare airline seat, and they have footrests that fold down from the seat in front. Lights and air vents are overhead. Each seat has its own audio jack where you can listen to one of several stations or just pick up the audio from the on-board movie. I watched Transformers 2 in Spanish. Interesting. There are also men&amp;rsquo;s and women&amp;rsquo;s restrooms in the back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://fbcdn-sphotos-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash3/600382_10151896100380437_1848917125_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;540&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we stopped at Leon it began to rain, but by the time we were halfway to Guanajuato the skies had cleared. At one point our bus was selected (randomly?) for an inspection by some nice people from the Mexican army. The first one on board announced the inspection and seemed to generally calm everyone. He then walked through and inspected everyone&amp;rsquo;s bags and purses. I presume he was looking for weapons, drugs and/or explosives. And just in case you thought his calm demeanor was a sign of weakness, a second soldier stepped into the doorway and watched while resting his hand on the grip of his H&amp;amp;K G3 Battle Rifle. That&amp;rsquo;s a big gun!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://fbcdn-sphotos-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash4/306606_10151897024320437_59276117_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;540&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Very soon we were on our way again and we arrived in Guanajuato only slightly behind schedule. We took a taxi directly to our intended destination, the Hostel Alonso. We were so excited &amp;ndash; our very first night in a hostel! And so far it has not disappointed one bit. Our room is private and on the second floor. The shower is also the toilet. The toilets do not have seats. Supposedly this has something to do with scorpions, but I think I&amp;rsquo;d rather not know for sure&amp;hellip; The bed is just about as firm as it can get. We are, so far, sharing the facilities with two Japanese girls and two other couple from parts unknown. We are, also, unsurprisingly the oldest people in the building, by far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://fbcdn-sphotos-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash4/314072_10151896101395437_1880566886_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;540&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://fbcdn-sphotos-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash4/396623_10151896102090437_627351429_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;540&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://fbcdn-sphotos-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-snc7/376323_10151897024460437_1622543814_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We strolled the city a couple of times, mainly the area around the Jardin de la Union. We walked by Casa de Pita, the B&amp;amp;B we used on our first visit back in 2008. We bought a coca light and an agua at the nearby tienda just for old times sake. We had a decent dinner at a restaurant, a latte at a local coffee shop and picked up some drinks and snacks at an Oxxo convenience store. All set for the night!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://fbcdn-sphotos-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash3/530797_10151896104440437_57620121_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;540&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://fbcdn-sphotos-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-snc6/250820_10151896102585437_88422294_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;540&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is the rainy season in this part of Mexico. It starts in mid-June and ends later in the year. Normally they say that the rain arrives with San Antonio and departs with San Francisco. No, not the cities &amp;#8212; those are days honoring the saints. Dia de San Antonio is June 13, Dia de San Francisco is October 10. The rain started in Chapala right around June 11, and it hasn&amp;rsquo;t stopped since. Mostly it rains in the middle of the night, but here and there you get it during the day as well. It rained last night so hopefully we can walk around all day without worrying about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More pictures soon, and most will be added to Facebook. You can see the whole album here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&#34;Guanajuato&#34; href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/media/set/?set=a.10151896097500437.874894.648515436&amp;type=1&amp;l=8d63902558&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Guanajuato&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Death and Beyond in Guanajuato, Mexico</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/death-and-beyond-in-guanajuato-mexico/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/death-and-beyond-in-guanajuato-mexico/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So Wednesday morning, July 4, we awoke early and went to breakfast at Casa Ofelia. We appeared to be the first customers of the day. Soon after we sat down, a very small indigenous man in white traditional garb with a guitar on his back came in to pray and bless himself at the little altar of Mary just inside the front door. Then he began to play and sing &lt;em&gt;Besa Me Mucho&lt;/em&gt; at us. We were also his first customers of the day. Remembering what my Mexicana friend Tere had told me about the importance of the first customer and its influence on the way the day goes, we gave him a few pesos. The next customers rebuffed him and he left after kissing a few more pictures on the wall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; title=&#34;Seranade&#34; src=&#34;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_m6o4w2d0NO1qzu24w.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our breakfast was quite tasty, and then we were on our way &amp;ndash; to see a museum full of mummified corpses under glass, at least one of which is believed to have been accidentally buried alive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Guanajuato is famous for its Museo de las Momias where over 100 naturally mummified bodies are on display, many of which were buried during a cholera outbreak in 1833. They were disinterred between 1865 and 1958 when families failed to pay the yearly tax to keep them in the mausoleum (later the law changed and they quit pulling them out). At some point workers started charging a few pesos to see them, and the famous museum was born.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_m6pttyubpl1qzu24w.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dry climate and conditions in the mausoleum dried and preserved many bodies before they could decay.  The skin even shows the pores and texture, and much of the hair is there &amp;ndash; some in disturbing places.  Many are still clothed, at least partially.  So many have no clothing, and I wonder if they were just buried naked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ignacia Aguilar-Chirilo suffered from catalepsy, which made her heart appear to stop for long periods. During one of these incidents in 1922, her heart appeared to stop for more than the usual time so she was declared dead and her relatives decided to bury her. When her body was disinterred, her arms were over her head instead of simply being crossed over the body. It appears she was biting her arm, and there were wounds on her forehead. Not how you want to wake up and spend your last minutes!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_m6o5yweO6h1qzu24w.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This museum also houses the smallest mummy in the world, along with its unfortunate mother. She was a victim of malnutrition and cholera and died when she was 6 months pregnant.  Her child is one of the most well-preserved mummies, according to the notes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_m6pebd7zrD1qzu24w.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;230&#34; /&gt;  &lt;img src=&#34;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_m6peg8oEHS1qzu24w.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;230&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_m6pqisFQgi1qzu24w.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;230&#34; /&gt;  &lt;img src=&#34;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_m6pqodtMfj1qzu24w.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;230&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the babies were lovingly dressed and accessorized for burial.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_m6pqthJVMn1qzu24w.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;230&#34; /&gt;  &lt;img src=&#34;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_m6pr18tOC21qzu24w.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;  &lt;img src=&#34;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_m6pr61mtzs1qzu24w.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The broom is for one of the saints, I believe.  The one wearing rubber pants looks like it was a much later burial.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But enough with all the death.  Before we went to the mummy museum, we got waylaid by a tour hawker with a nice private walking tour in English. Our guide, Manuel, has lived all his life in Guanajuato, and is a very young and energetic 71.  He even told us about how he and a couple of his altar boy friends found a secret passage under one of the cathedrals that contained torture devices from the Inquisition and some old paintings that were probably ordered destroyed but were hidden instead.  One is of a pregnant Virgin Mary and now hangs in the foyer of the church.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_m6prjfYJoR1qzu24w.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Manuel said that the priest caught the already spooked boys when they came up from the passage. He told them they must never, ever speak of it or they would go to hell.  He never did, at least until that priest died.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The highlight of Guanajuato for me, both this trip and back in 2008, are the nightly singing tours to the Alley of the Kiss. Students at the University of Guanajuato (estudiantinas) dress like troubadours and sing and play instruments and clown around and give a very entertaining tour.  Since the old part of the city is shaped like a bowl you can hear their wonderful male voices everywhere. The tours start outside the 2nd most beautiful theater in all of Mexico, Teatro Juarez.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_m6ps6prOak1qzu24w.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;230&#34; /&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_m6pswnPp931qzu24w.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;230&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was so much to see and take pictures of, but I think this post is already long enough. To see more, pop on over to this &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/media/set/?set=a.10151091058738993.491801.677503992&amp;amp;type=3&#34;&gt;public link on Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and see the best photos and their descriptions!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>