<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sixmonths on Vagabondians</title>
    <link>http://vagabondians.com/categories/sixmonths/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sixmonths on Vagabondians</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright &amp;#169; by Glenn and Dixie Dixon</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vagabondians.com/categories/sixmonths/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>The International Crane Foundation -- Baraboo, Wisconsin</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/international-crane-foundation-baraboo-wisconsin/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/international-crane-foundation-baraboo-wisconsin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Of all the things that Aldo Leopold wrote about, I was most interested in his observations about birds. He is possibly most well-known for the things he wrote about Cranes. In my &lt;a href=&#34;http://vagabondians.com/776/leopold-center-baraboo-wisconsin/&#34;&gt;previous article&lt;/a&gt; on our visit to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://aldoleopold.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Aldo Leopold Center&lt;/a&gt; I quoted Leopold&amp;rsquo;s famous Marshland Elegy about Sandhill Cranes. We saw a few of these amazing birds on our way to the Center that day. But a day later we saw all fifteen Crane species in one place!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is no coincidence that the &lt;a href=&#34;http://savingcranes.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;International Crane Foundation&lt;/a&gt; is located less than seven miles from Aldo Leopold&amp;rsquo;s famous shack. The two founders met at Cornell and one of them grew up birding on Leopold&amp;rsquo;s property. The Foundation breeds cranes in captivity to repopulate the species, especially the whooping crane, which at one point was down to 22 birds in the wild. They also work with &lt;a href=&#34;http://operationmigration.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Operation Migration&lt;/a&gt; to reintroduce migrating flocks to Florida.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some pictures we took when we visited back in September, 2011.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Photos coming soon!]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy New Year! Time&#39;s A&#39;wastin&#39;!</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/happy-year-times-awastin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/happy-year-times-awastin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I read this from a Facebook friend:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My wish for everyone in 2012 - &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;../images/2011/12/fireworks.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
12 months of happiness&lt;br /&gt;
52 weeks of fun&lt;br /&gt;
365 days success&lt;br /&gt;
8760 hours good health&lt;br /&gt;
52600 minutes good luck&lt;br /&gt;
3153600 seconds of joy !!&lt;br /&gt;
Happy New Year&amp;rsquo;s Eve Hugs !!! ♥&lt;br /&gt;
{: style=&amp;ldquo;text-align: center;&amp;rdquo; }&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../images/2011/12/bored-baby.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
{: align=&amp;ldquo;left&amp;rdquo; }
Sounds nice!  But I started thinking about it:  8760 hours in a year.  Not all that many when you think of a whole year.  How many do I just WASTE of my LIFE?  This is my most important asset we&amp;rsquo;re talking about here:  MY LIFE!  Only one time around, no do-overs.  How much time do I spend these days just sitting in front of my computer basically doing absolutely nothing?  Not fun, not productive, just nothing; boredom?  That just totally SCARED me!  I&amp;rsquo;m no spring chicken anymore.  Can I afford to just throw that many hours away?  Trash.  Nothing.  Can I?  Can you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I thought, well, you have to subtract 8 per day for sleeping/staring into space/hoping to sleep, and it&amp;rsquo;s only 5840.  Then you have to spend, say,  1.25 hours in the bathroom a day:  5384.  Then there&amp;rsquo;s time eating/cooking/cleaning the kitchen and dishes, say 2 hrs a day:  4654.  Over a whole year, I only have about 4654 hours to LIVE.  That&amp;rsquo;s only 12.75 hours a day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../images/2011/12/old-celebrate.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
{: align=&amp;ldquo;right&amp;rdquo; }
When I get to my death bed (presuming nothing sudden happens early), will I say, Wow, I sure wish I&amp;rsquo;d worked more hours, spent more time playing computer games, spent more time in virtual space doing whatever, spent more time just &amp;ldquo;resting&amp;rdquo;?  No I will not!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SO&amp;hellip;.I hereby apologize to myself for all my wasted time in this one life I have been allotted &amp;ndash; apology accepted &amp;ndash; and I resolve to spend my time more wisely.  I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t just flush dollars for no reason, would I?  No, I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t.  Life is so much more valuable than money.  You can always make more money.  You can never make more life or more time.  Spent is spent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HAPPY NEW LIFE, EVERYBODY!  What will you do with this year?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Leopold Center -- Baraboo, Wisconsin</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/leopold-center-baraboo-wisconsin/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/leopold-center-baraboo-wisconsin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dixie has always loved nature and wildlife. As a child, she thought nothing of picking up a skunk by the tail and bringing it home for a pet. (Strangely enough, her mother let her keep it!) In high school and college she developed an interest in herpetology and had quite a succession of snakes as pets. It was quite natural, therefore, that she fell in love with her first copy of Sand County Almanac.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vagabondians.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/12/Sand_county_almanac.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignleft size-medium wp-image-832&#34; title=&#34;Sand_county_almanac&#34; src=&#34;http://vagabondians.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/12/Sand_county_almanac.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;198&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;This book by Aldo Leopold made quite an impression on her. Aldo&amp;rsquo;s writing was captivating. He is generally considered to be one of our nation&amp;rsquo;s first environmentalists. His work in science, ecology and forestry was seminal. Eventually, Dixie would graduate from Texas A&amp;amp;M with a degree from the Wildlife and Fisheries department.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She still had this book when we married in 1990. When I eventually got around to reading it, it was an eye-opener. It jolted my understanding of things  as simple as what &amp;lsquo;nature&amp;rsquo; was. I had generally viewed wide swaths of ranch and farm land in Texas as natural. Sand County Almanac revealed the hidden history of land use to me. It was difficult to picture what the original prairie grasses and trees might have looked like to the original pioneers who arrived, but this book caused me to try. It also sparked in me a love for wildlife, birds in particular. We still have this book, although I&amp;rsquo;m not sure it is going to make it to South America with us. However, I have always remembered his description of the dusk skydance of the woodcock, but perhaps his most memorable words were reserved for the sandhill crane when he wrote:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some day, perhaps in the very process of our benefactions, perhaps in the fullness of geologic time, the last crane will trumpet his farewell and spiral skyward from the great marsh. High out of the clouds will fall the sound of hunting horns, the baying of the phantom pack, the tinkle of little bells, and then a silence never to be broken, unless perchance in some far pasture of the Milky Way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; title=&#34;Sandhill Cranes in the wild&#34; src=&#34;https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-OJgp7B5HNgY/Tq6EQux4EXI/AAAAAAAACsc/yu1RhY_3Fx4/s1024/P1160433.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;717&#34; height=&#34;403&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Leopold began his own wildlife restoration project near Baraboo, there were only 25 pairs of nesting Sandhill Cranes left in the entire state of Wisconsin. To this day I am unable to read that passage out loud without getting a bit choked up. Such is the power of the words and imagery of Aldo Leopold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shortly before we left on our RV journey in April of 2011 we found out that a new documentary about Leopold would be shown in Farmer&amp;rsquo;s Branch. Green Fire was a great overview of Leopold&amp;rsquo;s life and work, and a nice sendoff for our trip. It also made us aware of the Leopold Center in Baraboo, Wisconsin. Another pin appeared on our trip map.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; title=&#34;The Leopold Center&#34; src=&#34;https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-eXh_rErlZBI/Tq6ErYAy0BI/AAAAAAAACdE/ibZ75htwFDQ/s800/SAM_1021.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;800&#34; height=&#34;600&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, on September 12th we arrived. We spoke with the volunteers manning the center&amp;rsquo;s front desk and wandered around the facilities. We admired the form and function of the buildings and its zero-carbon footprint. We learned from a display that Leopold now has only one remaining daughter. We also discovered that the center provided bicycles for the short trip down the road to Leopold&amp;rsquo;s old cabin. Dixie was rather insistent, so we took the ride and strolled around the cabin, trying to imagine what it would have looked like back in the 1935 when Leopold acquired the land and began one of the nation&amp;rsquo;s first ecological restoration projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; title=&#34;Dixie enjoying the ride&#34; src=&#34;https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-i6tKTgYowZU/Tq6EXvoxaxI/AAAAAAAACcY/Zq6_Fo9wFTk/s1024/P1160460.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;573&#34; height=&#34;323&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We soaked it in. We walked to the river&amp;rsquo;s edge through deep sand. We hiked through the trees. Dixie spent time sitting on a small bench in front of the shack. I used the outhouse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; title=&#34;Dixie soaks it in&#34; src=&#34;https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-ZSLQ450bjbw/Tq6EUFmHv1I/AAAAAAAACsw/wYLFtISPgD4/s1024/P1160445.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;717&#34; height=&#34;403&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We thoroughly enjoyed our time there. I could write forever and never describe this place adequately. Kenneth Brower, however, wrote eloquently about the shack and Leopold in 2001 in the Sierra Club magazine, and I could add nothing to his eloquence. Give it a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sierraclub.org/sierra/200101/leopold.asp&#34;&gt;read here&lt;/a&gt;. You won&amp;rsquo;t regret it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the full album of photos:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table style=&#34;width: 194px;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td style=&#34;height: 194px; background: url(&#39;https://picasaweb.google.com/s/c/transparent_album_background.gif&#39;) no-repeat left;&#34; align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
      &lt;a href=&#34;https://picasaweb.google.com/dixonge/TheLeopoldCenter?authuser=0&amp;feat=embedwebsite&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;margin: 1px 0 0 4px;&#34; src=&#34;https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-_Dt7pg-glMw/Tq6EQAF7YmE/AAAAAAAACtU/eOEhzY75_oM/s160-c/TheLeopoldCenter.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;160&#34; height=&#34;160&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center; font-family: arial,sans-serif; font-size: 11px;&#34;&gt;
      &lt;a style=&#34;color: #4d4d4d; font-weight: bold; text-decoration: none;&#34; href=&#34;https://picasaweb.google.com/dixonge/TheLeopoldCenter?authuser=0&amp;feat=embedwebsite&#34;&gt;The Leopold Center&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anywhere in Texas, RFD</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/texas-rfd/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/texas-rfd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sorry, I just really, REALLY love that old Louis Prima song.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And yes, we&amp;rsquo;re back in Texas! I sometimes forget that not everyone is following along via Facebook and Twitter. But you really should! That is where you get the latest updates, the minutiae.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously I have not been very good at keeping up with the photos and travel tales. So many to do! But I have some ideas rattling around in my head about how to catch up and keep up, and we&amp;rsquo;re gonna need it! Oh my, the plans we have&amp;hellip;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, as I think you probably already know, we are planning on staying here for a couple of months. We will see my parents and brother, and we have lots of friends to reunite with and catch up on. Dixie is already planning a weekend with her bestest friend in the world for her friend&amp;rsquo;s birthday. Big girls&amp;rsquo; night out with the Jazzercise gang too. We also have friends everywhere from south Arlington to Denton to see again. Wine Squared, I&amp;rsquo;m thinking of you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then there&amp;rsquo;s the work part. We&amp;rsquo;ve emptied the pop-up, now we need to clean and sell it. We also have lots of camping crap to sell, and eventually we&amp;rsquo;ll sell the SUV too. And then we hop on a plane with a one-way ticket to&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, that&amp;rsquo;s a good question, isn&amp;rsquo;t it? Frankly it all depends. One part of our overall plan that has changed a little bit is that we are going to further increase our fun factor while reducing our expenses by housesitting! And so our next destination really depends on which housesitting opportunities work out first. Maybe Lake Chapala in central Mexico? And we probably have something lined up for Costa Rica in July or August. We get to use someone&amp;rsquo;s house, and they don&amp;rsquo;t have to worry about the house looking vacant. Pets get fed and walked, lawns get watered. It&amp;rsquo;s a win-win!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that&amp;rsquo;s all for now, stay tuned for updates!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And for those unfamiliar check out the amazing Louis Prima and his crazy &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0013AJBK6/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B0013AJBK6&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=selfservehost-20&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Anywhere In Texas, RFD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wisconsin and the Dells</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/wisconsin-dells/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/wisconsin-dells/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Wisconsin had some very interesting things to see, like highway signs, and upside-down buildings&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table style=&#34;width: 194px;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td style=&#34;height: 194px; background: url(&#39;https://picasaweb.google.com/s/c/transparent_album_background.gif&#39;) no-repeat left;&#34; align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
      &lt;a href=&#34;https://picasaweb.google.com/dixonge/Wisconsin?authuser=0&amp;authkey=Gv1sRgCIyPnd6Ds_6KXQ&amp;feat=embedwebsite&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;margin: 1px 0 0 4px;&#34; src=&#34;https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-qto05vm-AvA/Tq6EsamDhPE/AAAAAAAACbo/51fb8SREEJA/s160-c/Wisconsin.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;160&#34; height=&#34;160&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center; font-family: arial,sans-serif; font-size: 11px;&#34;&gt;
      &lt;a style=&#34;color: #4d4d4d; font-weight: bold; text-decoration: none;&#34; href=&#34;https://picasaweb.google.com/dixonge/Wisconsin?authuser=0&amp;authkey=Gv1sRgCIyPnd6Ds_6KXQ&amp;feat=embedwebsite&#34;&gt;Wisconsin&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minnesota -- It&#39;s Flat!</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/minnesota-its-flat/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/minnesota-its-flat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We first met our wine-making friends Del and Kat Erickson in 2007 when Kat and her daughter Jessica came to Texas for Winestock. Since we were fairly nearby we veered a bit north and dropped in for a visit. We got to see their house, her husband Del&amp;rsquo;s farm, daughter Jessica&amp;rsquo;s family in Grand Forks, ND and much more. Enjoy the slideshow, read the captions!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Almost Canada -- Wyoming to Minnesota</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/canada-wyoming-minnesota/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/canada-wyoming-minnesota/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On September 2, we finally left Wyoming and headed for northern Minnesota. The first night we made it as far as eastern Montana. On the way, we passed what is possibly the funniest high school mascot we&amp;rsquo;ve ever seen!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; title=&#34;Belfry bats&#34; src=&#34;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-BX5sD-eeo7E/TpGEjARN9_I/AAAAAAAAB_g/irZYeajEIRI/s640/SAM_0738.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;480&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; title=&#34;a bat!&#34; src=&#34;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-VUy2vNPYsXg/TpGElPZV6bI/AAAAAAAAB_k/I-v2fSRhqv4/s640/SAM_0739.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;480&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But then, if your town is named Belfry, what else are you going to have for a mascot? LOL&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We stayed in Eastern Montana for the first night, then headed East in the morning. It was the first ever visit for both of us to North Dakota, another first in a long line of firsts for us on this trip! Also, we&amp;rsquo;re evidently close to Canada..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; title=&#34;Oh Canada!&#34; src=&#34;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-10XmcR4Vz6E/TpGEoStU-zI/AAAAAAAAB_o/RbaXEQKTU6A/s640/P1160426.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;480&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; title=&#34;West of what?&#34; src=&#34;https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/--24lmzpaPoc/TpGEqOcOk-I/AAAAAAAAB_s/vVmz1Y3zmhI/s640/SAM_0742.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;480&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve stopped at a lot of National Parks and Monuments on this trip. Almost all of them were planned ahead of time, but this one was a surprise &amp;ndash; Theodore Roosevelt National Park. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem like much of a park, but is evidently popular for horseback riding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; title=&#34;park sign&#34; src=&#34;https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-wEGE8Ia3meM/TpGExai1rKI/AAAAAAAAB_4/nwDdSj0yEl8/s640/SAM_0752.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;480&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; title=&#34;horsies!&#34; src=&#34;https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-upzOKbUF7A4/TpGE69G8kAI/AAAAAAAACAI/_GqbGEsovn8/s640/SAM_0757.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;480&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;North Dakota looks a whole lot like South Dakota, without the Black Hills and massive sculptures of Presidents and native warriors. Not to be outdone, this state has the &amp;ldquo;World&amp;rsquo;s Largest Metal Sculptures&amp;rdquo; which you can see by driving the almost 64-mile round trip of the &lt;a title=&#34;Enchanted Highway&#34; href=&#34;http://www.enchantedhighway.net/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Enchanted Highway&lt;/a&gt;. We opted out, but took a few pictures along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; title=&#34;Enchanted?&#34; src=&#34;https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/--r1x--78z2I/TpGE8aeqWnI/AAAAAAAACAM/RnXcomC-skQ/s640/SAM_0761.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;480&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; title=&#34;Geese&#34; src=&#34;https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-ljYdvn9z7DI/TpGE-t0OhUI/AAAAAAAACAQ/J--KbFhCvUY/s640/SAM_0764.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;480&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; title=&#34;Deer&#34; src=&#34;https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-Ib--kfKxBgg/TpGFDVER8fI/AAAAAAAACAY/229qmLtN4Js/s640/SAM_0766.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;480&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later, we passed the &amp;ldquo;World&amp;rsquo;s Largets Holstein Cow&amp;rdquo; near New Salem, ND. Great for a chuckle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; title=&#34;moo&#34; src=&#34;https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-QrTEb24xH60/TpGFIHJgwiI/AAAAAAAACAg/gLnfqWSYOSk/s640/SAM_0776.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;480&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; title=&#34;MOO!&#34; src=&#34;https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-EcC1hIpaVpA/TpGFKVSiCZI/AAAAAAAACAk/SDzeqe_bzj0/s640/SAM_0779.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;480&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We stopped for the night near Bismarck at a decent little park. When I went to switch the refrigerator from propane back over to electricity, I discovered a ton of red dirt had blown in while driving down I-90.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; title=&#34;Recession RV?&#34; src=&#34;https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-L0r2pMZ90GM/TpGFUSCSV9I/AAAAAAAACA4/pk2qZqbAs2w/s640/SAM_0786.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;480&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; title=&#34;dirt&#34; src=&#34;https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-Ak8pV7xZKYQ/TpGFYJw6mVI/AAAAAAAACBA/p1ePeYOAVRw/s640/IMG_0555.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;480&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day we finally made our way to the home of Kat and Del Erickson in Warren, Minnesota. Check that out on Google Maps, but take my word for it &amp;ndash; the next thing to the north is Canada. We&amp;rsquo;re way up here in the middle of NOwhere!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can see all the photos from this part of the trip here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table style=&#34;width: 194px;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td style=&#34;height: 194px; background: url(&#39;https://picasaweb.google.com/s/c/transparent_album_background.gif&#39;) no-repeat left;&#34; align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
      &lt;a href=&#34;https://picasaweb.google.com/dixonge/WyomingToMinnesota?authuser=0&amp;feat=embedwebsite&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;margin: 1px 0 0 4px;&#34; src=&#34;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-Kn2hIPMKjUc/TpGEgTBdjdE/AAAAAAAACDg/C0WSZVc_4gQ/s160-c/WyomingToMinnesota.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;160&#34; height=&#34;160&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center; font-family: arial,sans-serif; font-size: 11px;&#34;&gt;
      &lt;a style=&#34;color: #4d4d4d; font-weight: bold; text-decoration: none;&#34; href=&#34;https://picasaweb.google.com/dixonge/WyomingToMinnesota?authuser=0&amp;feat=embedwebsite&#34;&gt;Wyoming to Minnesota&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wyoming</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/wyoming/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/wyoming/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On the last day of August we packed up, cranked down the camper, hitched &amp;lsquo;er up and took off for our final trip through Yellowstone. Our route took us almost directly through the middle of the park and out the east gate. We proceeded east all the way to Cody, Wyoming, about 130 miles away. We got into town and set up camp and then Dixie contacted Deb, a classmate from high school!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She jumped on her scooter and her hubbie Mike got on his Harley and they came over for a visit. The next day after they got off work we met up and went to their favorite restaurant in town for some great wine and excellent food! The next morning we packed up again and took off for northern Minnesota, via Montana and North Dakota!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; title=&#34;Dessert!&#34; src=&#34;https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-2BYLxY0u2iU/TpEEJZo6R0I/AAAAAAAAB9o/Ir4lvgsmWSE/s640/SAM_0736.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;480&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; title=&#34;Salud!&#34; src=&#34;https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-SacjtWCN8VY/TpEEHWqq0eI/AAAAAAAAB9k/9awxDyVgpdM/s640/SAM_0735.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;480&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; title=&#34;group photo!&#34; src=&#34;https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-4k7OBnq9gb0/TpEELYoTZsI/AAAAAAAAB9s/YGZmE-VRDOI/s640/SAM_0737.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;480&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yellowstone</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/yellowstone/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/yellowstone/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We Arrive&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We drove in to the Yellowstone area from the NorthWest. It was pretty easy to find our destination, the &lt;a title=&#34;Wagon Wheel RV&#34; href=&#34;http://www.wagonwheelrv.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wagon Wheel RV park&lt;/a&gt;. Ken not only checked us in but pulled out a map and gave us a thorough overview of the park and the town. He drew lines and circled and annotated everything, including recommended businesses and complete mileage logs for each loop. It was a bit overwhelming at first, but proved to be invaluable later. It would be difficult to find a better park manager than this guy! We set up the trailer and took a brief stroll through town. Things were pretty quiet &amp;#8212; it was, after all, Sunday evening. Perfect! We love avoiding the crowds!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; title=&#34;Wagon Wheel RV Park&#34; src=&#34;https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-cejvCCUpVNc/ToIINCwCnLI/AAAAAAAAB0k/zVYBRuMqKR8/s640/SAM_0126.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;480&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We Explore&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Normally I would walk you through a daily blow-by-blow of when and where we visited, but for Yellowstone I am going to cover things by feature. Besides, I&amp;rsquo;m writing this almost a month after our visit there and my photo dates don&amp;rsquo;t seem to match up. So I&amp;rsquo;ll just start with an overview.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; title=&#34;Trying on hats at the gift shop&#34; src=&#34;https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-ilne9Q_NGjM/TlsM_9RdfPI/AAAAAAAABW8/jTCTV9J7NlE/s640/SAM_0137.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;480&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you ever heard of a Supervolcano? There is only one supervolcano area in the whole world that is on land &amp;#8212; that&amp;rsquo;s Yellowstone. Every 100,000 years or so these things go off in massive explosions. This is the kind of eruption that makes species go extinct. Unfortunately they don&amp;rsquo;t go fully, permanently dormant. So the entire Yellowstone region is sitting on top of this volcanic area. That is why there are regular earthquakes and tremors and lots of hot water bubbling up everywhere. And every time the earth quakes the water pathways are diverted. Old springs and geysers shift or dry up, new springs and geysers pop up or become more active. It&amp;rsquo;s enough to make the Park maintenance crew crazy I&amp;rsquo;m sure! Note: Mammoth Hot Springs is currently 85-90% dry in 2011. I don&amp;rsquo;t know if that will change, but keep it in mind when planning your trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hot Spots&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the first things you notice when approaching a hot spring or geyser is the smell. It&amp;rsquo;s hydrogen sulfide, a.k.a. that &amp;lsquo;rotten egg&amp;rsquo; smell. It&amp;rsquo;s not concentrated enough to be toxic, but whew! Stinky!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; title=&#34;Steam vent&#34; src=&#34;https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-VqwWt5uU004/ToINeGJSMJI/AAAAAAAAB1Q/HLsBCWgcvlw/s800/P1150364.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;800&#34; height=&#34;450&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the air is bubbling up slowly through water, you have a hot spring. You can find these all over the park. If the air flow is higher, you might end up with a geyser. Some geysers seem rather steady, but most oscillate. Some explode just a few times a year, others are very sporadic, and some go off on a regular schedule. It is rather surprising that &amp;lsquo;Old Faithful&amp;rsquo; still adheres to a regular schedule after over 100 years of observation. Many others are no longer active.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; title=&#34;Bubble bubble&#34; src=&#34;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-Aw10JKahfM4/ToIPo5cBxsI/AAAAAAAAB1k/99z-vFhAHBg/s800/P1150467.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;800&#34; height=&#34;450&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; title=&#34;Old Faithful&#34; src=&#34;https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-13Yz8wCYxTA/Tlx1kYzmSkI/AAAAAAAABX4/YIjZ50gKdEA/s640/P1150807.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;480&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have air coming up through mud, instead of water, you have a mud pot. The thick mud just bubbles and plops around. Very entertaining!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; title=&#34;Mud pot&#34; src=&#34;https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-pnQ0COYWExk/TmBlBdM2f7I/AAAAAAAABbo/qDTcaHwz_aQ/s800/P1150342.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;800&#34; height=&#34;450&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Water&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course there is plenty of non-heated water in the park as well. The Madison River is long and shallow and flat and a favorite of fly-fisherman. Most of the fishing occurs outside the park, but you saw guys in waders everywhere. The other main river is the Yellowstone, including the upper and lower falls and the Grand Canyon of the Yellowstone. This river begins at Yellowstone Lake, the largest freshwater lake above 7,000 feet in all of North America. Most of the lake freezes three feet thick in the winter, except for along the northern edge where several hot springs keep it open or thin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; title=&#34;Elk at Madison River&#34; src=&#34;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-gocWVHgRrdI/ToJNDYIPjOI/AAAAAAAAB2Q/WuKvzKLjTZg/s800/P1150576.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;800&#34; height=&#34;450&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; title=&#34;Lower Falls&#34; src=&#34;https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-JxY3fvwYIFo/TmQPBwMZ9jI/AAAAAAAABcs/h3Geg2eC51Y/s800/P1150607.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;800&#34; height=&#34;450&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; title=&#34;Crand Canyon of the Yellowstones&#34; src=&#34;https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-wjIPbJa-KgU/ToJNXAojsKI/AAAAAAAAB2U/LvBwFYioQg8/s800/P1150595.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;800&#34; height=&#34;450&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wildlife&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The average visitor to Yellowstone is going to see mainly three species of wildlife. One is the Osprey, which are plentiful. Unfortunately most people won&amp;rsquo;t even notice them. Another is the elk, which are a frequent cause of traffic jams. The third is the bison, which are everywhere. Unfortunately we had already seen very good examples of each on our trip, so there really wasn&amp;rsquo;t that much new wildlife for us in the park. Fortunately there are a couple of places in the park which have populations wolves and grizzly bears, so we headed for the east side to check out Lamar and Hayden valleys. Our first trip was rather uneventful. We saw a massive bison heard in the distance at Lamar Valley, but that&amp;rsquo;s about it. We briefly scanned the Hayden Valley treeline but saw no wolves or bears.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; title=&#34;Osprey nest&#34; src=&#34;https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-_WJm-89_1jo/TmQRO6qZCxI/AAAAAAAABc0/kX8aHAaYDGQ/s640/P1150666.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;480&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day I got a great tip from Kevin Sanders, a.k.a. &lt;a title=&#34;Bearman&#34; href=&#34;http://www.yellowstone-bearman.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Bearman&lt;/a&gt;. He runs a tour guide service and is possibly more familiar with the park than anyone else, including rangers! He posted an update on his &lt;a title=&#34;Bearman&#39;s Yellowstone Outdoor Adventures&#34; href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/BearmansYellowstoneOutdoorAdventures&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Facebook page&lt;/a&gt; and mentioned some wolves feasting on a carcass. We had missed them! But he indicated that they would probably be there again the next day, and sure enough they were! Unfortunately, they were WAY off in the distance, about a mile from the road. Our binoculars and camera zoom were insufficient for much detail. But we DID get a hot tip from one of the other wolf watchers. He said that just to our south a grizzly bear was munching on a carcass really close to the road! Soon we were in our car.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; title=&#34;Bison in Lamar Valley&#34; src=&#34;https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-ZGeq8Nm2eOM/TmQam_Dy7PI/AAAAAAAABdg/CFBC-tHC1i4/s640/P1150734.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;480&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we arrived there was a tremendous traffic jam. We parked in the first open area and walked down the road to where all the action was. And there it was! WOW that thing was close! We estimated that it was about 75 feet off the road. Normally it is NOT safe to be that close to a grizzly! Fortunately he was busy eating and was in a grove of trees so he felt protected. We took a lot of photos and video, but eventually the rangers pushed the crowds to the left and right away from the bear, ending any sort of good viewing. We were so excited to be able to see this beast from such a short distance!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; title=&#34;Grizzly Bear&#34; src=&#34;https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-pDT6hgq0j3w/Tl21z-cUUjI/AAAAAAAABY8/M0X_xz83nhk/s800/P1160331.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;800&#34; height=&#34;450&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scenery&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to see all of these things in Yellowstone, you have to drive. You drive a lot! Most of the major features are on two main loops. The northern loop is about 70 miles, the southern loop is 96 miles. This doesn&amp;rsquo;t include the roads in and out of the different exits, each anywhere from 5 to 30 miles long. In other words, there is a lot of ground to cover! You can see most of the main features from your car or by taking short hikes on well-traveled paths. You can also take long hikes cross-country, but just be sure to go in groups and take plenty of bear spray. Two different people lost their lives to grizzly bears this year, neither had any bear spray and one was hiking solo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; title=&#34;View from hill above the Artists Paint Pots area&#34; src=&#34;https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-AKrVFeRHasQ/ToINonNzA9I/AAAAAAAAB1U/9k1I7kN0jNI/s800/P1150371.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;800&#34; height=&#34;450&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But in addition to the main features, there is also a lot of scenery. There are many locations in the park where it seems like you can see forever. Blue skies, green trees, brown grasses, water of blue and green and orange even! All of this makes for a lot of beauty to take in, so plan ahead and do just that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; title=&#34;Madison River at sunset&#34; src=&#34;https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-waLC0vGwHp4/TlxntxG0tkI/AAAAAAAABXc/eLAA4vMr4gI/s640/SAM_0387.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;480&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we first planned our trip, Yellowstone was on the map but neither of us thought of it as a highlight. I was more excited about the tall trees of California, Dixie was rather fixated on Yosemite. But Yellowstone got our attention and held it, its beauty and wildness proving why it was the World&amp;rsquo;s first National Park.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are 73 photos in this photo album &amp;ndash; see the whole thing here!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(click the picture below)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table style=&#34;width: 194px;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td style=&#34;height: 194px; background: url(&#39;https://picasaweb.google.com/s/c/transparent_album_background.gif&#39;) no-repeat left;&#34; align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
      &lt;a href=&#34;https://picasaweb.google.com/dixonge/Yellowstone?authuser=0&amp;feat=embedwebsite&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;margin: 1px 0px 0px 4px;&#34; src=&#34;https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/---py-F7BEqQ/TlsM-lDDKlE/AAAAAAAAB6c/PJ3soCK9Nts/s160-c/Yellowstone.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;160&#34; height=&#34;160&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center; font-family: arial,sans-serif; font-size: 11px;&#34;&gt;
      &lt;a style=&#34;color: #4d4d4d; font-weight: bold; text-decoration: none;&#34; href=&#34;https://picasaweb.google.com/dixonge/Yellowstone?authuser=0&amp;feat=embedwebsite&#34;&gt;Yellowstone&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Under the Big Sky</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/big-sky/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/big-sky/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So eventually we reached our destination in St. Regis and stayed there a couple of nights, catching up on laundry, rest, reading and writing. We then made our way to Deer Lodge, again staying two nights. Finally we drove south to West Yellowstone which we intended to use as a base for our Yellowstone explorations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; title=&#34;Welcome to Montana&#34; src=&#34;https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-0Y4eE1w7IE8/Tmose5yEmSI/AAAAAAAABts/5I-araGR2o0/s640/P1150216.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;480&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wondered where the motto &amp;ldquo;Big Sky&amp;rdquo; came from. Obviously there are wide-open vistas here, but the same could be said for many places west of the Mississippi River. As it turns out, it started with a novel. A.B. Guthrie wrote a six-novel series of historical fiction on the settling of Montana, from 1830 to the beginning of World War I. The first novel of the series was sent to the publisher untitled. The editor read through it and the accompanying biographical notes and came across an exclamation from Guthrie&amp;rsquo;s father when he first arrived at Choteau, Montana: &amp;ldquo;standing under the big sky I feel free.&amp;rdquo; The editor chose &amp;ldquo;Big Sky&amp;rdquo; as the title. And in 1961 Guthrie gave the state permission to use it for tourism, and the phrase has stuck ever since!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; title=&#34;Wheat&#34; src=&#34;https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-gdzNIRwwX8k/TniFAVYzPkI/AAAAAAAABzs/kCHPtgZUvbY/s640/P1150271.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;480&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; title=&#34;Man&#39;s attempt to keep snow drifts off of the freeways&#34; src=&#34;https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-BPgC5ompLOc/TniFXTEOWyI/AAAAAAAABzw/3kn8zy67eVE/s640/P1150273.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;480&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The western half of Montana has a lot of mountains and passes. Once we cleared most of those we headed south for West Yellowstone. The drive was very scenic. Mountains with snow, valleys, plains, meadows. Not very many people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; title=&#34;Mountains&#34; src=&#34;https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-IZ-0cuVZzR8/TniGf7vmrlI/AAAAAAAABz8/AlhsELxbiwk/s640/P1150282.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;480&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click the picture below to see the slide show!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table style=&#34;width: 194px;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td style=&#34;height: 194px; background: url(&#39;https://picasaweb.google.com/s/c/transparent_album_background.gif&#39;) no-repeat left;&#34; align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
      &lt;a href=&#34;https://picasaweb.google.com/dixonge/Montana?authuser=0&amp;feat=embedwebsite&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;margin: 1px 0 0 4px;&#34; src=&#34;https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-ZJePR6iCWnI/TmoseGqDoGE/AAAAAAAAB0A/FmQg5vkPZUI/s160-c/Montana.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;160&#34; height=&#34;160&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center; font-family: arial,sans-serif; font-size: 11px;&#34;&gt;
      &lt;a style=&#34;color: #4d4d4d; font-weight: bold; text-decoration: none;&#34; href=&#34;https://picasaweb.google.com/dixonge/Montana?authuser=0&amp;feat=embedwebsite&#34;&gt;Montana&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Washington to Montana</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/washington-montana/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/washington-montana/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We finally bid farewell to Rand and Angie and packed up for our departure from Seattle. Before we actually hit the road, we borrowed some caulk from the garage and recaulked the main seam down the middle of the roof. It had developed a small hole and water tended to puddle right near this hole. Fortunately we have experienced almost no rain on the entire trip so far!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; title=&#34;This is how Glenn does roof repair!&#34; src=&#34;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-aR-zTcfqnH8/TmexY-34xZI/AAAAAAAABrc/9mwUaHNywkc/s640/P1150047.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;507&#34; height=&#34;381&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We drove south and then east on I-90. After passing through the Cascades we entered the great Columbia Plateau, a large depression where so much of the earth&amp;rsquo;s mantle flooded out in great lava flows that the crust eventually collapsed downward. A massive earth-scale turning of the soil, if you will. It is now a semi-arid savanna full of grasses and shrubs. I was a bit surprised as it reminded me of parts of New Mexico. Not exactly what I was expecting in the great Pacific Northwest!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We crossed the Columbia River at a small lake created by the Wanapum dam near Vantage. Shortly after our crossing, we took a scenic turnout and snapped a few pictures of the river below. A bonus was the wild horse sculpture on a nearby hillside! We stayed one night in an RV park near Moses Lake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; title=&#34;Vantage Bridge on I-90&#34; src=&#34;https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-rUOv9gAaoxY/TmexdJql8iI/AAAAAAAABro/Z1FGnzaBUy4/s640/P1150068.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;518&#34; height=&#34;389&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; title=&#34;Horse sculpture&#34; src=&#34;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-bNcZZNlh5BQ/TmexfSsuETI/AAAAAAAABrw/zqWtS7VCtOc/s640/P1150075.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;512&#34; height=&#34;384&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next morning we packed again and took off, stopping after only 17 miles in Moses Lake itself. We got gas and breakfast, and upon returning to the vehicle I noticed that I had left the AC power adapter for the Coleman cooler on top of the Montero. Oops! Somehow it had managed to stay put. Disaster averted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; title=&#34;oops&#34; src=&#34;https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-MsqS7mtOiJ0/Tmexg5bN8wI/AAAAAAAABpA/3XeUGHEMhtQ/s640/IMG_0544.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;512&#34; height=&#34;384&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eastern Washington had another surprise for us, dust devils! And unlike most of these we typically see in Texas or New Mexico, these were tall rope-like funnels. They were very reminiscent of landspouts, just without the clouds above. At one point we saw several of these all in one area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; title=&#34;Dust devil&#34; src=&#34;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-lH8nnWgVi2M/TmexjJaz1FI/AAAAAAAABr4/d8ZK-zEQBtw/s512/P1150081.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;384&#34; height=&#34;512&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Spokane we stopped to see someone whom I only knew only from the internet. Gregg Thurman was someone who introduced me to investing in options. He trades almost exclusively in Apple stock, so we share an interest in both investing and Mac gear. We stopped by his antique car restoration shop and he gave us a tour of his wonderful old cars, and his project Mustang/GT, as well as his awesome Ford GT, one of only 4000 ever made. We&amp;rsquo;re both talkers, so Dixie ended up wandering around and taking pictures. We only stayed for a couple of hours and then took off to the east since our destination for the night was in Montana!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; title=&#34;Dixie inspecting an antique&#34; src=&#34;https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-z7eqf5IdH1I/TmexmWhdEuI/AAAAAAAABsE/C09TpuOSw78/s640/P1150095.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;512&#34; height=&#34;384&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; title=&#34;Packard Clipper&#34; src=&#34;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-fySjTKtFQk0/Tmexse0KdzI/AAAAAAAABsc/I3gZIUb3rno/s640/P1150111.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;512&#34; height=&#34;384&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; title=&#34;Gregg and Glenn chatting&#34; src=&#34;https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-HktwjwH4saY/Tmex0_ff7cI/AAAAAAAABs4/h_zIZ5Gf_f8/s640/P1150125.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;512&#34; height=&#34;384&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; title=&#34;Ford GT&#34; src=&#34;https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-0I6AuuXdkgs/Tmex3mAisTI/AAAAAAAABtA/2lqFzGc2Iks/s640/P1150133.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;512&#34; height=&#34;384&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; title=&#34;Rear engine, with braces signed by many Ford motor sports luminaries&#34; src=&#34;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-limfW5iJdsY/Tmex8K6_NGI/AAAAAAAABtM/pKq8xSQ0oUM/s640/P1150143.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;512&#34; height=&#34;384&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, Idaho had other plans for us. We managed to bypass a big traffic jam in Spokane by visiting Gregg, but while we were in Idaho, just after going through the 4th of July pass, we ourselves were passed by three different State Troopers in a big hurry. Unfortunately the 4th of July Pass is also the last exit for six miles. Soon we passed a trooper setting out flares on the shoulder, lights flashing. And then we stopped. Eventually Dixie went walking down the road, rounding two curves, but she still couldn&amp;rsquo;t see what was stopping traffic up ahead. The word being passed back through the truckers was that a big rig had caught on fire. Great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; title=&#34;0 mph on I-90&#34; src=&#34;https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-xtBvPerBSJQ/TmeyD9qWwHI/AAAAAAAABrQ/ls1ph2QqyO8/s640/P1150207.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;512&#34; height=&#34;384&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the next hour we saw ambulances and wreckers come and go, and eventually we were moving again, slowly. Hope the driver got out in time!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; title=&#34;Looks like the entire cab behind the driver burned up&#34; src=&#34;https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-D0JqpgLsdLY/TmeyEz0yyjI/AAAAAAAABrU/WQu2R-enXgE/s640/P1150209.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;512&#34; height=&#34;384&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were obviously much later getting in to camp than we had anticipated. We had no cell phone service so I didn&amp;rsquo;t get the voice mail when the RV park tried to call us, but I later found Google Voice&amp;rsquo;s attempt to transcribe it! LOL&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; title=&#34;What kind of park???&#34; src=&#34;https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-cATaROyARC0/TmeyGrk06kI/AAAAAAAABrA/M5qe073RLKQ/IMG_0545.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; height=&#34;480&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately we made it in long before they closed the gates at 10PM. I was tired enough that we even stayed an extra night, just to recuperate. But we made it to Montana!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click the picture below to see the entire photo album!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table style=&#34;width: 194px;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td style=&#34;height: 194px; background: url(&#39;https://picasaweb.google.com/s/c/transparent_album_background.gif&#39;) no-repeat left;&#34; align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
      &lt;a href=&#34;https://picasaweb.google.com/dixonge/Washington?authuser=0&amp;feat=embedwebsite&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;margin: 1px 0 0 4px;&#34; src=&#34;https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-Kmur-ZrJODo/TmexXoCwdRE/AAAAAAAABv0/RfxPo62--q4/s160-c/Washington.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;160&#34; height=&#34;160&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center; font-family: arial,sans-serif; font-size: 11px;&#34;&gt;
      &lt;a style=&#34;color: #4d4d4d; font-weight: bold; text-decoration: none;&#34; href=&#34;https://picasaweb.google.com/dixonge/Washington?authuser=0&amp;feat=embedwebsite&#34;&gt;Washington&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seattle</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/seattle/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/seattle/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On August 10th we departed from the Mt. St. Helens area and drove north to Seattle. It was our first time here, and our first time to see our old friends Angie and Rand in their home. We backed in to their driveway and set up the trailer which fit perfectly behind their gate. Urban incognito.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While we were there we spent most evenings enjoying some fine dining. Rand even prepared his infamous pizza made from scratch twice! We also enjoyed some wine most evenings, as best I can remember. I still blame Rand for that one night, no matter what Angie says! &lt;img src=&#34;http://v2j.vagabondians.com/wp-includes/images/smilies/simple-smile.png&#34; alt=&#34;:)&#34; class=&#34;wp-smiley&#34; style=&#34;height: 1em; max-height: 1em;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also did some sightseeing. Rand took us to a nice spot with a great view of the bay and city. He also took us to see the troll! No, seriously, a troll. Big sculpture under a bridge. I&amp;rsquo;m still not really sure why someone would create such a thing, but it seemed to be a popular spot! And of course we went downtown to the Public Market, the famous place where people out in front of the fish stands take orders and toss them back to the guys behind the counter. For every one person placing an order, there are a hundred tourists standing around with their cameras waiting to get a picture. I was one of &amp;lsquo;em.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=273114556038705&amp;amp;#038;set=a.273113942705433.89527.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=273114556038705&amp;amp;#038;set=a.273113942705433.89527.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=273113996038761&amp;amp;#038;set=a.273113942705433.89527.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=273113996038761&amp;amp;#038;set=a.273113942705433.89527.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=273115096038651&amp;amp;#038;set=a.273113942705433.89527.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=273115096038651&amp;amp;#038;set=a.273113942705433.89527.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also got to do something a bit out of the ordinary, an underground tour! We followed our tour guide through a maze of alleys and basements, exploring what was the original street level before the city raised the streets several feet. Bank vaults, massage parlors, brothels, wooden sewage pipes, speakeasies&amp;hellip;in other words, all the cool places to hang out! It was all there. Very entertaining and interesting!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; title=&#34;Seattle Underground tour&#34; src=&#34;https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-tnA7IRaztmg/TmUtWuy3k7I/AAAAAAAABl4/uWjxtTuxO4M/s912/P1150007.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;912&#34; height=&#34;513&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=273115316038629&amp;amp;#038;set=a.273113942705433.89527.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=273115316038629&amp;amp;#038;set=a.273113942705433.89527.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mt. St. Helens</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/mt-st-helens/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/mt-st-helens/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mount St. Helens was not on my original list of things to do or see in Washington. But as things turned out, it was a good stopping point on the way to Seattle. So hey, why not, right? I mean, it&amp;rsquo;s a huge frickin&amp;rsquo; volcano! So we parked for a couple of nights at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.silvercovervresort.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Silver Cove RV Resort&lt;/a&gt; and took a day trip in to the Mount St. Helens National Volcanic Monument.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=271218176228343&amp;amp;#038;set=a.271218136228347.89161.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=271218176228343&amp;amp;#038;set=a.271218136228347.89161.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main visitors center is at the Johnston Ridge Observatory. In May of 1980, this was just another ridge, known as &amp;lsquo;Coldwater II,&amp;rsquo; and was being used by scientists to monitor the mountain, which had seen increasing seismic activity and steam-driven explosions. The location was 5.5 miles from the mountain, and was thought to be a relatively safe distance. David Johnston was stationed here for the USGS on May 18. At Spirit Lake, two amateur volcanologists had stayed behind at their own risk to take readings, and a local resident Harry Truman had refused to leave his Mt. St. Helens lodge on the edge of the lake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=271218279561666&amp;amp;#038;set=a.271218136228347.89161.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=271218279561666&amp;amp;#038;set=a.271218136228347.89161.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On May 17, a convoy of 35 frustrated homeowners were escorted into the restricted zone to gather personal belongings. Another such convoy was scheduled for the next day at 10AM. On May 18 at 8:32AM a 5.1 magnitude earthquake happened one mile under the mountain. David Johnston saw the northern face of Mt. St. Helens, which had been bulging for several days, simply collapse. 1,300 feet of the mountain plunged into the valley below, the largest landslide in recorded history. All snow and glacial ice melted instantly and the water mixed with rock and ash began racing towards Spirit Lake. Johnston got on the radio to the USGS in Vancouver, Washington. All they heard was &amp;ldquo;Vancouver! Vancouver! This is it!&amp;rdquo; Rock, ash and trees hit his position at over 500mph. His body has never been found.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two miles north of Johnston&amp;rsquo;s position, a ham radio observer named Gerry Martin saw Johnston disappear and transmitted &amp;ldquo;The camper and the car just over to the south of me are covered. It&amp;rsquo;s going to hit me too.&amp;rdquo; In all 57 people lost their lives to the blast that day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The landslide released the trapped gas which resulted in a huge explosion that flattened every tree within a 230 square mile area in 180 seconds. The flow of debris hit Spirit Lake and forced all of the water up into the hillsides. By the time the water returned, the new bottom of the lake was actually 100 feet higher than the previous lake&amp;rsquo;s surface! To this day it still has no fish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A 25-foot wall of debris, the bulk of the initial landslide, raced down the Toutle River. It destroyed 27 bridges on its way down to the Columbia River, 75 miles away. The normally 40-foot deep channel there was reduced to 17 feet and had to be dredged just to reopen normal shipping lanes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On our visit, we watched the movie at the visitors center and took a guided tour. Young Ranger Kelly was an excellent guide. Even though she was born eleven years after the eruption, she lost four relatives that day. The mountain has always fascinated her and obviously motivated her to study and learn about it. I guess by being up here for work and walking around every day, by being near the mountain, she feels closer to those who have gone on before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=271218612894966&amp;amp;#038;set=a.271218136228347.89161.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=271218612894966&amp;amp;#038;set=a.271218136228347.89161.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hiked the trail to a better view of Spirit Lake, then returned to our car. Like so many things on this trip, you simply can not comprehend the scale of the devastation and the beauty of the mountain without seeing it in person. We really enjoyed this little side trip!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=271218769561617&amp;amp;#038;set=a.271218136228347.89161.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=271218769561617&amp;amp;#038;set=a.271218136228347.89161.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=271218919561602&amp;amp;#038;set=a.271218136228347.89161.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=271218919561602&amp;amp;#038;set=a.271218136228347.89161.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a wonderful overview and lots of pictures of the Mt. St. Helens eruption and victims and survivors, check out the web site of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.columbian.com/news/mount-st-helens/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Daily Columbian&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/media/set/?set=a.271218136228347.89161.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/media/set/?set=a.271218136228347.89161.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oregon Coast</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/oregon-coast/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/oregon-coast/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On August 5th we left the California Redwoods behind and drove up the Oregon Coast. There were no national parks or big tourist draws, just nice scenery and lots of ocean views. We drove through Gold Beach and Port Orford. At Coos Bay we stayed one night at the Mill Casino RV Park and robbed that casino of $17.50 in winnings!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=279066408776853&amp;amp;#038;set=a.279066288776865.90807.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=279066408776853&amp;amp;#038;set=a.279066288776865.90807.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day we soldiered north again, hugging the coastline on Hwy. 101. We stopped for a couple of nights at Coyote Rock RV park behind Siletz Bay, on the river. We were invited to get in on the fresh crab action as someone knew someone down at Depoe Bay who had just hauled in a catch, but we declined. Besides, we have nothing to boil crab in, and these were big crabs! Dungeness. The next day we drove to Depoe Bay and had some awesome clam chowder at the Bay Walk Cafe. Actually, we ate their twice. The first time we got a small cup to go, then continued strolling the street. Later, after visiting the whale watching center and the rest of the shops, we stopped back by for lunch which included a nice bowl of the chowder. Delicious!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/TPXupV23zL8&#34;&gt;Bay Walk Cafe in Depoe Bay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=279067005443460&amp;amp;#038;set=a.279066288776865.90807.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=279067005443460&amp;amp;#038;set=a.279066288776865.90807.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also watched someone processing buckets of crabs. He had it down to a science, whacking the carapace off with usually just one blow, then tossing the body onto a stainless steel table. After he had about two dozen crab bodies on the table, still slowly wriggling in their death throes, he washed them off and tossed them into a large pot to boil. Fascinating. And yet having a job like that would probably be my worst nightmare&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=279341648749329&amp;amp;#038;set=a.279066288776865.90807.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=279341648749329&amp;amp;#038;set=a.279066288776865.90807.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later that day we drove back south of town and stopped at the Devil&amp;rsquo;s Punch Bowl State Park. This geographic feature is just a large hole in the rocks which empties at low tide but fills with angry, swirling water at high tide. There are several small gift shops and a winery here. The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dutchmanwinery.com/index.html&#34;&gt;winery&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; claim to fame is that all of their wines are fermented in open-top fermenters, with access to the sea salt air. Dixie did a tasting and liked their wines just fine!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=279342168749277&amp;amp;#038;set=a.279066288776865.90807.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=279342168749277&amp;amp;#038;set=a.279066288776865.90807.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that, we continued south and saw a sign and exited the highway to do something we had been intending to do ever since we first got to the Pacific: see a lighthouse! The Yaquina Head Outstanding Natural Area is run by the BLM, so our Access Pass got us in for no fee. (side note: we have saved over $200 this year on that pass!) This lighthouse has been in continuous operation since 1873, even during a long restoration from 2005-6, which included new glass panes and ironwork and paint. Staff are dressed in period costume (late 19th century) and we got to climb the large spiral staircase to the top! My mom has always had some sort of fascination with lighthouses, so I made sure I got some pictures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=279342985415862&amp;amp;#038;set=a.279066288776865.90807.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=279342985415862&amp;amp;#038;set=a.279066288776865.90807.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=279067508776743&amp;amp;#038;set=a.279066288776865.90807.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=279067508776743&amp;amp;#038;set=a.279066288776865.90807.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=279067718776722&amp;amp;#038;set=a.279066288776865.90807.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=279067718776722&amp;amp;#038;set=a.279066288776865.90807.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=279343458749148&amp;amp;#038;set=a.279066288776865.90807.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=279343458749148&amp;amp;#038;set=a.279066288776865.90807.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day we said goodbye to the Pacific Ocean and headed east, back to civilization. We rejoined I-5 in Portland and headed north, entering Washington State and eventually settling in for a couple of nights at the Silver Cove RV park, anticipating a day at Mt. St. Helens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/media/set/?set=a.279066288776865.90807.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/media/set/?set=a.279066288776865.90807.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Prairie Creek Redwoods State Park</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/exploring-prairie-creek-redwoods-state-park/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/exploring-prairie-creek-redwoods-state-park/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After our own big &amp;lsquo;day of discovery&amp;rsquo; with the Grove of Titans, the next day we moved on to Prairie Creek Redwoods State Park, home of some of the tallest Coast Redwoods. My hopes were not very high as the location of this grove is even more secret than the Grove of Titans. In addition, it is relatively easy to spot the huge misshapen behemoths that are the Titans when they are so much larger at ground level. In comparison, one of the tallest trees in the Atlas Grove is barely nine feet in circumference! Without our own expensive laser range finder or LIDAR unit it would be next to impossible to find this grove.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did hope for a glimpse of the Arco Giant which was supposedly visible from the meadow in front of the visitor center. I looked, but I did not find. In the meantime we checked out some park maps and decided to hike some of the trails. We started with a nice little half-mile loop that was supposed to be a simple nature trail. Unfortunately it wasn&amp;rsquo;t so simple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=277886715561489&amp;amp;#038;set=a.277885202228307.90476.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=277886715561489&amp;amp;#038;set=a.277885202228307.90476.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After crossing a small bridge, the trail was supposed to curve to the left then cross back over the creek again and lead back to the  visitor center. So we crossed the bridge and came to a sign which seemed to indicate that the nature trail went both left and right. I just assumed that perhaps the trail went a bit further than the map indicated so we turned left and marched on. The further we went, the more I began to notice some things. First, this trail did not seem to be as wide or well-worn as the other parts. Second, some downed limbs and even small trees had not been cleared from the trail. Third, we met no other hikers along the way. However, we did continue to see informational markers with various messages on them, so we continued on. Eventually we spied an RV on the other side of the creek. I knew that there was a campground over there, but I thought it was past the bridge we were looking for. Nevertheless, onward we pressed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=277889252227902&amp;amp;#038;set=a.277885202228307.90476.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=277889252227902&amp;amp;#038;set=a.277885202228307.90476.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually we concluded that we had hiked for a good mile and a half, perhaps two miles. I consulted the map again and discovered that the bridge we were looking for crossed the creek well &lt;em&gt;ahead&lt;/em&gt; of the camping area. We had flat out missed it somewhere. But rather than turn around, we decided to continue toward a bike trail that should have been just ahead. But it was not to be. The trail became fainter and more overgrown until it eventually just died out. It was an eerie feeling. We were deep in the woods, all alone. The large ferns spread up the hillsides among the giant hemlocks, the redwoods now conspicuously absent. We were wearing light jackets since the air was a bit cool and misty and the plants were shoulder high and sporting the occasional spider web, but inside we were drenched in sweat. We turned around for the march home. We tried one last shortcut at a spot where the creek was shallow and had just enough rocks and gravel to hop over, but there was no obvious trail there either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=277888068894687&amp;amp;#038;set=a.277885202228307.90476.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=277888068894687&amp;amp;#038;set=a.277885202228307.90476.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=277888598894634&amp;amp;#038;set=a.277885202228307.90476.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=277888598894634&amp;amp;#038;set=a.277885202228307.90476.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we retraced our route. I was more than a bit upset at the park for leaving this trail off the maps, yet not blocking it off at the entrance or somehow warning us off. But eventually we got back to the trailhead where we had first turned off, and that was when I looked at the sign from a different angle, and it all made sense. What had appeared to be a sign pointing right and left was actually a sign pointing down the trail and back up the trail in the direction we had originally come from. The trail we had taken actually had a signpost right in the middle of it, but the sign itself was missing. I&amp;rsquo;m betting it said something like &amp;ldquo;Trail Closed.&amp;rdquo; To further confuse matters, we had entered the nature trail from a completely different direction than I had intended. I thought it proceeded counter-clockwise from my position when in fact we were taking the clockwise route.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[NOTE: As it turns out, the trail we took is an abandoned section of what used to be a longer Nature Trail loop]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=277889802227847&amp;amp;#038;set=a.277885202228307.90476.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=277889802227847&amp;amp;#038;set=a.277885202228307.90476.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we went ahead and finished the nature trail. It was actually only one-half mile in length and took us back directly to the visitor center. After we got to the car, I changed shoes and I think shirts, then we had lunch on a bench and laughed at our stupid adventure. I decided I was done with trees for now, and we drove back to camp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=277890608894433&amp;amp;#038;set=a.277885202228307.90476.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=277890608894433&amp;amp;#038;set=a.277885202228307.90476.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/media/set/?set=a.277885202228307.90476.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/media/set/?set=a.277885202228307.90476.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>