<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tales From The Tiki Bar on Vagabondians</title>
    <link>http://vagabondians.com/categories/tales-from-the-tiki-bar/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tales From The Tiki Bar on Vagabondians</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright &amp;#169; by Glenn and Dixie Dixon</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vagabondians.com/categories/tales-from-the-tiki-bar/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Talking Points!</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/talking-points/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/talking-points/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vagabondians.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/spider.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignleft size-medium wp-image-2109&#34; alt=&#34;spider&#34; src=&#34;http://vagabondians.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/spider.jpg&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Being on the road, we meet a lot of new and interesting people from all over the world and have precious little time to get to know them, perhaps only the one day or evening to form a friendship. I am, and perhaps you are too, a little shy and often stumped for something to talk about. My culture is prone to be a bit distant and untrusting of new people and so I have always been hesitant to ask anything probing or personal and seem forward and nosy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I have been searching, and my favorite advice for getting someone to like you is to be interested in them rather than talking about yourself (thanks to a post by &lt;a title=&#34;Married With Luggage&#34; href=&#34;http://www.marriedwithluggage.com/2012/12/12/be-interested-really-interested/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Married with Luggage&lt;/a&gt;). That takes the pressure off me to talk and makes the subject something interesting for both of us. I also found a great article from Ash Ambirge at The Middle Finger Project called &lt;a title=&#34;Your Life in Six Words&#34; href=&#34;http://www.themiddlefingerproject.org/your-life-in-6-words/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Your Life In Six Words&lt;/a&gt;. As part of a survey of her clients, she asked a series of questions. I am including them here, as well as a small sample of the inspiring answers left by her readers. (For the complete list of answers, read &lt;a title=&#34;Your Life in Six Words&#34; href=&#34;http://www.themiddlefingerproject.org/your-life-in-6-words/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Ash&amp;rsquo; article&lt;/a&gt;) I think these kinds of questions way trump &amp;ldquo;where are you from&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;what do you do,&amp;rdquo; don&amp;rsquo;t you? And they open up all kinds of possibilities for keeping the convo going beyond small talk about the weather and whether you like this city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This first one is interesting and fun &amp;ndash; quick, six words for your life story! Kind of like a Haiku. What would yours be? Tell me in the comments!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In response to being asked to write a 6-word memoir summing up their lives:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Her beautiful mind kept her distant.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Took risks, found passion, followed dream.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am still figuring shit out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Took leap of faith, landed spectacularly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Soul searching sentimental crazypants. Dreams big.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wind in her hair, world&amp;rsquo;s her playground.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In response to what advice they’d give their future children:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When you feel safe somewhere, stretch your limits a bit, be a little wild. Then go somewhere new.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Love deeply. Laugh often. Find something you love to do. Be conscious. Give back. Send money.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be brave, have heart, do what you love, fuck conventional wisdom.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In response to what one of their greatest unfulfilled dreams is:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tour the world singing jazz.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have a month-long sabbatical in Thailand.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be able to financially support my mother. She was never a mother to me but it isn’t because she didn’t want to be. Her own tormented childhood led her to be eternally 9 years old &amp;amp; she still makes decisions as a child would. Her soul is (ultimately) kind and I want nothing more than to be able to give her a home but most importantly, the peace she’s never been able to give herself. Wow that was intense. But honest. I’m not a fan of phony small talk.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In response to being asked what they believe with all their heart:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The world is a beautiful place and all people are basically good.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mistakes are OK, but mediocrity isn’t. Failure to innovate is a death sentence.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Life’s too short to do work you hate and art can teach a soul how to sing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In response to a cause they’re really passionate about:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clean water for 3rd world countries.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creating a safe, accepting and compassionate world for LGBT youth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Animal cruelty and domestic violence. I REALLY wish those two things just didn’t exist.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In response to something they’re most proud of:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My three year old daughter. She is so intelligent and bright.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Co-writing my uni’s plan to lower carbon emissions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My motorcycle adventures. Vancouver CA to the beaches of Cabo San Lucas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In response to something they wonder if:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My parents will ever move out of South Dakota and into civilization like I did.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I should have gotten married at 22.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I should just pack it in, move to somewhere with a beach that never gets cold, and just be a bartender and swim in the ocean for the rest of my life.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blogsyapp.com/&#34;&gt;Posted with Blogsy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tales from the Tiki Bar -- Rambutans!</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/tales-from-the-tiki-bar-rambutans/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/tales-from-the-tiki-bar-rambutans/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I bought a special treat at the market this afternoon. They look freaky but are delicious!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Tiki Bar Kitchen -- 4</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/my-tiki-bar-kitchen-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/my-tiki-bar-kitchen-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today let&amp;rsquo;s do a couple of different but out-of-the-ordinary recipes, both easy and delicious! That was one of my requirements for Lorena, simple. She came through on most occasions since I managed to communicate that I&amp;rsquo;m no cook. So put on your apron, pop a cork (always cook with wine!), and jump right in!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ATUN! (ah-toon)  OR A NEW TAKE ON TUNA SALAD&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Atun is the Spanish word for tuna.  I’m not a big canned tuna fan, so I wasn’t excited about it &amp;ndash; until I tasted it.  The way the Mexicans do it is to my liking!  I’ll list the full recipe, but you can do it without some things and jimmy it around and it’s still really good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_m7kkfhIuhs1qzu24w.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;170&#34; /&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_m7kkkfNrIb1qzu24w.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;170&#34; /&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_m7kkopNdXB1qzu24w.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;170&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Start with two regular cans of tuna, drained&lt;br /&gt;
2 Roma tomatoes diced “chiquita” (small)&lt;br /&gt;
1 small onion diced small&lt;br /&gt;
1 can of “tuna salad” that already has some peas, carrots, mayo in it&lt;br /&gt;
1 cup of “crema” &amp;ndash; it’s like full whipping cream only a bit thicker&lt;br /&gt;
(it comes from the cheese tianguis in a plastic cup with a wax paper cover)&lt;br /&gt;
2 big spoons of your favorite mayo&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;-1 small can of whole yellow corn, drained (1-serving size)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mix it all up together and serve it on “saladitas,” which are saltines, or on tostadas or with chips.  It makes a great light lunch or an accompaniment to a big green salad or with soup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first time she made this, she didn’t have the can of tuna salad or the crema, and it was still delicious.&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_m7kkty5a6D1qzu24w.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And now for something kinda scary for gringos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Camarones are shrimp &amp;#8212; good, fresh shrimp &amp;ndash; yum!&lt;br /&gt;
For some reason when she said she was going to do ceviche, I was thinking of cold veggie soup, like Italian gazpacho!  Don’t ask me why.  Definitely not what I was expecting, but this is SO good.  Don’t be afraid &amp;ndash; just go with it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_m7kjvuhVYS1qzu24w.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CEVICHE DE CAMARONES&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2 lbs of fresh shrimp, cleaned, shelled and tails off, cut in 3-4 bite-sized pieces&lt;br /&gt;
several large limes, maybe 6-8&lt;br /&gt;
salt&lt;br /&gt;
¼ cup each of finely chopped tomato, peeled cucumber, red onion&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;½ &amp;ndash; 1 serrano pepper, seeds removed, finely chopped&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;several cilantro stalks &amp;amp; leaves finely chopped&lt;br /&gt;
1 ripe avocado &amp;ndash; or two&lt;br /&gt;
tostadas &amp;ndash; flat, round, hard tortilla shells that come like that from the store&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clean and cut up the shrimp to bite-size pieces, sprinkle it with salt, put it in a bowl that’s deeper than wide so you can cover the shrimp with fresh-squeezed lime juice.  Cover it and let it sit for 1 ½ hours.  You will notice that it looks cooked &amp;ndash; and it sort of is cooked.  Yes, it’s safe if the shrimp were fresh!  Hey, I had it in Mexico and I’m still here and didn’t have the slightest bit of negative intestinal reaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you get ready to eat, chop the tomatoes, cucumbers, red onions, cilantro, and&lt;br /&gt;
hot pepper (to taste).  Put all that in a bowl and add the drained shrimp pieces and mix well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Serve piled on tostadas and top with thinly sliced avocado.  So gooood!&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_m7kk4exTUW1qzu24w.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buen provecho and salud!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MY TIKI BAR KITCHEN -- 3</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/my-tiki-bar-kitchen-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/my-tiki-bar-kitchen-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE FOOD IS DIFFERENT HERE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only is shopping a bit different &amp;ndash; unless you do the gringo thing and buy all your stuff at Super Lake or Walmart &amp;ndash; but the food itself is different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We’ll never sell a fat yellow chicken.”  Ad words from one of the big chicken mega processors in the US.  When I got here and saw all the yellow chicken for sale in the stores and the markets, I was appalled &amp;ndash; I’m talking rubber-chicken-paint yellow.  I didn’t know what to make of it.  Yuck!  I refused to buy any chicken for the first few weeks until I found out that the yellow is on purpose and caused by marigold-type flowers in their diet.  Okay, much better &amp;ndash; whew!  The chicken here is actually very tasty and good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_m64tcdq66k1qzu24w.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did I mention the feet are included in a whole roasting/boiling chicken?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The veggies are fresh and local, and many appear alien &amp;ndash; like “from Mars” alien.  Also you can get fresh organic veggies and lettuces at the organic market that are a lot less work once you get them home.  The lettuce at the tianguis is fresh out of the ground complete with whatever little bugs and dirt that are in it.  If I buy that, I have to cut it apart into separate leaves, wash them well, and disinfect them in the solution for 10 minutes in the sink.  Then the leaves must be drained and then dried and put into baggies before being put into the fridge.  A bit of work.  Or you can clean and disinfect some each time you want salad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_m65jn52sHZ1qzu24w.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;280&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_m65js5fpMS1qzu24w.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;280&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the organic market, you can get lettuces and other salad leaves are already washed and dried and ready to use.  It’s well worth the bit of extra cost over the tianguis.  Or for a bit less you can buy the fresh-picked heads of all kinds of lettuces and wash and disinfect it.  Calabaza squash, tomatoes, onions, avocados, and other veggies, you have to soak them in the disinfectant anyway, but that’s easy, so I just buy the tianguis offerings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a side note, I’m not sure why Americans don’t disinfect things like spinach and lettuce now, since there have been so many E. coli outbreaks in recent years.  Water alone doesn’t kill it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hamburger, either at the carniceria or the grocery store, has very little fat.  I used to make bigger, thicker patties because I knew they would cook down quite a bit.  Here, they stay about the same size, and there’s very little fat to drain.  So our first hamburger patties were HUGE.  This is how much fat wasn&amp;rsquo;t in the pan when they were done! &lt;img src=&#34;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_m65m4rBdZ01qzu24w.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most popular meat cuts in the States aren’t really sold down here.  Unless you go to a gringo boutique carniceria, you won’t find a roast or a brisket.  They have some steaks and hamburger and bistek.  Bistek is very thin, like about ¼ inch or a little more.  I tried cooking it fast in a cast iron skillet, but that’s just not good.  We don’t buy the regular steaks since we don’t have a grill here, and I don’t like pan steak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can buy fresh organic eggs at the organic market, but they are really small and pretty expensive, so &amp;ndash; against my better judgment &amp;ndash; I buy the extra omega 3 eggs at Soriana grocery store.  We go through almost 2 ½ dozen eggs a week, and we’re on a budget.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eggs from the mega henhouse are very large here, bigger than extra-large back in Texas, and the yolks are very large compared to US eggs.  The yolks are also usually a very bright pretty orange.  I believe the orange is from the yellow flowers that the chickens are all fed here.  And eggs are not refrigerated.  In fact, many countries around the world keep their eggs non-refrigerated and always have.  People aren’t dropping dead from salmonella either.  Eggs have no need for refrigeration &amp;ndash; unless they have been refrigerated &amp;ndash; althoughit’s probably not a good idea to keep them out in the summer heat very long.  In a store or home is fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_m65kikn1So1qzu24w.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;270&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other thing about eggs, possibly because they’re not refrigerated, is that there’s a trick to not breaking the yolks if you want to fry them sunny.  You have to be very careful not to rake them with the shell as you drop them into the skillet.  I am getting better at it, but success isn’t a given.  Thankfully, Glenn likes his broken and/or with hard yolks anyhow, since I usually only get 3 of 4 whole. And then there&amp;rsquo;s boiled eggs &amp;ndash; the yolks all go to one end and poke out of the whites. I wonder if it&amp;rsquo;s because the whites are thinner without refrigeration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_m65kn0DnfJ1qzu24w.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;270&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then there’s BACON!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bacon, the meat everyone loves to hate &amp;ndash; unless you’re on a low-carb diet &lt;img src=&#34;http://v2j.vagabondians.com/wp-includes/images/smilies/simple-smile.png&#34; alt=&#34;:-)&#34; class=&#34;wp-smiley&#34; style=&#34;height: 1em; max-height: 1em;&#34; /&gt;  At the carniceria that we go to they slice it up on the spot, whatever thickness desired.  We’ve also bought the FUD brand bacon at the grocery store.  (Really?  If you have to name it “food,” is it?  It’s actually pretty good bacon.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both the packaged and fresh bacon take &lt;em&gt;for-evver&lt;/em&gt; to cook.  I have no idea why.&lt;br /&gt;
And there’s hardly any fat left behind in the pan.  If you like to save and use bacon drippings, here you’re going to have to cook a LOT of bacon.  The flavor is milder too &amp;ndash; not as addicting.  (Hmmmm, what do they use to enhance the flavor in the States?  Flavor addiction in all processed food is bi-i-i-ig business.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_m65kqwKfZt1qzu24w.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;270&#34; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This is an entire package of bacon chopped and cooked, and no fat has been removed!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of bacon &amp;ndash;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Carne en su jugo (meat in its juice)!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a wonderful Mexican stew, of sorts.  The first time I saw a sign for this dish, I thought it said “meat in your juice” and pictured a frosty glass of orange with a hunk of meat in it &amp;ndash; YISH!  Ha!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Super Lake grocery, they had some free samples of a jarred brand and so I tried it.  It was delicious.  I almost bought a jar, but our housekeeper, Lorena, had said she was going to teach me that one the following week.  I hired her to teach me a recipe a week while we’re here.  Smartest move ever!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So&amp;hellip;on to the recipe!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CARNE EN SU JUGO&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;15 small tomatillos (green tomato-like veggies with a papery outer shell and sticky skin, remove the papery shells and wash)&lt;br /&gt;
½ lb bacon&lt;br /&gt;
2 lb “bistek” &amp;ndash; ¼” thick skirt steak  (** see note below!)&lt;br /&gt;
2-3 medium-large cloves of garlic&lt;br /&gt;
½ &amp;ndash; 1 serrano chili pepper&lt;br /&gt;
1 onion fairly finely diced&lt;br /&gt;
cilantro finely chopped&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add a can of beans, white or your favorite, if you choose&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;limones (key limes &amp;ndash; or regular limes) for squeezing onto your serving to taste&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_m65memony01qzu24w.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;270&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Put the tomatillos in a pan of water and boil the heck out of them for about 10-15 minutes, till they are very-ripe-soft, drain and let cool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chop the bacon into ¾” pieces and cook it in a good-sized pot till done but not crisp at all.  Mexican bacon, it’s best to add some oil to the pan to cook it.  (American bacon, you’ll probably want to drain out most of the fat after you get it cooked and you might need closer to a whole pound.  Can’t have too much bacon, right?)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the bacon cooks, chop the bistek into bite-sized pieces.  When the bacon is ready, add the chopped meat or hamburger and cook it till done.  Salt the meat, maybe a half teaspoon plus/minus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the meat is cooking, put the cooled tomatillos into a blender, add several pieces/stalks/branches (whatever you’d call them) of fresh cilantro, the 2 cloves of garlic, ½-1 serrano pepper to taste, about 1 ½ cups of water.  Blend very well and long so that everything is chopped up fine  (depending on your blender, you may want to chop the garlic and the serrano pepper before adding them)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the meat is cooked, pour the blender contents into the pot.  Cover and simmer/boil for 20 minutes or so.  Check the flavor and adjust if needed.  You may need to boil off some water or add more, depending on your preferences.  It should be fairly soupy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While it’s cooking, chop finely the onion and more cilantro.  These will be added raw to each serving to taste, and as a pretty garnish.  You can add a few little pieces of red tomato to make it pretty, and it adds to the flavor too.  Limones are squeezed on to taste (I like it as is, without the limon, personally)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Serve in a bowl with a spoon and tortillas for sopping.  Or if you make it thicker, you can spoon it into your tortillas as a wet taco.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TIP:  Flour tortillas from the store are so much tastier if you “toast” them on both sides in a dry pan on the stove.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;** This dish is also good with hamburger in place of the bistek, and it doesn’t have to cook as long.  Just let the flavors meld.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Salud! &amp;ndash; to your health!&lt;strong id=&#34;internal-source-marker_0.4579134329687804&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MY TIKI BAR KITCHEN -- 2</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/my-tiki-bar-kitchen-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/my-tiki-bar-kitchen-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;internal-source-marker_0.8239042330533266&#34;&gt;LET’S START WITH SHOPPING&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We started living here and quickly discovered that if you want fresh veggies, you should go to the tianguis.  Most towns have their own market day, and Chapala’s is Monday; neighbor town Ajijic’s is Wednesday.  The tianguis are markets set up along the street, sheltered with tarps, and they sell everything imaginable that you can carry away in a bag, from food to clothing and CDs and DVDs and toys.  &lt;img src=&#34;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_m5dn3x8sfj1qzu24w.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;270&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_m5dpfhr29A1qzu24w.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;270&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;internal-source-marker_0.8239042330533266&#34;&gt;Some of the veggies are a third the price of the grocery store, and most all are significantly cheaper.  And the grocery gets their produce trucked in from who-knows-where, while the tianguis usually get theirs from the nearby Guadalajara farmers market as well as their own gardens or farms.  Not as convenient as one-stop shopping in a store, but it’s always fun and interesting.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;internal-source-marker_0.8239042330533266&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_m5dmkn9yZy1qzu24w.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_m5dphjqu3z1qzu24w.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;230&#34; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are so many different veggies and fruits available, many of which I’ve never encountered.  My what-the-hell-is-that moments are getting fewer and farther between, but they still happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;internal-source-marker_0.8239042330533266&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_m5dmqtYJfF1qzu24w.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;270&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_m5dp5td6ly1qzu24w.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;230&#34; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are now buying our veggies for the week here, and we will either buy a couple of fresh fish (whole and cleaned or filleted) or some chicken breasts, all very fresh and tasty.  We buy our hamburger (real cubes of fresh beef ground while we watch) and bacon sliced to our specs at a little butcher shop or carniceria across the street from the Soriana grocery store.  If we need fresh cheeses, we can get that at the tianguis too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Tuesdays there is an organic market where I buy my assorted lettuces and salad leaves, like baby spinach, sorrel, and Swiss chard, since many are already washed and disinfected or at least the dirt mostly rinsed out.  More expensive, but organic &amp;ndash; and it saves me a lot of work.  This market has organic breads and prepared foods, honey, eggs, clothing, juices, all kinds of produce, organic soaps, toothpaste, shampoo and more &amp;ndash; and it&amp;rsquo;s in an actual building.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;internal-source-marker_0.8239042330533266&#34;&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;internal-source-marker_0.8239042330533266&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_m5dncjgkSO1qzu24w.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_m5dpc4hKiE1qzu24w.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;270&#34; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;internal-source-marker_0.8239042330533266&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Then there’s Super Lake grocery where you can get all kinds of gringo food so you can eat like you’re still in the States &amp;ndash; for a price.  For example, I bought a small roll of frozen Jimmy Dean sausage for some stuffed jalepenos I want to make, and that cost me $8.50 US!  I had already bought the other ingredients at Soriana or I would have opted out.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The local Walmart has a lot of gringo stuff &amp;ndash; especially in the “ethnic section” &amp;ndash; and looks more familiar.  A lot of expats shop at Walmart and Super Lake, but they’re missing out on the experience of living in Mexico, if you ask me.  They’re often afraid to venture out to the markets.  We have shopped in them since we got here in mid-February and have never had or seen a problem or anything to be afraid of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have found the people here very nice and welcoming and helpful, even though our Spanish is pretty pitiful.  Yes, there is crime, yes, there is violence, but you don’t go where that is, for the most part.  Sometimes you can’t avoid it, but it’s the same back home too.  Really, it’s family people going about their business of living here, not a bunch of thugs and pickpockets waiting to prey on the gringos.  You might end up paying a little more than local Mexicans in the markets unless you’re willing to step out of your comfort zone and bargain, but it’s to be expected.  Even just hesitating and starting to leave will often get you a much better price automatically.  The prices are better than you’d ever get in the States, so many gringos just pay them the quoted amount.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, when in Rome &amp;ndash; or wherever you are &amp;ndash; do as the locals do.  You’ll be richer for it, both experientially and financially!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On to our first recipe!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HOLY GUACAMOLE!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have always loved guacamole, but I never had the gumption to try to make my own.  It’s so easy &amp;ndash; who knew!  Great with chips or Lorena made it as a side dish when she prepared fish for us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For two to four servings, depending on your serving size, you need:&lt;br /&gt;
2 man-fist-sized avocados that are a little soft, nicely ripe&lt;br /&gt;
1 large or two small Roma tomatoes, finely diced&lt;br /&gt;
½ medium onion, finely diced&lt;br /&gt;
1 large limon (key lime) or half a regular lime&lt;br /&gt;
fresh cilantro, finely chopped&lt;br /&gt;
salt&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;internal-source-marker_0.8239042330533266&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_m63ec9Z77U1qzu24w.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;230&#34; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Choosing avocados was daunting to me until I&amp;rsquo;d bought a lot of them and have had them ripening in the kitchen.  I now know that it&amp;rsquo;s great when it&amp;rsquo;s just a little soft all over.  If there are areas that you can actually press in on, that part might be black inside &amp;ndash; yuk.  Then you have to just scoop around that part.  Avocados don&amp;rsquo;t really ripen on the tree, apparently, so often they are rock hard at the store.  Just take them home and put them in a bowl on the counter and check on them till they&amp;rsquo;re ripe.  Or I&amp;rsquo;ve heard putting them in a paper bag might be better.  I haven&amp;rsquo;t tried that yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;internal-source-marker_0.8239042330533266&#34;&gt;Take a big knife and slice the avocado, seed deep, all the way around longways.  Twist the two halves and they will come apart with the seed staying in one side.  Whack your knife blade into the seed, give it a little twist, and it will come out cleanly &amp;ndash; keep the seed handy.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scoop out the tasty meat from both avocados into a bowl, and mash it with a fork.  Squeeze the limon (lime) juice onto the mash to prevent any browning of the fruit if you get delayed.  Use quite a bit of juice for great flavor.  Add the rest of the ingredients and mix well.  Play with the amount of cilantro, limon juice, and salt to get the flavor you want.  Serve with chips &amp;ndash; and margaritas!  It’s also wonderful as just a side salad-y dish with many of your favorite meals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;internal-source-marker_0.8239042330533266&#34;&gt;Garnish with some tomato pieces, onion bits, and cilantro and/or chips&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TIPS:  If your guacamole is going to be served a little later, put the seed back into the middle of it.  Somehow it helps to keep it fresh.  Cover with plastic wrap, placed directly on the guacamole so that the contact with air is minimized and refrigerate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, if you will find the tostadas, possibly in the Mexican food aisle, these make very fine-tasting chips if you break them up.  Probably significantly cheaper than a bag of chips too, though not as perfectly pretty. &lt;img src=&#34;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_m5errr7e5b1qzu24w.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;270&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MY TIKI BAR KITCHEN -- 1</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/my-tiki-bar-kitchen-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/my-tiki-bar-kitchen-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I know, tiki is so South Pacific and we’re in Mexico &amp;ndash; but it’s also retro American kitsch that evokes silliness and warmth and friends having cocktails at sunset. So grab your tiki mug and just go with me!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_m5djr07vUY1qzu24w.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what could be so different about food prep in Mexico? What’s the big deal? Well, for me, it is quite different and a challenge. I can’t really put my finger on one thing or one area and explain it to anyone, so there will be several articles in this series about food purchase, preparation, and cooking &amp;ndash; and some authentic Mexican recipes that I find easy and tasty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Disclaimer: First off, I’m no cocinera! I can cook basic stuff fairly well at home in the US. But when I came to Mexico, I found so many differences in the food and how it cooks and what’s available, that I had to stop and regroup and ask for help from an expert &amp;ndash; our Mexican housekeeper. (She came with the house-sit job &amp;ndash; score!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re going to explore shopping and cooking here in the state of Jalisco, Mexico.  From what I hear, this vast country has many styles, and each state is different. Hang onto your hats &amp;ndash; it&amp;rsquo;s not Tex Mex!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;May the roof above us never fall in, and may the friends gathered below it never fall out.-Unknown&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life and Living in Mexico</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/life-living-mexico/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/life-living-mexico/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One month (well, almost two since I started this post and never finished it!) under our belts living in a foreign country, here in Chapala, Jalisco, MX.  The time has flown by.  Somehow I thought that the days would seem longer, that I would have so much time on my hands to get things done.  Not so.  Of course, I&amp;rsquo;ve been mentally chained to my computer way more than I planned.  Just one more email check, a little more Facebook reading, one more game.  Then it&amp;rsquo;s time for the dogs&amp;rsquo; afternoon walk, dinner&amp;hellip;. That&amp;rsquo;s got to change!  Glenn is using the time here to get his internet business going.  A lot of learning, trying things, changing things, on and on.  Couldn&amp;rsquo;t do much of that when we were touring the US and seeing all those national parks and whatnot.  Here in our four-month house sitting job, maybe he can get it knocked out so he can get into maintenance mode before too long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately -or unfortunately, depending- we can get by here in Chapala/Ajijic with very little Spanish.  I finished my Fluenz Spanish 1 &amp;amp; 2, and it&amp;rsquo;s an awesome course.  I highly recommend it.  I wish I had 3-5, but it&amp;rsquo;s more money than I want to part with now that we don&amp;rsquo;t have jobs.  The people here are very patient with us and very kind.  Many people here speak English to some degree and love to practice.  Check out &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fluenz.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Fluenz for Spanish&lt;/a&gt; and other languages too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Groceries and shopping seem to be the biggest problem for me.  It takes forever, and I never buy enough to last, and I don&amp;rsquo;t have enough easy recipes.  The food is different here, and I don&amp;rsquo;t know what to do with a lot of it.  We like to get almost all of our veggies and berries at the tianguis, or open air markets, here.  Monday&amp;rsquo;s in Chapala, that we just discovered, is really huge and offers so much.  We have been going to the organic market on Tuesday and the tianguis on Wednesday in Ajijic.  Seems still, every time I go, that I have a what-the-hell-is-THAT moment for some fruit/veg thing on a table or two.  Alien stuff, whatever your definition of alien!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img class=&#34;alignleft  wp-image-1144&#34; src=&#34;http://vagabondians.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/04/IMG_0135.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vagabondians.com/1094/life-living-mexico/img_0140-2/&#34; rel=&#34;attachment wp-att-1146&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter  wp-image-1146&#34; src=&#34;http://vagabondians.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/04/IMG_01401.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;550&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We want to find a butcher and find out where his meat comes from and hopefully get mostly grass-fed now.  Chicken here is all yellow &amp;ndash; and I mean primary color/rubber chicken yellow!  For all I know, this is normal and the chicken in the US is bleached.  I need to learn!  I want to get away from American beef with all the antibiotics and the &amp;ldquo;pink slime&amp;rdquo; in almost all the hamburger and the other questionable practices of big ag.  I think the dozen or so cows by the market were for sale, and the pen did not smell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our house-sit, we are to walk the big dog twice a day and the little dog once a day, so we get our exercise going up and down the many hills in this neighborhood on the rough cobblestone roads.  The maid comes on Monday and Friday (love this perk!), and the gardener comes weekly (or he&amp;rsquo;s supposed to).  So it&amp;rsquo;s been a fairly busy schedule with just basic living.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The weather is about perfect so far, and when we go down to Chapala&amp;rsquo;s malecon (walkway by the lake with a market on weekends, restaurants, beach, boat rides&amp;hellip;), it&amp;rsquo;s really nice.  Lots of interesting people to watch too.  Ajijic also has one that is beautiful, but newer and not as active on a regular basis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that&amp;rsquo;s the skinny.  More to come.  Don&amp;rsquo;t worry &amp;ndash; I&amp;rsquo;m going to start writing more often and shorter articles with more pictures.  This isn&amp;rsquo;t cutting the mustard, so to speak!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Medicine in Mexico</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/medicine-mexico/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/medicine-mexico/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve been asked, What will you do if you get sick or need a doctor?  You&amp;rsquo;re in MEXICO, for heaven&amp;rsquo;s sake!  Oh, horror of horrors!  Their health care can&amp;rsquo;t possibly be trustworthy!  Or can it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, our plan is, if we need to, we&amp;rsquo;ll go to the doctor here.  We don&amp;rsquo;t have any insurance.  We&amp;rsquo;d rather (to borrow a quote) pay for what IS instead of what MIGHT BE.  Here in Mexico and most all the other countries we plan to visit over the next several years, it&amp;rsquo;s actually possible to pay for your care out of pocket!  Really! (more on that later)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; style=&#34;margin: 5px;&#34; src=&#34;http://a3.sphotos.ak.fbcdn.net/hphotos-ak-ash4/405036_10150776629948993_677503992_11483150_2097365987_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;599&#34; height=&#34;450&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I purposely avoided going to a doc before we left the States, since we really couldn&amp;rsquo;t afford (translate:  didn&amp;rsquo;t want to pay exorbitant prices for) a doc visit and medicine for a little infection under my toenail.  So after we got settled, I chose a doc from a local expat forum and went in.  He was a very nice young doc, excellent English, took a good history, did a basic exam, and sent me for blood work.  He says I&amp;rsquo;m supposed to be immune to this type of infection.  I think he already knew what my blood work was going to show.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; src=&#34;http://sphotos.xx.fbcdn.net/hphotos-ash3/522774_10150776630493993_1473331998_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;609&#34; height=&#34;504&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took his order for tests around the corner to the lab where a couple of lovely, friendly ladies who really didn&amp;rsquo;t speak much English took my blood and payment and told me to pick up the results the next day after 2:00.  I have fainted in the US from lab techs digging the needle around to make it go into the vein and I had the bruises to show for it. But this tech was so good that I was surprised to hear a hissing sound and had to turn and look to make sure that it was my blood filling the vial!  So much for my needle phobia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back to the doc with my results:  Yep, diabetes!  WHAT???  He gave me my instructions and prescriptions to go fill at the farmacia. (Oh, boy, I hope all the forms are in English!)  I went into the Farmacia Guadalajara (the Ajijic branch), gave the lady my RXs, she went and got the boxes, I paid and left.  No red tape, no paperwork, no bother, AND very inexpensive medicine!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, then the liver tests came back and the doc requested I come in to go over treatment plans.  Oh, great.  Now what?  After a consult/discussion, he sent me to Guadalajara for a CAT scan of my abdomen to see why my bilirubin numbers are so high.  He said I could go locally for an ultrasound, but it would be better to examine all the organs.  He called for me and made the appointment, gave me the order complete with map, and sent me on my way. Hm, wonder what this will cost!  But it has to be less than paying outlandish premiums and meeting a very high deductible, then 20% like back home, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; src=&#34;http://sphotos.xx.fbcdn.net/hphotos-prn1/525669_10150776631003993_677503992_11483157_1551424664_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;620&#34; height=&#34;440&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the big lab in the big city I went in and the tech scared the living crapola out of me &amp;ndash; for no reason.  I think it&amp;rsquo;s the English/Spanish thing.  Partly.  (And my absolute phobia of medical procedures since being traumatized by The Exorcist at age 11.)  He said, &amp;ldquo;We have to put in your vein medicine to paint the organs and it will be hot, uncomfortable, but for a short time.&amp;rdquo;  I took that to mean that my arm was going to burn off as I groan and writhe and fight tears.  (Okay, this is going to be BAD &amp;ndash; suck it up!)  Then they said I needed a full bladder, so I had to drink 4 cups of water down.  Then she came back and said maybe some coffee would speed it up, so I drank 2 cups of Nescafe, then two more glasses of water to wash that out of my mouth as I nervously waited.  The ocean in my gut!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally the tech gave me a clean cotton gown (nice long, wide one that covered very nicely, thank you very much!) and I went in and laid on the plank with a pillow.  They put a foam thing under my knees, stuck a needle in my arm (hardly felt that either!), and hooked it up to a drip.  Arms overhead and they left.  So far so good &amp;ndash; no fire &amp;ndash; and in I rolled, under the arch.  Back and forth, hold your breath, out again.  I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel anything go into my vein.  She came in and checked my needle and put my arms on my stomach and told me to relax and left for a few.  Still didn&amp;rsquo;t feel anything.  I started giggling when I though about relaxing though, and wondered if I was high.  I didn&amp;rsquo;t think so &amp;ndash; dangit!  Then she came back in, put my arms back over my head in a slightly different position and left, and in I rolled again.  This time I did feel some heat, but it was in my abdomen, and it was just a weird warmth.  No fire down my arm!  Yay!  Then I was done.  I&amp;rsquo;m to pick up my results at the cashier window in one hour.  That&amp;rsquo;s it?  Wow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; src=&#34;http://sphotos.xx.fbcdn.net/hphotos-prn1/557649_10150776631458993_677503992_11483159_555700202_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;621&#34; height=&#34;464&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This whole experience was great.  I simply went in (we were about 45 minutes early), showed them my slip from the doc, they looked up my appointment, I paid.  I waited maybe 15 minutes, went in, drank all the liquid, had the procedure, out, get results, leave.  No pages of paperwork to fill out  here either!  Really!  I got all my CT Scan films and a CD, and they email the doc with the results too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From reading other travel blogs, I was ready for the building to be kind of shabby, and in the US I would not have set foot in it.  But they put their money into cleanliness, good modern equipment, and professionalism instead of fancy, costly buildings.  Same with my personal doc.  He&amp;rsquo;s just by himself  with his computer in his consultorio on a cobblestone side street.  Fine with me!  I don&amp;rsquo;t like paying for the unnecessary fancy accoutrements found everywhere back home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After all this, I had a reaction to the dye with my meds, so to stop feeling awful and drained, Dr. Loza sent me to the farmacia to get IV supplies to take to the clinic in Ajijic to have them administer it.  Walked in with my stuff, they took me to a little room, and a nurse hooked me up and came back now and then to check on me.  Her English was excellent as well.  She was also very good and didn&amp;rsquo;t hurt me when putting the catheter in my hand.  I&amp;rsquo;m going to have to be over having a needle phobia now &amp;ndash; it&amp;rsquo;s just silly!  The clinic always looks busy from the outside, but inside was clean and nice and there was no waiting &amp;ndash; and, once again, no red tape and paperwork!  Awesome!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, so here&amp;rsquo;s the bottom line:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;|&amp;mdash;
| Initial office visit/doc consult and history: | $500 pesos/ $38.99 USD
| Lab work: complete blood workup: |  $750 pesos/$58.49 USD
| Doc consult office visit: |  $300 pesos/$23.39
| Farmacia Rx: |  $29 pesos/$2.26 for 60 days&amp;rsquo; worth
| Lab work: complete liver profile workup: |  $700 pesos/$54.59
| Doc office visit on liver, sent to get CAT scan: |  $ zero pesos
| Doc regular office visit/consult/exam: |  $300 pesos/$23.39
| Big city lab CAT scan: |  $4,500 pesos   $355 USD
| Doc consult on CAT, sent for IV: |  $300 pesos/$23.39
| Farmacia:  IV bottle, tubing, needle catheter: |  $106.30/$8.29
| Other Rx: | $245.90/$19.18
| Ajijic clinic to administer the IV on a bed for 1 hour + B12 vitamins I forgot at pharmacy: | $450 pesos/$35.09
|===
| &lt;strong&gt;GRAND TOTAL&lt;/strong&gt; | &lt;strong&gt;$7,681 pesos/$598.97 USD&lt;/strong&gt;
|&amp;mdash;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that, my friends, is less than one month of insurance premiums for one of us, had we been paying them!  And I have in my hands the originals of all the blood tests and CAT scan in case I want to review them, look up something on the internet, or go have a second opinion.   No muss, no fuss, sane and logical here in Mexico.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more pictures, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/media/set/?set=a.10150776629728993.463540.677503992&amp;type=3&amp;l=bcdf0579df&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Musings On Being Homeless after 7 Months</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/musings-homeless/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/musings-homeless/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Homelessness on purpose is a pretty freaky feeling.  We, like you, have always had a lot of stuff.  We had a small house that eventually seemed a bit cramped.  We moved closer to our good jobs and bought our dream home with the vow never to move again.  We bought the house we thought we&amp;rsquo;d retire in, in a nice neighborhood.  It was big enough for us and overnight guests and party gatherings.  We filled it with stuff that attracted us.  I never threw things away or got rid of very much that I really could have/should have, just in case I might need it later.  Then came the epiphany.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not where we want to be in 10+ years when we retire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We don&amp;rsquo;t want to be tied down anymore with debt and a mortgage.  We had been thinking about retirement for a few years and what we wanted to do &amp;ldquo;someday.&amp;rdquo;  We got the freedom bug and the travel bug, and all we&amp;rsquo;d collected over our 20 years together started to seem a huge anchor around our necks choking the life out of us. We were getting emails at work about people that retired 1, 2, 3 years ago and now they&amp;rsquo;re dead &amp;ndash; come to the funeral.  Is that our future?!!  We have living to do!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reading about others that went before us into the world at large inspired us to take action to get out of the &amp;ldquo;American Dream&amp;rdquo; system.  We took drastic measures to kill off all our debt and stuck to it.  We started selling off all our stuff.  Hard watching all my beautiful stuff that I paid good money for going out the door for pennies on the dollar, but we had a dream.  I was telling everyone about how we were leaving so that I couldn&amp;rsquo;t chicken out.  I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to be all talk and no do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally the day came when we left the world of having an address where we live.  We have almost no personal belongings.   I&amp;rsquo;m a woman; women &amp;ldquo;nest.&amp;rdquo;  My nest was gone and I must fly free.  It&amp;rsquo;s liberating yet kinda freaky and unsettling.  I have to remind myself when I &amp;ldquo;look down and see the ground far below&amp;rdquo; that my stuff is now in the bank.  That&amp;rsquo;s my nest egg, if you will.  I realized that the only real security in having stuff is that you could sell it if you needed money.  We sold it already.  That&amp;rsquo;s the only difference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I have pictures of all my stuff if I ever want to look at them &amp;ndash; so far, not. Seems that having a lot of stuff is just what we do to give ourselves the illusion of permanency in the world or having an anchor. I haven&amp;rsquo;t regretted any of this except for maybe a few kitchen items that we had to replace with cheaper versions when we got our travel trailer.  That&amp;rsquo;s it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I LOVE BEING HOMELESS!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can make much less money since there&amp;rsquo;s no bills and no maintenance, other than our vehicle that will soon be gone.  Breathing is easier without that &amp;ldquo;load on my shoulders.&amp;rdquo; Downsizing to two backpacks is the next step as we head for adventure in the world outside our previous experience.  New languages to learn, new food to try, new people and cultures to explore, new friends, new vistas, new sunsets.  Nope, not regretting it at all, thank-you-very-much.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy New Year! Time&#39;s A&#39;wastin&#39;!</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/happy-year-times-awastin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/happy-year-times-awastin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I read this from a Facebook friend:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My wish for everyone in 2012 - &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;../images/2011/12/fireworks.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
12 months of happiness&lt;br /&gt;
52 weeks of fun&lt;br /&gt;
365 days success&lt;br /&gt;
8760 hours good health&lt;br /&gt;
52600 minutes good luck&lt;br /&gt;
3153600 seconds of joy !!&lt;br /&gt;
Happy New Year&amp;rsquo;s Eve Hugs !!! ♥&lt;br /&gt;
{: style=&amp;ldquo;text-align: center;&amp;rdquo; }&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../images/2011/12/bored-baby.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
{: align=&amp;ldquo;left&amp;rdquo; }
Sounds nice!  But I started thinking about it:  8760 hours in a year.  Not all that many when you think of a whole year.  How many do I just WASTE of my LIFE?  This is my most important asset we&amp;rsquo;re talking about here:  MY LIFE!  Only one time around, no do-overs.  How much time do I spend these days just sitting in front of my computer basically doing absolutely nothing?  Not fun, not productive, just nothing; boredom?  That just totally SCARED me!  I&amp;rsquo;m no spring chicken anymore.  Can I afford to just throw that many hours away?  Trash.  Nothing.  Can I?  Can you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I thought, well, you have to subtract 8 per day for sleeping/staring into space/hoping to sleep, and it&amp;rsquo;s only 5840.  Then you have to spend, say,  1.25 hours in the bathroom a day:  5384.  Then there&amp;rsquo;s time eating/cooking/cleaning the kitchen and dishes, say 2 hrs a day:  4654.  Over a whole year, I only have about 4654 hours to LIVE.  That&amp;rsquo;s only 12.75 hours a day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../images/2011/12/old-celebrate.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
{: align=&amp;ldquo;right&amp;rdquo; }
When I get to my death bed (presuming nothing sudden happens early), will I say, Wow, I sure wish I&amp;rsquo;d worked more hours, spent more time playing computer games, spent more time in virtual space doing whatever, spent more time just &amp;ldquo;resting&amp;rdquo;?  No I will not!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SO&amp;hellip;.I hereby apologize to myself for all my wasted time in this one life I have been allotted &amp;ndash; apology accepted &amp;ndash; and I resolve to spend my time more wisely.  I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t just flush dollars for no reason, would I?  No, I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t.  Life is so much more valuable than money.  You can always make more money.  You can never make more life or more time.  Spent is spent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HAPPY NEW LIFE, EVERYBODY!  What will you do with this year?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tales from the Tiki Bar:  Napa Valley, baby!</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/tales-tiki-bar-napa-baby/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/tales-tiki-bar-napa-baby/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Highway 29 from Napa to Calistoga will take you through a river of wine.  If each winery is a boulder, it&amp;rsquo;s a rapid run of gargantuan proportions. The term &amp;ldquo;highway&amp;rdquo; is kind of a misnomer too.  It&amp;rsquo;s a two-lane road winding through gorgeous wineries at about 35 mph. Sometimes it&amp;rsquo;s just a long line of cars, but mostly it kept moving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262594200424074&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262594200424074&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We decided to run the road to the far end and start from there.  As we drove we made a list of places we might want to stop and taste.  There&amp;rsquo;s even Old Faithful Geyser of California on the edge of Calistoga.  We decided to pass that one up in anticipation of the granddaddy of old faithful geysers at Yellowstone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We began the serious part of the jaunt at Calistoga, which is a cute town in its own right, full of shops and tasting rooms and a foodie&amp;rsquo;s delight.  The public market/farmers market was in full swing.  Not large, but colorful, and everything from fresh turnips and flowers to arts and crafts and African woven baskets and fans to gourmet treats and even a pretty good trio of ladies singing and playing instruments.  Just behind them, a nice creek with a bridge and a local chocolate lab taking a nice swim to cool off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262589513757876&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262589513757876&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262589730424521&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262589730424521&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First stop was Chateau Montelena of &lt;em&gt;Bottle Shock&lt;/em&gt; fame.  It was a great movie with lots of &amp;ldquo;poetic license&amp;rdquo; involved.   We were told the book has the real story, so now I must read.  We shared a tasting of 5 superb wines for $20 there and ended up buying a bottle of red zinfandel to save for our 21st anniversary in September.  A tasting there includes your own private pour person instead of one person covering 10-15 people, and she was fun and knowledgeable. The grounds were beautiful, including a lake with a path to two gazebo islands with beautifully set tables to rent for occasions.  They had a large Coastal Redwood they planted in 1990 that was now about 150 ft. high, I think.  In about 500-1000 years it will be among the giants, if conditions are right there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262592250424269&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262592250424269&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262590947091066&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262590947091066&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lunch was next on the list, tasty burgers and fries at a quaint little place there in Calistoga.  Next!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Freemark Abbey winery.  We met a nice young couple tasting next to us who were fairly new to wine and this was their first winery.  The wines and conversation were lively between us and our pour person. (I just like that title I made up.  What are they really called?)  The best was a bonus taste of their dessert white wine.  A little taste of heaven trickling down your throat!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262592993757528&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262592993757528&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hm, what&amp;rsquo;s this, A Dozen Vintners next door?  We can get an overview of several boutique wineries in one place.  We&amp;rsquo;re the only ones there and our host, Tim Mertz, was perfectly awesome!  The shared tasting was, I think, $10, waived if you purchase something, and off we went.  I don&amp;rsquo;t remember how many wines, maybe eight &amp;ndash; or fifteen?  Who knows!  It was a delightful afternoon of wine and conversation.  We stayed there quite some time and left with a case -yes, case! &amp;ndash; of a nice sangiovese for 50 bucks (!) that was one of the last on sale.  Tasted it at the end so we know it was pretty good.  I hope.  Nexsht!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262593480424146&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262593480424146&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe we ought to walk around a bit before going into the next winery?  The slow drive brought us to Grgich Hills Estate (not a drunken typo). The vintner was also involved in the &lt;em&gt;Bottle Shock&lt;/em&gt; saga.  It was very pretty and they had some nicely priced gift boxes and souvenirs and an exhibit about their famous wine.  We weren&amp;rsquo;t overly impressed with the actual wines, good, not excellent.  Back out into the perfect summer day.  Are we done yet?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262593833757444&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262593833757444&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nope.  Just *had* to stop in at Folie a Deux/Napa Cellars where they make one of our favorites, *Menage a Trois.  *The shared tasting there was only $7, and they had samples of some really brilliant dipping sauces.  Yum!  Our pour guy there was fun too.  And we got double tastes of two wines, before-and-after glasses, one out of the newly opened bottle and one run through the Vinturi Red Wine Aerator.  We thought we could actually taste a slight difference &amp;ndash; but by that time, who really knows!  We spent some time on the parklike grounds among the grapevines with actual fruit hanging before taking off for home.  It was sunny, about 75 degrees, slight cool breeze, bright green grass, grapevines, blooming flowers and lavender&amp;hellip;..aaaaaah, perfection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262595023757325&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262595023757325&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A VOTRE SANTE&lt;/em&gt;!  CHEERS!  SALUTE!  &lt;em&gt;clink&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_0:6d6904fc67a34897a8c2b08f006285ca&#34;&gt;**&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;** {#product-name}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262596513757176&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262596513757176&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/media/set/?set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;notif_t=like&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/media/set/?set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;notif_t=like&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tales from the Tiki Bar:  Awesome People</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/tales-tiki-bar-awesome-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/tales-tiki-bar-awesome-people/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve had an interesting couple of days with our rig.  I say rig.  It&amp;rsquo;s a rig to us.  But I digress.  Already.  Anyway, we discovered a leak under the kitchen sink.  Not a big one, but big enough to do damage if we didn&amp;rsquo;t get it fixed right away.  We were getting ready to pack up and move from McAlpine Lake campground to near YOSEMITE &amp;ndash; yay!  Glenn investigated and determined where the little leak was and that he couldn&amp;rsquo;t fix it. So we had to take a side trip to the nearest Camping World since we have a comprehensive warranty.  $50 at any CW takes care of it.  Called the place and they&amp;rsquo;re booked and can&amp;rsquo;t fix it for a few days, so we drive there anyway to see if we can get any action or even parts to try to DIY.  The desk guy said, oh, no, you have to take it to where you bought the camper.  Albuquerque, NM?  We can&amp;rsquo;t do that.  So you want to talk to the supervisor?  Um, yeah.  Enter Max Hayes, the service manager and our hero!  He just jumped in and said, come on, let&amp;rsquo;s take a look, pull it in over here.  We took off the outer cover and he looked at it and proceeded to send someone out to get some parts and fixed it himself in an hour and a half.  Charge?  $20.  Even.  What?  Are you sure?  Yep, $20.  Max Hayes at the Camping World in San Martin, CA!  CHEERS!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This on top of another great experience the day before.  Our battery was acting kind of hinky like it might want to strand us somewhere when we least need that to happen &amp;ndash; like ANYtime.  Just a bit of hesitation when starting up.  So after leaving the beach in Santa Cruz we stopped in Scotts Valley, CA, at Batteries Plus to get their free battery test/evaluation.  Bryan Parker was ever so helpful.  He took his handy-dandy battery widget out there  and tested whatnot, showing us what was going on with the battery.  He got us a very reasonable-priced battery and proceeded to wrestle in the hot sun with our Montero, who didn&amp;rsquo;t want to give up its battery.  He worked like crazy to get the problem solved and the new battery in and the connections all cleaned up.  A very personable and interesting fellow, we had a great conversation as he worked.  When it was finally extracted, we discovered a 4-year-old battery on its last legs.  We are glad to have met Bryan who gave us excellent customer service.  SAAA-LUTE!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love being on the road.  The people you meet tell the most interesting tales and are the real gems of a big trip.  There are still people out there who care what happens to strangers and go out of their way to just be nice.  &amp;rdquo;It&amp;rsquo;s not my job&amp;rdquo; did not apply here, and we are oh, so thankful!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now we are ensconced in a wonderful camp 24 miles south of Yosemite, crown jewel of U.S. parks waiting for the weekend crowds to go home!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hoodoo You Think You Are?</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/hoodoo-are/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/hoodoo-are/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;!&amp;ndash; p.p1 {margin: 0.0px 0.0px 13.0px 0.0px; line-height: 19.0px; font: 13.0px Georgia} &amp;ndash;&amp;gt;Pictures of Bryce Canyon evoke wonder, but taking in the view from Inspiration Point for the first time in person takes your breath away.  An open-mouthed &amp;ldquo;Whohhhhhhhhhh&amp;rdquo; is about all I could muster from my overwhelmed senses.  The heady aroma of warm Ponderosa pine in the late afternoon mountain sun tipped my brain right over the precipice down into the hoodoos. The trail through the canyon beckoned that I should just run right down there and lose myself in their mysterious fairytale world, never to return.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=249780888372072&amp;amp;#038;set=a.248887665128061.84396.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=249780888372072&amp;amp;#038;set=a.248887665128061.84396.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately sanity eventually returned, if I ever had it to begin with, and I settled for a promised trip down in the morning.  The ranger suggested that it&amp;rsquo;s best to begin at Sunrise Point and end at Sunset Point for the &amp;ldquo;best three-mile hike on earth.&amp;rdquo; We were filled with glee as the view changed dramatically every few steps.  The cameras were going to get a workout today!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=249784715038356&amp;amp;#038;set=a.248887665128061.84396.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=249784715038356&amp;amp;#038;set=a.248887665128061.84396.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Long, yet still fairly steep, switchbacks seemed to confirm the choice of direction, as we marveled at how hard the people had to work to get up out of the canyon as we descended.  As we got deeper, the hoodoos seemed to grow taller as they dwarfed us in their mystic shadows.  The colors seemed to intensify as they worked their witchery on us.  On we went, around and through this natural wonderland, hoping we wouldn&amp;rsquo;t fall into any rabbit holes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=249786228371538&amp;amp;#038;set=a.248887665128061.84396.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=249786228371538&amp;amp;#038;set=a.248887665128061.84396.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We wound through and ended up in a nice pine forest for a while.  We took an apple break in the lap of a friendly tree.  Then as we sat in its shade we spied a lone figure lying in a tree across the way.  We watched as people passed him up, laughing at his misfortune.  He seemed so sad sitting there.  No telling how long he&amp;rsquo;d been there.  We took our time on our break, and no one came to rescue him, so we decided to save him and he rode behind me, waving to people out of my backpack, just in case we would pass his original negligent owner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=249791031704391&amp;amp;#038;set=a.248887665128061.84396.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=249791031704391&amp;amp;#038;set=a.248887665128061.84396.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=249792411704253&amp;amp;#038;set=a.248887665128061.84396.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=249792411704253&amp;amp;#038;set=a.248887665128061.84396.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=249794008370760&amp;amp;#038;set=a.248887665128061.84396.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=249794008370760&amp;amp;#038;set=a.248887665128061.84396.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soon we came to the way up out of the canyon.  It looked like nice long switchbacks, and we were glad.  Little did we know that we were in for straight-up, zipper switchbacks carved into the side of the mountain after  passing through a near slot canyon space that was filtering very welcome cool air through the rocks.  But the entire experience was well worth the panting effort to get back out, safe and sound and free of hexes&amp;hellip;.maybe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=249803251703169&amp;amp;#038;set=a.248887665128061.84396.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=249803251703169&amp;amp;#038;set=a.248887665128061.84396.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We made our way back to the car and no one exclaimed as we passed by, and that&amp;rsquo;s how Roxi got her new friend&amp;hellip;.Soxi.  Perhaps Soxi has some mysterious ways about him, but he seems happy to ride balanced in the crook of the assist handle by the windshield with Roxi in the higher crows nest handle, ready to assist with directions or provide refreshment at the campsites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=249806868369474&amp;amp;#038;set=a.248887665128061.84396.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=249806868369474&amp;amp;#038;set=a.248887665128061.84396.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day we went to Zion National Park, and even with its hulking mountains and merry running river in the desert, it hardly holds a candle to Bryce.  It&amp;rsquo;s a shame we didn&amp;rsquo;t see it first so that we could appreciate the majesty there without the spell of the hoodoos&amp;hellip;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tales from Vagabondia, the Ancient Way</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/tales-vagabondia/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/tales-vagabondia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Greetings from the middle of nowhere.  For real.  The nearest ATM is an almost 20-mile round trip.  Nearest Walmart is in Grants, NM, 40 miles one way.  Here is a mix of unique people dealing with life together in a secluded, beautiful place.  Life and living can be harsh in this high desert area, but to them it&amp;rsquo;s all worth it.  Here everyone is free to be themselves or figure out who that self might be or become.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone we met was just so friendly and caring, we felt almost like we just belonged here.  The natural setting, the people, the fresh air, the solitude combine to make this a very healing atmosphere to spend time in.  It&amp;rsquo;s a wonderful place to create art, whether it be with paint, music, percussion, cooking, collage, or arranging rocks on the ground, and to just find your expression.  If ever there was a place I could call Vagabondia, it&amp;rsquo;s here.  Don&amp;rsquo;t fit the normal city businessperson life?  Here may be where you could belong or reinvent yourself and claim a new name.  There&amp;rsquo;s no end to the possibilities here for doing good for others, the community, and for yourself, to grow and expand your personal and cultural horizons, even to be forced to learn and grow because of the conditions of life and living here.  Wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be an easy road, but few things really worth it are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Ancient Way Cafe and El Morro RV Park and surrounding businesses like the Old School Gallery and the Inscription Rock Trading and Coffee Co., with workers and customers coming from &amp;ldquo;nearby&amp;rdquo; towns, all seemed to blend to make a close community.  In my last post I mentioned most of the new friends we&amp;rsquo;ve made &amp;ndash; well, I wish I could develop friendships with them, but alas, we leave today after a final breakfast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, I probably have formed an idealistic impression of everything I&amp;rsquo;m talking about, but is that all bad, since I&amp;rsquo;m here and gone?  Vagabondia is an ideal in itself, after all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my favorite sayings &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(S)he who returns from a journey is not the same as (s)he who left. &amp;ndash;Chinese proverb&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;is certainly true here.  I will never be the same, having crossed the paths, however briefly, of those I met here.  Farewell and thank you all!  May all good things flow your way!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Tiki BaRV WAS heading for Mesa Verde to discover the ancient cliff dwellings and hike the paths the ancients took &amp;ndash; after a brief night in a motel to keep from freezing our pipes &amp;ndash; BUT our LP gas had some kind of a problem.  We seem to be running in circles, and we&amp;rsquo;re once again in Albuquerque camped in a park next door to Camping World.  Now the gas problem fixed itself.  Sheesh!  Stay tuned to see if we ever get out of NM or if we are stuck in a perpetual Groundhog Day movie!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers, everybody!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;imgur-embed-pub&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34; data-id=&#34;a/KOjZl&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;//imgur.com/a/KOjZl&#34;&gt;View post on imgur.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//s.imgur.com/min/embed.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Tiki BaRV -- a Reality!</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/tiki-barv-reality/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/tiki-barv-reality/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Tiki BarV is open!  Roxi is an excellent little proprietress serving up her special concoctions and showing off Speedy the snake to unsuspecting patrons.  She loves the traveling life and adventure.  Come see us if we come near your neck of the woods!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tent-sweet-tent lost its appeal fairly quickly.  It wasn&amp;rsquo;t bad, but all our stuff was jumbled in the back of the Montero, and I could never find what I needed without digging and many expletives.  For me, expletives mean I&amp;rsquo;m stressed, and that&amp;rsquo;s what we&amp;rsquo;re out here to get away from, right?  So we looked around and found this HUGE popup palace, and finally got it pretty well organized.   &amp;#8212; Ahhhh!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, how do we get rid of all that nice camping gear so we have room in the Montero and don&amp;rsquo;t have to lug an extra 200 pounds or so around the country?  We&amp;rsquo;re open to ideas, so please comment!  We have the tent and a ground tarp, suitcase kitchen, Coleman 2-burner gas stove , two double-height twin air beds, and an instant-up screen shelter.  I put up a CraigsList ad and will pull it if it doesn&amp;rsquo;t sell and run it at the next place.  Maybe a flea market, set it all up and hope it sells without wasting all day there.  Thoughts?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s kind of nice to have a &amp;ldquo;home&amp;rdquo; again.  The weather doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter quite so much, so we should be able to avoid the motels that we&amp;rsquo;ve been relying on too heavily so far, although if you come out to Abq, the Sandia Peak Inn is a great little budget motel with a wonderful owner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re both ready to leave Abq and start on this big adventure of ours.  Finally!  We&amp;rsquo;ve been trapped here by my surgery and getting the camper organized.  We&amp;rsquo;ve done a few cool local things, Sandia Peak drive and Bosque del Apache, but sitting here in the KOA isn&amp;rsquo;t our dream life.  We&amp;rsquo;re off tomorrow to head for Grants, NM, where we will see some very interesting things.  Stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tonight is celebration night, clam chowder, salmon patties, wine and cheese and crackers, with music from the computer!  Whoopeeeee!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://50.22.11.21/~dixonbui/vagabondians.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/meal.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone size-full wp-image-2962&#34; src=&#34;http://50.22.11.21/~dixonbui/vagabondians.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/meal.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;meal&#34; width=&#34;535&#34; height=&#34;258&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers, everybody!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>