<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jalisco on Vagabondians</title>
    <link>http://vagabondians.com/tags/jalisco/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Jalisco on Vagabondians</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright &amp;#169; by Glenn and Dixie Dixon</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vagabondians.com/tags/jalisco/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>MY TIKI BAR KITCHEN -- 1</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/my-tiki-bar-kitchen-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/my-tiki-bar-kitchen-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I know, tiki is so South Pacific and we’re in Mexico &amp;ndash; but it’s also retro American kitsch that evokes silliness and warmth and friends having cocktails at sunset. So grab your tiki mug and just go with me!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_m5djr07vUY1qzu24w.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what could be so different about food prep in Mexico? What’s the big deal? Well, for me, it is quite different and a challenge. I can’t really put my finger on one thing or one area and explain it to anyone, so there will be several articles in this series about food purchase, preparation, and cooking &amp;ndash; and some authentic Mexican recipes that I find easy and tasty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Disclaimer: First off, I’m no cocinera! I can cook basic stuff fairly well at home in the US. But when I came to Mexico, I found so many differences in the food and how it cooks and what’s available, that I had to stop and regroup and ask for help from an expert &amp;ndash; our Mexican housekeeper. (She came with the house-sit job &amp;ndash; score!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re going to explore shopping and cooking here in the state of Jalisco, Mexico.  From what I hear, this vast country has many styles, and each state is different. Hang onto your hats &amp;ndash; it&amp;rsquo;s not Tex Mex!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;May the roof above us never fall in, and may the friends gathered below it never fall out.-Unknown&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>