<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>California on Vagabondians</title>
    <link>http://vagabondians.com/tags/california/</link>
    <description>Recent content in California on Vagabondians</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright &amp;#169; by Glenn and Dixie Dixon</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vagabondians.com/tags/california/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Prairie Creek Redwoods State Park</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/exploring-prairie-creek-redwoods-state-park/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/exploring-prairie-creek-redwoods-state-park/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After our own big &amp;lsquo;day of discovery&amp;rsquo; with the Grove of Titans, the next day we moved on to Prairie Creek Redwoods State Park, home of some of the tallest Coast Redwoods. My hopes were not very high as the location of this grove is even more secret than the Grove of Titans. In addition, it is relatively easy to spot the huge misshapen behemoths that are the Titans when they are so much larger at ground level. In comparison, one of the tallest trees in the Atlas Grove is barely nine feet in circumference! Without our own expensive laser range finder or LIDAR unit it would be next to impossible to find this grove.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did hope for a glimpse of the Arco Giant which was supposedly visible from the meadow in front of the visitor center. I looked, but I did not find. In the meantime we checked out some park maps and decided to hike some of the trails. We started with a nice little half-mile loop that was supposed to be a simple nature trail. Unfortunately it wasn&amp;rsquo;t so simple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=277886715561489&amp;amp;#038;set=a.277885202228307.90476.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=277886715561489&amp;amp;#038;set=a.277885202228307.90476.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After crossing a small bridge, the trail was supposed to curve to the left then cross back over the creek again and lead back to the  visitor center. So we crossed the bridge and came to a sign which seemed to indicate that the nature trail went both left and right. I just assumed that perhaps the trail went a bit further than the map indicated so we turned left and marched on. The further we went, the more I began to notice some things. First, this trail did not seem to be as wide or well-worn as the other parts. Second, some downed limbs and even small trees had not been cleared from the trail. Third, we met no other hikers along the way. However, we did continue to see informational markers with various messages on them, so we continued on. Eventually we spied an RV on the other side of the creek. I knew that there was a campground over there, but I thought it was past the bridge we were looking for. Nevertheless, onward we pressed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=277889252227902&amp;amp;#038;set=a.277885202228307.90476.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=277889252227902&amp;amp;#038;set=a.277885202228307.90476.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually we concluded that we had hiked for a good mile and a half, perhaps two miles. I consulted the map again and discovered that the bridge we were looking for crossed the creek well &lt;em&gt;ahead&lt;/em&gt; of the camping area. We had flat out missed it somewhere. But rather than turn around, we decided to continue toward a bike trail that should have been just ahead. But it was not to be. The trail became fainter and more overgrown until it eventually just died out. It was an eerie feeling. We were deep in the woods, all alone. The large ferns spread up the hillsides among the giant hemlocks, the redwoods now conspicuously absent. We were wearing light jackets since the air was a bit cool and misty and the plants were shoulder high and sporting the occasional spider web, but inside we were drenched in sweat. We turned around for the march home. We tried one last shortcut at a spot where the creek was shallow and had just enough rocks and gravel to hop over, but there was no obvious trail there either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=277888068894687&amp;amp;#038;set=a.277885202228307.90476.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=277888068894687&amp;amp;#038;set=a.277885202228307.90476.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=277888598894634&amp;amp;#038;set=a.277885202228307.90476.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=277888598894634&amp;amp;#038;set=a.277885202228307.90476.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we retraced our route. I was more than a bit upset at the park for leaving this trail off the maps, yet not blocking it off at the entrance or somehow warning us off. But eventually we got back to the trailhead where we had first turned off, and that was when I looked at the sign from a different angle, and it all made sense. What had appeared to be a sign pointing right and left was actually a sign pointing down the trail and back up the trail in the direction we had originally come from. The trail we had taken actually had a signpost right in the middle of it, but the sign itself was missing. I&amp;rsquo;m betting it said something like &amp;ldquo;Trail Closed.&amp;rdquo; To further confuse matters, we had entered the nature trail from a completely different direction than I had intended. I thought it proceeded counter-clockwise from my position when in fact we were taking the clockwise route.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[NOTE: As it turns out, the trail we took is an abandoned section of what used to be a longer Nature Trail loop]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=277889802227847&amp;amp;#038;set=a.277885202228307.90476.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=277889802227847&amp;amp;#038;set=a.277885202228307.90476.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we went ahead and finished the nature trail. It was actually only one-half mile in length and took us back directly to the visitor center. After we got to the car, I changed shoes and I think shirts, then we had lunch on a bench and laughed at our stupid adventure. I decided I was done with trees for now, and we drove back to camp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=277890608894433&amp;amp;#038;set=a.277885202228307.90476.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=277890608894433&amp;amp;#038;set=a.277885202228307.90476.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/media/set/?set=a.277885202228307.90476.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/media/set/?set=a.277885202228307.90476.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grove of Titans</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/grove-titans/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/grove-titans/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Two of our favorite authors are &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.prestonchild.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Douglas Preston and Lincoln Child&lt;/a&gt;. You may have seen the movie &amp;lsquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.zuguide.com/#The-Relic&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The Relic&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo; which was based on some of their books. Douglas Preston has also written several non-fiction books which we love. Back in May of 2007 I stumbled across a book written by Douglas&amp;rsquo; brother, Richard, entitled &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0812975596/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=selfservehost-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=217145&amp;amp;creative=399369&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0812975596&#34;&gt;The Wild Trees: A Story of Passion and Daring&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img class=&#34; ahvsxllnypvwxbzmklmr&#34; style=&#34;border: none !important; margin: 0px !important;&#34; src=&#34;http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=&amp;l=as2&amp;o=1&amp;a=0812975596&amp;camp=217145&amp;creative=399369&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;1&#34; height=&#34;1&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; /&gt;. We were captivated and enthralled by these stories of people exploring vast acres of previously unexplored redwood forests and finding and climbing taller and taller trees. We began reading everything we could find about these trees, in print or on the internet. Scientists have found entire ecosystems living in the upper branches over 300 feet from the forest floor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though this was something we were fascinated by, we had no hope of actually seeing them until we began planning our RV road trip. As I began to look for more details it became apparent that the tallest trees for which a location was public were not actually the tallest trees any more. These scientists and enthusiasts were discovering new ones all the time! As a matter of fact, most of the 25 tallest trees were in undisclosed locations. My enthusiasm began to wane. Sure, we could still see massive Sequoias and tall Coast Redwoods, but the tallest trees would be off-limits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In late July while we were in California I began researching again and looking through my notes so we could pick a park to stay in that was convenient to the biggest trees. Most of the tallest trees were in undisclosed locations in Redwood National Park and Humboldt Redwoods State Park. It became evident that I would be unable to see them. The tallest ones we could access had once been the tallest of all, back in the late 1950&amp;rsquo;s.  Now they weren&amp;rsquo;t even in the top 40.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was, however, one other way of measuring trees, and that is their volume. A couple of groves have been found where the trees may not be the tallest, but they are massive. One such area is the Atlas Grove in Prairie Creek Redwoods State Park. The tree named Illuvatar is there, the 3rd largest Coast Redwood (in volume). It has more reiteration (new trunks growing from the main trunk) than any other known tree. It basically looks like its own little forest. Three other trees in this park are in the top 10 of the largest Coast Redwoods. But like most big trees, the locations are being kept secret.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The grove with the largest Coast Redwoods is the Grove of Titans in the Jedediah Smith Redwoods State Park. The only &amp;lsquo;official&amp;rsquo; grove of these redwoods in the park is the Stout Grove, with the Stout Tree being touted as the largest. In fact, it is now only 28th largest! Four of the top 10 largest Cost Redwoods are in the Grove of Titans. And while its location is still officially undisclosed, others have found it and are dropping hints all over the internet. Some wish it to be fully open to the public, others want the park to put boardwalks around it and make it an official trail, like the Stout Grove.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&#34;Stout Grove&#34; href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/48315294@N00/9145310200/&#34; rel=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; title=&#34;Stout Grove&#34; src=&#34;http://farm4.staticflickr.com/3833/9145310200_60224cc046_z.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Stout Grove&#34; width=&#34;360&#34; height=&#34;640&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To prevent the possible disclosure, some are putting misleading information out there, including pins on Google Maps. While I was trying to decipher all of the clues I made a discovery. I found an actual map of the location of the Grove of Titans! We were scheduled to be there within 48 hours! I was so excited.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On August 3rd we drove into the park. Actually, we came in on the opposite side from where I had intended, but as it turns out this was the closest way in to the grove. We parked and headed out the appropriate trail, with me occasionally checking the map images I had downloaded to my iPhone. After a few false starts, we came to a spot and saw what &lt;em&gt;might&lt;/em&gt; have been some large trees. It was difficult to tell, but the location matched the map. We waded through the underbrush no more than 300 feet or so, and there it was, a huge Coast Redwood. It was a mass of trees fused together near the base. It was the Fused Titan! We had found it, the Grove of Titans!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&#34;Fused Titan&#34; href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/48315294@N00/9143087303/&#34; rel=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; title=&#34;Fused Titan&#34; src=&#34;http://farm3.staticflickr.com/2880/9143087303_45a6a6b5c0_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Fused Titan&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; height=&#34;180&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a title=&#34;Fused Titan&#34; href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/48315294@N00/9145313678/&#34; rel=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; title=&#34;Fused Titan&#34; src=&#34;http://farm3.staticflickr.com/2838/9145313678_9f7e01eab5.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Fused Titan&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;281&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We marveled at its size. We took pictures. And then we consulted the map again, turned and headed toward the others. The next tree was the largest Coast Redwood known to man, the Lost Monarch. Somehow it was even larger than the previous one. Taking pictures is one thing, seeing it in person is quite another. And then the next tree, around a fallen giant, was El Viejo del Norte, with its signature &amp;lsquo;claw&amp;rsquo; extending towards the earth. Soon we climbed over another downed tree, or perhaps branch and found our way towards a large twin tree, fused near the base. But wait, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t the one we were looking for. That was the NEXT tree, the Screaming Titans! This pair of trees have fused from the ground up to a height of 20-25 feet. Their combined mass is possibly larger than many others, but because they are not technically one tree they don&amp;rsquo;t get categorized with all the rest. But at breast height they have a wider circumference than the massive Sequoia General Sherman!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a style=&#34;color: #0f3647;&#34; title=&#34;Lost Monarch&#34; href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/48315294@N00/9145312822/&#34; rel=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; title=&#34;Lost Monarch&#34; src=&#34;http://farm6.staticflickr.com/5479/9145312822_bb70dcc578_b.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Lost Monarch&#34; width=&#34;576&#34; height=&#34;1024&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a title=&#34;Lost Monarch&#34; href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/48315294@N00/9143085513/&#34; rel=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; title=&#34;Lost Monarch&#34; src=&#34;http://farm3.staticflickr.com/2825/9143085513_7ab319e123_c.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Lost Monarch&#34; width=&#34;450&#34; height=&#34;800&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a title=&#34;El Viejo del Norte&#34; href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/48315294@N00/9143088773/&#34; rel=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; title=&#34;El Viejo del Norte&#34; src=&#34;http://farm4.staticflickr.com/3676/9143088773_90caa5a5ef_z.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;El Viejo del Norte&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;360&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a title=&#34;El Viejo del Norte&#34; href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/48315294@N00/9145314794/&#34; rel=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; title=&#34;El Viejo del Norte&#34; src=&#34;http://farm6.staticflickr.com/5330/9145314794_29e49bed2e_z.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;El Viejo del Norte&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;360&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a title=&#34;Screaming Titans&#34; href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/48315294@N00/9143084179/&#34; rel=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; title=&#34;Screaming Titans&#34; src=&#34;http://farm4.staticflickr.com/3736/9143084179_449367ae07_b.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Screaming Titans&#34; width=&#34;576&#34; height=&#34;1024&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a title=&#34;Screaming Titans&#34; href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/48315294@N00/9143084179/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; title=&#34;Screaming Titans&#34; src=&#34;http://farm4.staticflickr.com/3736/9143084179_449367ae07_b.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Screaming Titans&#34; width=&#34;576&#34; height=&#34;1024&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;
  We spent at least an hour wandering the grove, taking it all in. Surprisingly we were not the only people there that day! Fortunately, the other explorer is someone who had previously discovered the grove and was giving his brother a tour. He gave us some clarifications on how to get to the other large tree, Del Norte which was across the river. Although we eventually found it we weren&#39;t prepared for water crossings and decided that we had seen enough for one day.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&#34;Sword Ferns&#34; href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/48315294@N00/9145309554/&#34; rel=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; title=&#34;Sword Ferns&#34; src=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7344/9145309554_7f7cecf4b8_z.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Sword Ferns&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;480&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although our trip is not yet over, I can&amp;rsquo;t imagine that anything will be able to surpass the feeling of standing in the middle of some of the world&amp;rsquo;s largest living creatures. I think it will be the highlight of our journey through America. Then again, in two days we will be in Yellowstone!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Lost Coast</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/lost-coast/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/lost-coast/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On August the first we took a recommended road to see some scenery. A fellow Escapee recommended it to us. It follows the same road that one takes to get to the Tall and Giant trees in the park, then continues on out to the coast. We already knew that the section through the park was a slow drive due to both roughness and lots of huge trees which force the road to wind around a lot. What we didn&amp;rsquo;t know is that the road is pretty much just as rough and windy all the way out. Cell phones don&amp;rsquo;t work out here. Hardly anyone lives out here. I discovered later that this region is called The Lost Coast, and is the most undeveloped part of all of California. I&amp;rsquo;m not surprised.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=272785119404982&amp;amp;#038;set=a.269971516353009.88935.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=272785119404982&amp;amp;#038;set=a.269971516353009.88935.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dixie tells me that the views were terrific, but I will have to take her word for that because I was unable to take my eyes off the road for more than a brief glimpse here and there. Bulls Creek Flats Road is the name while still inside Humboldt Redwoods State Park. It changes to Mattole Road about a mile before exiting the park. The park section also includes some switchbacks as one is either climbing or descending a ridge constantly. The topography of this region is so crazy that both the Federal Hwy. 101 and State Route 1 avoid it by turning inland. I&amp;rsquo;m not even sure who is responsible for the maintenance on this route. I suspect that the road has become lost too, considering the many potholes and sections where the asphalt has been washed out and never repaved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=269971636352997&amp;amp;#038;set=a.269971516353009.88935.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=269971636352997&amp;amp;#038;set=a.269971516353009.88935.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The road takes you through the small unincorporated communities of Honeydew and Petrolia and Capetown. I remember seeing a few places along the road with buildings, perhaps a gas station and convenience store, but this usually consists of an above-ground tank and old-school pumps. Most residents live in the hills, I guess. Supposedly almost 500 people live out here and many of them are completely off the grid. No kidding. Past Petrolia the road descends quickly to the ocean, where a nice long straight and flat stretch of road follows the coastline for a few miles. The beaches are black sand, and the view is very nice. We stopped for pictures and to just soak it in for a bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=272785236071637&amp;amp;#038;set=a.269971516353009.88935.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=272785236071637&amp;amp;#038;set=a.269971516353009.88935.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=272785312738296&amp;amp;#038;set=a.269971516353009.88935.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=272785312738296&amp;amp;#038;set=a.269971516353009.88935.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=272785372738290&amp;amp;#038;set=a.269971516353009.88935.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=272785372738290&amp;amp;#038;set=a.269971516353009.88935.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=269973049686189&amp;amp;#038;set=a.269971516353009.88935.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=269973049686189&amp;amp;#038;set=a.269971516353009.88935.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soon we were climbing the hills again and on our way to Ferndale, which I guess, among other things, could be called the gateway to the Lost Coast. Ferndale could also be called quirky. Many of the houses here are Victorian in architecture, and two local cemeteries are on hillsides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=269974343019393&amp;amp;#038;set=a.269971516353009.88935.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=269974343019393&amp;amp;#038;set=a.269971516353009.88935.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=269978146352346&amp;amp;#038;set=a.269971516353009.88935.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=269978146352346&amp;amp;#038;set=a.269971516353009.88935.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=269976636352497&amp;amp;#038;set=a.269971516353009.88935.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=269976636352497&amp;amp;#038;set=a.269971516353009.88935.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That by itself provides for quite a few interesting photographs. But every spring this town just goes completely nuts! That is when they host the annual &lt;a href=&#34;http://kineticgrandchampionship.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Kinetic Sculpture race&lt;/a&gt;. It started in 1969, when two artists built kontraptions with pedals and raced them down main street. It has since evolved into a three-day, 42-mile &amp;lsquo;Triathlon of Art&amp;rsquo; in which people pedal and push kontraptions over roads, across sand and mud and through the water. Fans follow along on bicycles. It is truly an event where participation and fun are valued above just being first. I dearly want to see this event some day, but we are here at the wrong time of the year. We did, however, get to see the museum! This building houses many past kinetic race vehicles. I think the photos speak for themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=269979746352186&amp;amp;#038;set=a.269971516353009.88935.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=269979746352186&amp;amp;#038;set=a.269971516353009.88935.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=269980536352107&amp;amp;#038;set=a.269971516353009.88935.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=269980536352107&amp;amp;#038;set=a.269971516353009.88935.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=269981006352060&amp;amp;#038;set=a.269971516353009.88935.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=269981006352060&amp;amp;#038;set=a.269971516353009.88935.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The race has now been replicated all over the world. See if you can &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kinetic_sculpture_race&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;find one near you&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/media/set/?set=a.269971516353009.88935.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/media/set/?set=a.269971516353009.88935.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Humboldt Redwoods</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/humboldt-redwoods/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/humboldt-redwoods/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On July 29th we left Napa Valley and drove up to the redwoods of Humboldt County.  Once you get near Humboldt Redwoods State Park you can take the scenic route dubbed Avenue of the Giants.  It is a two-lane road which winds through the edge of the forest, dodging giant redwoods all along the way.  Our destination was the &lt;a href=&#34;http://ancientredwoods.net&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Ancient Redwoods RV Park&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=269345949748899&amp;amp;#038;set=a.269345169748977.88781.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=269345949748899&amp;amp;#038;set=a.269345169748977.88781.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=269345949748899&amp;amp;#038;set=a.269345169748977.88781.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=269345949748899&amp;amp;#038;set=a.269345169748977.88781.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While we were there for a few nights we drove around the area, touring the sights and the trees.  The first day we hiked through a couple of trails, one leading to the three main trees which were deemed the tallest back in the late 1950&amp;rsquo;s.  They were given simple names like Giant Tree and Tall Tree.  One of them, the Dyerville Giant, fell in 1991, a victim of another tree which was knocked down by yet another tree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=269354069748087&amp;amp;#038;set=a.269345169748977.88781.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=269354069748087&amp;amp;#038;set=a.269345169748977.88781.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=269356309747863&amp;amp;#038;set=a.269345169748977.88781.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=269356309747863&amp;amp;#038;set=a.269345169748977.88781.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also visited the park visitor center and saw what is probably the first ever RV, the shell of which was made from a redwood trunk back in 1917.  The shell was attached to a Nash Quad chassis. You can read about Charles Kellogg and his Travel Log here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=269346699748824&amp;amp;#038;set=a.269345169748977.88781.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=269346699748824&amp;amp;#038;set=a.269345169748977.88781.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day we took a leisurely drive on a route recommended to us by JD, an Escapee we met at Park Sierra.  It starts off on the same road that leads to the Tall Tree trail, then continues on out to the coast, then north to Ferndale.  But I am guessing that it&amp;rsquo;s been a few years since JD has driven this road, because it is a mess!  The dips and potholes and washed out sections were constant for miles and miles.  The first time I could really stop and enjoy the view was when we got to the Pacific Ocean.  The views from there to Ferndale were gorgeous!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=269971636352997&amp;amp;#038;set=a.269971516353009.88935.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=269971636352997&amp;amp;#038;set=a.269971516353009.88935.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=269973049686189&amp;amp;#038;set=a.269971516353009.88935.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=269973049686189&amp;amp;#038;set=a.269971516353009.88935.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ferndale is a quirky little town. There are dozens of quaint little Victorian homes, cemeteries on a hillside and a strange race that began there in 1969.  The Kinetic Sculpture World Championship race, to be precise.  Unfortunately the race is held in May so we won&amp;rsquo;t be able to check it out in person, but we did visit the museum!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=269978146352346&amp;amp;#038;set=a.269971516353009.88935.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=269978146352346&amp;amp;#038;set=a.269971516353009.88935.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=269979746352186&amp;amp;#038;set=a.269971516353009.88935.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=269979746352186&amp;amp;#038;set=a.269971516353009.88935.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the way home we did one last hike on the Drury-Chaney Loop trail. The next morning we headed to Klamath.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/media/set/?set=a.269345169748977.88781.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/media/set/?set=a.269345169748977.88781.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/media/set/?set=a.269971516353009.88935.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;saved&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/media/set/?set=a.269971516353009.88935.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;saved&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Napa Valley</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/napa-valley/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/napa-valley/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our trip to Napa Valley didn&amp;rsquo;t start as we had planned. After leaving the wonderful &lt;a title=&#34;Park Sierra&#34; href=&#34;http://www.parksierra.net/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Escapee&amp;rsquo;s SKP Park Sierra&lt;/a&gt; north of Fresno we made the long haul drive out of the San Joaquin valley and then north on I-5. We made the usual pit stops for gas and snacks and bathroom visits, and we made decent time. We were slowing down to make the last turn from Hwy 12 to Hwy 29 when the trailer brakes clamped down and caused the tires to screech. WTF? We took it easy until we found a place to pull over and I got out to inspect things. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t pretty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Evidently one of the wheels on the left side had overheated and the grease was oozing out and slinging everywhere. We had some choices to make. After some discussion and some online searching we decided to backtrack a bit and drive the trailer over to the Camping World in Vacaville and park it. After we did that, we holed up in a nearby Motel 6 for the night. The next morning we were at the front doors when Camping World opened for business and talked to the service department. They were very busy and would take awhile to get to it so we went back to the motel and packed and checked out. Regardless the outcome on the trailer, this particular Motel 6 wasn&amp;rsquo;t worth extra nights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually we talked to a service rep and got the bad news. Evidently the bearings weren&amp;rsquo;t quite done correctly at the previous Camping World and when they overheated they took out the brake system with them. Two of the brake pads were cracked in half. All of them had excess grease in the drum. We finally opted to replace the entire brake system, just to be sure. Unfortunately the parts would not be in until Wednesday, so we found a half-way decent hotel and booked five days. I guess there are worse places to break down than Napa Valley, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next morning we drove north through the valley up to Calistoga and then began working our way back south, one winery at a time. We shared tastings in order to pace ourselves, and it helped to save money too as most of the wineries along the main road charge anywhere from $7 to $25 just to sip a little.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262588787091282&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262588787091282&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Calistoga was having a farmer&amp;rsquo;s market so we checked it out for a few minutes. An all-female group (&lt;a title=&#34;Sweet Burgundy&#34; href=&#34;http://www.myspace.com/sweetburgundy&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Sweet Burgundy&lt;/a&gt;) was playing acoustic tunes &amp;ndash; bass, rhythm and lead guitars. The town itself was just totally cute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262588997091261&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262588997091261&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our first winery was &lt;a title=&#34;Chateau Montelena&#34; href=&#34;http://montelena.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Chateau Montelena&lt;/a&gt;. It is the quintessential winery, with a main building looking much like its European predecessors. Their claim to fame is their 1973 Chardonnay which beat the French wines at an infamous blind tasting in Paris in 1976. You can get the basics and a lot of good entertainment from the movie version of events:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can get the full story in the book:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Montelena also has beautiful grounds, with a small lake and gazebos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262590947091066&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262590947091066&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262591977090963&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262591977090963&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sheer amount of acreage in this part of the state planted as vineyards is staggering. All of the valley floor and half the hillsides were completely covered, edge to edge with grapevines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262594457090715&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262594457090715&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next stop was the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.freemarkabbey.com//index.cfm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Freemark Abbey&lt;/a&gt; winery.  It was one of the wineries which had participated in the Judgment of Paris, and the only winery entered in both white and red wine categories.  It didn&amp;rsquo;t really fare that well, but we actually enjoyed some of their current selection!  We also met a couple who were having their first-ever wine tasting!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262592993757528&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262592993757528&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we left, we decided to try the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.adozenvintners.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;tasting room next door&lt;/a&gt;.  Nothing fancy here, no paths lined with stone walls, no chateau, just a plain little commercial building.  But they represented a dozen local smaller wineries.  The tasting was cheap, and since we did indeed buy some of their wine it was free!  The gentleman doing the pouring was Tim and he was a partner in one of the wines we tasted.  It was very nice, but out of our budget range.  What &lt;em&gt;was&lt;/em&gt; in our budget was an entire case of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eagleandrose.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Eagle and Rose&lt;/a&gt; Sangiovese on sale for $50!  Score!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262593480424146&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262593480424146&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next stop was &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.grgich.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Grgich Hills Estate&lt;/a&gt;.  Mike Grgich was the guy who actually did most of the work on the Chateau Montelena Chardonnay that won all the awards back in 1976, or at least that is the story.  I&amp;rsquo;m sure the high-dollar Chardonnay he still makes is good, but we weren&amp;rsquo;t wowed.  Very nice facility and staff though!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262593703757457&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262593703757457&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last stop of the day was at &lt;a href=&#34;http://folieadeux.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Folie a Deux&lt;/a&gt;, makers of one of our favorites &amp;ndash; Menage a Trois.  Very interesting building, wonderful grounds, knowledgeable staff and good wines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262596000423894&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262596000423894&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a few days of sightseeing in San Francisco we returned to the valley again, but I&amp;rsquo;ll save that for another post!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/media/set/?set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/media/set/?set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tales from the Tiki Bar:  Napa Valley, baby!</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/tales-tiki-bar-napa-baby/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/tales-tiki-bar-napa-baby/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Highway 29 from Napa to Calistoga will take you through a river of wine.  If each winery is a boulder, it&amp;rsquo;s a rapid run of gargantuan proportions. The term &amp;ldquo;highway&amp;rdquo; is kind of a misnomer too.  It&amp;rsquo;s a two-lane road winding through gorgeous wineries at about 35 mph. Sometimes it&amp;rsquo;s just a long line of cars, but mostly it kept moving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262594200424074&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262594200424074&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We decided to run the road to the far end and start from there.  As we drove we made a list of places we might want to stop and taste.  There&amp;rsquo;s even Old Faithful Geyser of California on the edge of Calistoga.  We decided to pass that one up in anticipation of the granddaddy of old faithful geysers at Yellowstone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We began the serious part of the jaunt at Calistoga, which is a cute town in its own right, full of shops and tasting rooms and a foodie&amp;rsquo;s delight.  The public market/farmers market was in full swing.  Not large, but colorful, and everything from fresh turnips and flowers to arts and crafts and African woven baskets and fans to gourmet treats and even a pretty good trio of ladies singing and playing instruments.  Just behind them, a nice creek with a bridge and a local chocolate lab taking a nice swim to cool off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262589513757876&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262589513757876&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262589730424521&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262589730424521&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First stop was Chateau Montelena of &lt;em&gt;Bottle Shock&lt;/em&gt; fame.  It was a great movie with lots of &amp;ldquo;poetic license&amp;rdquo; involved.   We were told the book has the real story, so now I must read.  We shared a tasting of 5 superb wines for $20 there and ended up buying a bottle of red zinfandel to save for our 21st anniversary in September.  A tasting there includes your own private pour person instead of one person covering 10-15 people, and she was fun and knowledgeable. The grounds were beautiful, including a lake with a path to two gazebo islands with beautifully set tables to rent for occasions.  They had a large Coastal Redwood they planted in 1990 that was now about 150 ft. high, I think.  In about 500-1000 years it will be among the giants, if conditions are right there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262592250424269&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262592250424269&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262590947091066&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262590947091066&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lunch was next on the list, tasty burgers and fries at a quaint little place there in Calistoga.  Next!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Freemark Abbey winery.  We met a nice young couple tasting next to us who were fairly new to wine and this was their first winery.  The wines and conversation were lively between us and our pour person. (I just like that title I made up.  What are they really called?)  The best was a bonus taste of their dessert white wine.  A little taste of heaven trickling down your throat!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262592993757528&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262592993757528&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hm, what&amp;rsquo;s this, A Dozen Vintners next door?  We can get an overview of several boutique wineries in one place.  We&amp;rsquo;re the only ones there and our host, Tim Mertz, was perfectly awesome!  The shared tasting was, I think, $10, waived if you purchase something, and off we went.  I don&amp;rsquo;t remember how many wines, maybe eight &amp;ndash; or fifteen?  Who knows!  It was a delightful afternoon of wine and conversation.  We stayed there quite some time and left with a case -yes, case! &amp;ndash; of a nice sangiovese for 50 bucks (!) that was one of the last on sale.  Tasted it at the end so we know it was pretty good.  I hope.  Nexsht!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262593480424146&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262593480424146&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe we ought to walk around a bit before going into the next winery?  The slow drive brought us to Grgich Hills Estate (not a drunken typo). The vintner was also involved in the &lt;em&gt;Bottle Shock&lt;/em&gt; saga.  It was very pretty and they had some nicely priced gift boxes and souvenirs and an exhibit about their famous wine.  We weren&amp;rsquo;t overly impressed with the actual wines, good, not excellent.  Back out into the perfect summer day.  Are we done yet?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262593833757444&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262593833757444&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nope.  Just *had* to stop in at Folie a Deux/Napa Cellars where they make one of our favorites, *Menage a Trois.  *The shared tasting there was only $7, and they had samples of some really brilliant dipping sauces.  Yum!  Our pour guy there was fun too.  And we got double tastes of two wines, before-and-after glasses, one out of the newly opened bottle and one run through the Vinturi Red Wine Aerator.  We thought we could actually taste a slight difference &amp;ndash; but by that time, who really knows!  We spent some time on the parklike grounds among the grapevines with actual fruit hanging before taking off for home.  It was sunny, about 75 degrees, slight cool breeze, bright green grass, grapevines, blooming flowers and lavender&amp;hellip;..aaaaaah, perfection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262595023757325&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262595023757325&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A VOTRE SANTE&lt;/em&gt;!  CHEERS!  SALUTE!  &lt;em&gt;clink&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_0:6d6904fc67a34897a8c2b08f006285ca&#34;&gt;**&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;** {#product-name}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262596513757176&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262596513757176&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/media/set/?set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;notif_t=like&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/media/set/?set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;notif_t=like&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tales from the Tiki Bar:  Awesome People</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/tales-tiki-bar-awesome-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/tales-tiki-bar-awesome-people/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve had an interesting couple of days with our rig.  I say rig.  It&amp;rsquo;s a rig to us.  But I digress.  Already.  Anyway, we discovered a leak under the kitchen sink.  Not a big one, but big enough to do damage if we didn&amp;rsquo;t get it fixed right away.  We were getting ready to pack up and move from McAlpine Lake campground to near YOSEMITE &amp;ndash; yay!  Glenn investigated and determined where the little leak was and that he couldn&amp;rsquo;t fix it. So we had to take a side trip to the nearest Camping World since we have a comprehensive warranty.  $50 at any CW takes care of it.  Called the place and they&amp;rsquo;re booked and can&amp;rsquo;t fix it for a few days, so we drive there anyway to see if we can get any action or even parts to try to DIY.  The desk guy said, oh, no, you have to take it to where you bought the camper.  Albuquerque, NM?  We can&amp;rsquo;t do that.  So you want to talk to the supervisor?  Um, yeah.  Enter Max Hayes, the service manager and our hero!  He just jumped in and said, come on, let&amp;rsquo;s take a look, pull it in over here.  We took off the outer cover and he looked at it and proceeded to send someone out to get some parts and fixed it himself in an hour and a half.  Charge?  $20.  Even.  What?  Are you sure?  Yep, $20.  Max Hayes at the Camping World in San Martin, CA!  CHEERS!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This on top of another great experience the day before.  Our battery was acting kind of hinky like it might want to strand us somewhere when we least need that to happen &amp;ndash; like ANYtime.  Just a bit of hesitation when starting up.  So after leaving the beach in Santa Cruz we stopped in Scotts Valley, CA, at Batteries Plus to get their free battery test/evaluation.  Bryan Parker was ever so helpful.  He took his handy-dandy battery widget out there  and tested whatnot, showing us what was going on with the battery.  He got us a very reasonable-priced battery and proceeded to wrestle in the hot sun with our Montero, who didn&amp;rsquo;t want to give up its battery.  He worked like crazy to get the problem solved and the new battery in and the connections all cleaned up.  A very personable and interesting fellow, we had a great conversation as he worked.  When it was finally extracted, we discovered a 4-year-old battery on its last legs.  We are glad to have met Bryan who gave us excellent customer service.  SAAA-LUTE!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love being on the road.  The people you meet tell the most interesting tales and are the real gems of a big trip.  There are still people out there who care what happens to strangers and go out of their way to just be nice.  &amp;rdquo;It&amp;rsquo;s not my job&amp;rdquo; did not apply here, and we are oh, so thankful!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now we are ensconced in a wonderful camp 24 miles south of Yosemite, crown jewel of U.S. parks waiting for the weekend crowds to go home!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tales from the Tiki Bar:  The Universe Speaks!</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/tales-tiki-bar-universe-speaks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/tales-tiki-bar-universe-speaks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We should have listened!  We should have accepted the help offered after we had asked for help!  Duh! It was an awesome adventure that we missed out on, and it led to a low-level disaster.  There&amp;rsquo;s an important lesson in serendipity here:  Don&amp;rsquo;t swim against the tide &amp;ndash; just go with it. Isn&amp;rsquo;t that what we&amp;rsquo;re out here for?  GAH!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Internet and Facebook are awesome tools for a lot of things.  We needed a place to stay, it was generously offered, and instead of going with it and seeing what interesting people we could be with, we kept trying to be independent, looking for another campground and found it at the very last minute.  The new camp was a difficult path, and the serendipity path was easy.  Turns out we got offered a driveway, and she lived just south of where we were camped = Easy.  New campground was just a little too far to try to make it on time = Hard. We should have taken the hint from &amp;ldquo;the universe.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=251489888201172&amp;amp;#038;set=a.251489704867857.85034.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=251489888201172&amp;amp;#038;set=a.251489704867857.85034.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We already had planned to meet Kirby from Dixie&amp;rsquo;s high school for breakfast  to discuss staying in her driveway a few days so nobody would feel stuck/obligated if things weren&amp;rsquo;t going to work out.  Turns out we all hit it off, and it sounded like we would have had a great time if we stayed there. Kirby rocks! She was so much fun! We were a bit sorry we had found a place, but no, we didn&amp;rsquo;t change our mind and stay. Instead, we hurriedly finished packing up and took off out of our camp trying to make it before the new campground closed for the night. Made it about halfway before we discovered our next blunder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had taken off down the road with the main storage door open.  It had to happen.  We actually had congratulated ourselves that nothing bad had happened to us yet and said we still need to make that exit checklist. Yep!  Lost the main camper crank (the one the salesman told us not to lose!) and the stabilizer feet crank and some wood blocks for the feet and the two plastic wheel chocks. Stabilizer crank was easily replaced, but the main crank, not so much.  Going to have to special-order it from Jayco.  Hope we can even get it, since they changed the design.  Can&amp;rsquo;t even talk to them till after Monday July 4. So we shopped and shopped and finally came up with a way to get the camper up, but it&amp;rsquo;s not easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were attempting to stretch our dollars by seeking help, but we ended up having to buy some extra tools and stay the night in a motel in Bakersfield and missed out on an adventure.  GAH!  Not only that, but we had to change our mind and delay that particular camp we were trying to make because we hadn&amp;rsquo;t noticed that the temps were going to soar well over 100 for the next 5-6 days!  So here we go:  high-tail it back towards the coast over two mountain areas with our underpowered vehicle and heavy trailer.  We are waiting out the heatwave in a more expensive campground in kind of a nowhere place. Probably should have run right back to LA, hat in hand, and parked at Kirby&amp;rsquo;s.  Double-GAH!  Hope we don&amp;rsquo;t regret sticking ourselves here for a week.  No refunds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But thank you, Kirby, for the kind offer, not even knowing really who we were.  You are an exceptional person, and I hope we get to meet again in the future.  As for us&amp;hellip;.I hope we learn to go with opportunities that present instead of just trying to press on and stick to a plan that&amp;rsquo;s going bad on us!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, where has Roxi gone off to?  We need for her to open the Tiki Bar!  To serendipity! Cheers, everybody!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>