<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>New Mexico on Vagabondians</title>
    <link>http://vagabondians.com/tags/new-mexico/</link>
    <description>Recent content in New Mexico on Vagabondians</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright &amp;#169; by Glenn and Dixie Dixon</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vagabondians.com/tags/new-mexico/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Albuquerque, New Mexico -- May 3-8</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/albuquerque-mexico-3-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/albuquerque-mexico-3-8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tuesday we packed it all up and headed west. We somehow completely missed Cadillac Ranch! Oh well, at least we&amp;rsquo;ve been there before&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We briefly celebrated our passage across the New Mexico border and then continued west. The view from the road is mostly desert out here. If it wasn&amp;rsquo;t for the signs at the border, you&amp;rsquo;d never know the difference between the Texas panhandle and eastern New Mexico. We stopped briefly for gas at a small mom-and-pop station, and we also took a few pictures at Santa Rosa. Original Route 66 architecture and signage is rare, but they have a few places in every town. I enjoy trying to spot the old stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/nb4p9nC.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Original Route 66&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we arrived in Albuquerque we made our way to Sandia Peak Inn on the Historic Route 66. We found out about this little place from Trip Advisor where it gets rave reviews. The owners (Kay and her husband) moved from India to California in the &amp;lsquo;70&amp;rsquo;s. After the kids had all gone to college they moved to Albuquerque and bought a piece of land in a part of town that had become a bit run-down. The one structure on this lot was a motel that rented by the hour, and not surprisingly the main clientele were there for drugs or prostitution. They demolished that building and put up a very nice hotel from scratch. The owners live on the premises, so it is an odd cross between a hotel and a bed and breakfast. Over the years they have slowly but surely upgraded and maintained everything. The architecture and stucco and paint gives you the impression that it could have been an original old Route 66 facility. In fact, it is less than ten years old.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/sa7a3Q5.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;New-old&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kay is the main person you will deal with, and she takes hospitality and customer service very seriously. If you use a coupon from one of the books you pick up at the visitor center, you will get a basic room on the second floor. But if any other room is available, Kay will be sure to offer you an upgrade for a very minimal price. Large-screen LCD TV&amp;rsquo;s and whirlpool baths are usually available. They also have a laundry room and a heated indoor pool as well. All of this will set you back $50-60 per night. In case you couldn&amp;rsquo;t tell, Dixie and I thoroughly enjoyed this place!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For dinner our first night in town we chose the St. Clair Winery and Bistro. We tasted a flight and eventually chose a glass to go with. Both the wine and the food were great!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/XlpH6jJ.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Wine!&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day we did some work and then took a break and did a short hike through the Petroglyph National Monument just before they closed. The trails are mostly sand, the petroglyphs are all on volcanic rock. We did get to see some interesting wildlife though&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/2QMwlvV.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Ancient art&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Thursday we began our search for a popup camper in earnest. We drove through all of the RV dealerships on the east side of town, still on Route 66. We also found a nice Fleetwood on Craigslist. The only negative was the price, a bit steep for us. We also found what would eventually be our popup, a large dual-axle 14-foot Jayco Eagle. Everything seemed to work, but since it was on consignment the dealer was due to inspect it and make sure that it was safe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Friday morning we went hiking along the Rio Grande. The trail was full of runners and bicycles, so we took the first bridge we could over the levee and hiked down to the river itself to enjoy the view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/IIegE9d.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Dixie down at the river&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That night we vacated the hotel and set up camp at the KOA on the north side of town, in the suburb of Bernalillo. It is mostly quiet, the staff is wonderful, and you get free coffee and pancakes every morning! Hard to beat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;imgur-embed-pub&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34; data-id=&#34;a/ZNHB5&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;//imgur.com/a/ZNHB5&#34;&gt;Albuquerque, NM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//s.imgur.com/min/embed.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tales from the Tiki Bar, Tinkertown</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/tales-tiki-bar-tinkertown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/tales-tiki-bar-tinkertown/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Wow.  If you come to Albuquerque, one thing not to be missed is Ross and Carla Ward&amp;rsquo;s Tinkertown Museum.  Fabulous collection of the whimsical and historical along with Ross&amp;rsquo; skillfully and lovingly carved Old West figures in their tiny town dioramas.  My favorite part was the full miniature circus, complete with authentic carney banners &amp;ndash; authentic because the artist himself was a real circus banner painter &amp;ndash; and original photos from the old circus and carney days.  There&amp;rsquo;s a collection of old coin-operated mechanical arcade machines, a fortune teller, try-your-luck, one-man band and other wonders of days gone by.  It&amp;rsquo;s like the ghost of Coney Island pre-&amp;lsquo;50s!  And this is the highest port in the country since the Theodora R is at her final dock there after sailing around the world on a great adventure.  I could happily spend days there and never really see everything.  Here is a&lt;a href=&#34;http://itchyfeettraveler.com/Tinkertown_Museum.aspx&#34; title=&#34;Tinkertown Museum&#34;&gt; link to a fellow traveler&amp;rsquo;s blog&lt;/a&gt; who describes this place in word and picture far better than I ever could:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check it out!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://50.22.11.21/~dixonbui/vagabondians.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/06/RoxiChicken1.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignleft wp-image-2998 size-medium&#34; src=&#34;http://50.22.11.21/~dixonbui/vagabondians.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/06/RoxiChicken1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;RoxiChicken1&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Roxi loved the place even more than we did, since she&amp;rsquo;s, uh, small.  She got to keep the card from the antique magical fortune-telling machine lady, and she&amp;rsquo;s now the proud owner of her own mini rubber chicken &amp;ndash; ya just can&amp;rsquo;t be a real bartender without a rubber chicken, after all!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://50.22.11.21/~dixonbui/vagabondians.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/06/TRex.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright wp-image-3020 size-medium&#34; src=&#34;http://50.22.11.21/~dixonbui/vagabondians.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/06/TRex.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;TRex&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;We also visited the New Mexico Museum of Natural History and Science for a few hours this morning.  Fascinating exhibits on dinosaurs, volcanos, caves, space, computers, and more.  The volunteer docents in each area just love to talk to you and tell you all about the exhibits, and they are deeply knowledgeable about their subjects.  Show an interest and get a great education.  A+++ museum!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On another note, the smoke did clear eventually here during the morning, so we were lamenting not going ahead and going up to Bandelier today. So we&amp;rsquo;re going tomorrow and hoping for the best.  It&amp;rsquo;s not a place to be skipped if we can help it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So as the daylight is starting to fade, we&amp;rsquo;re back in our little Tiki BaRV as the afternoon winds pick up for our daily sandblasting.  Roxi will be opening the  bar soon.  Come join us for a cocktail!  Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning to Chill</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/learning-chill/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/learning-chill/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I normally think of myself as a fairly laid back person, moreso than most.  And yet even I have my moments where I get frustrated.  It isn&amp;rsquo;t pretty.  Today was one of those days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were a lot of factors, but the one issue that was at the root of it was our propane gas in the popup.  Earlier in the week we found that the gas was leaking from somewhere around the main cylinder valve.  Ortega&amp;rsquo;s in Grants, New Mexico went above and beyond in attempting to fix the leak but finally had to resort to replacing the main valve itself.  Of course, in order to do this they first had to bleed off the gas in the cylinder.  We just paid $15 to have the cylinder filled, so we flushed that money down the drain.  And once the new valve was in place, we had to fill the tank again!  But all that was worth it just to have gas for cooking, hot water and to help supplement the electric heater which struggled to keep us warm in the cold mountain air.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And for a few days everything was just fine.  Then the furnace quit.  It would attempt to light a few times and stop.  I checked the water heater.  The pilot light would light, but no flame.  The stovetop burners would light then quickly go out.  The tank gauge didn&amp;rsquo;t indicate that the tank was very low, but I thought maybe we used so much gas with the furnace that we had lowered the pressure too much.  I decided to have the cylinder refilled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The good news is that there was a big propane tank and refilling station right there in the El Morro RV park!  The bad news is that the only person who knew how to operate it was the owner, who was not yet returned from a vacation to Ireland.  Crap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At about that time I checked the weather forecast and noticed that a late-season freeze was about to hit.  It was just for one night, so we headed to Gallup, New Mexico for an evening at a La Quinta.  Our reward points dropped the cost to $30, an extra bonus!  We then drove around town looking for groceries and a place to refill the propane cylinder.  Once again, being full-time travelers caught us off-guard.  Holiday?  Oh yeah, we remember those.  So the propane shops and banks are all closed for Memorial Day.  Guess we will wait till tomorrow to fill the gas!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then this morning arrived.  For some reason I got frustrated about still being in New Mexico and having to drive all the way to eastern Utah just to have to turn back around and drive right back down to I-40.  We were already on I-40 for crying out loud!  And we&amp;rsquo;ve been in this state almost an entire month!  We&amp;rsquo;ll never make half of the places we plan to visit at this rate!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I moaned and whined about this for awhile, and then we finally got ready to go and headed for a propane dealer.  Google Maps took me to a spot in the middle of nowhere about five miles south of town.  There was a small ranch there, and nothing that looked like a propane dealer.  A quick phone call confirmed my suspicions.  I drove back to I-40, went west a few miles then pulled in to Gallup Propane.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The kid working the pump seemed surprised to see our tank bolted to the tongue.  Evidently no one does that any more (thanks Camping World!)  So he disconnected it and picked it up.  I think he started suspecting a joke at this point.  He said it didn&amp;rsquo;t seem like it needed any fuel.  He put it up on the scales.  55 pounds, give or take a bit.  That&amp;rsquo;s a completely full tank!  What the hell?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He connected an open-ended Acme valve and gas blew out full force when the valve was opened.  At this point the suspicion fell on our Acme valve, the pigtail, or some other part of the piping in the system.  Either we had a massive leak or blockage.  I began to think it was good we bought a full extended warranty!  We left and drove to a nearby truck stop to take a potty break and think about things for awhile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our next obvious stop was Camping World.  Warranty repair onsite had a $50 deductible vs work done elsewhere.  Plus they had other parts we wanted:  a second cylinder and some other way of attaching the cylinders to the tongue.  Maybe a cover as well.  But which one?  It was 130 miles to go back to Albuquerque, 185 to the one in Flagstaff, Arizona.  I liked the idea of moving forward, but it would mean missing out on Mesa Verde and Arches National Park.  We looked up the phone number for the Flagstaff Camping World.  This is what it said on their web site:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Important Notice: Due to tornado damage, our Flagstaff location is closed until further notice. We apologize for any inconvenience this may cause to our customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HELL?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since when do they have freakin&amp;rsquo; tornadoes in Flagstaff?  I couldn&amp;rsquo;t believe what I was reading.  We both laughed at how ridiculous this was all becoming.  We did some math on the mileage options.  In the end the solution with the least amount of extra miles was to go back to Albuquerque.  It was a long, windy drive.  The Montero drug the trailer back up over the Continental Divide at around 45-50mph.  We survived all the 30-35mph winds, the extra turbulence from all of the big rigs and motorhomes that passed us.  I watched the massive miles and miles of lava at El Malpais pass by our windows again.  It was as if New Mexico was laughing at us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally we arrived at Camping World.  We knew we would be too late for service so our plan was to set up at the RV park right behind the store and test the gas connections one more time.  So we pulled into the Enchanted Trails RV park and got a really good deal on a full hook-up site &amp;ndash; $15 a night!  We blocked, unhitched, leveled, raised, unfurled, braced and connected everything.  It was time.  I made sure the gas was connected and the valve was open.  The water heater pilot light barely lit, but it would not ignite.  The stovetop burners were the same.  One of them lit briefly, then nothing.  I inspected the lines under the trailer.  No obvious breaks or kinks, no rock damage.  I disconnected the Acme valve from the tank and inspected it.  Nothing obvious, nothing in the gauge.  I held the valve down and whacked it a few times on the tongue, just to see if I could dislodge anything.  Again, nothing obvious.  I reconnected it and went inside to test it just one more time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Flame.  Glorious flame!  All three burners!  I lit the water heater pilot light and turned the dial &amp;#8212; whomp-whoosh!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So.  Basically we are back in Albuquerque for no real good reason.  We could be camped near Mesa Verde right now.  However, we have worked out a compromise.  Tomorrow we will hit up Camping World for parts.  I bet they will be surprised to see us again!  Then we will book it on up to Bandelier National Monument to see the cliff dwellings there.  Hopefully that will assuage Dixie for not being able to go to Mesa Verde.  And as for Arches National Park, it&amp;rsquo;s just too far out of our way.  It has been officially scratched from our schedule.  In a few days we will head west on I-40 again, and maybe &amp;#8212; MAYBE &amp;#8212; this time we just might actually make it out of this state!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tales from Vagabondia, the Ancient Way</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/tales-vagabondia/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/tales-vagabondia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Greetings from the middle of nowhere.  For real.  The nearest ATM is an almost 20-mile round trip.  Nearest Walmart is in Grants, NM, 40 miles one way.  Here is a mix of unique people dealing with life together in a secluded, beautiful place.  Life and living can be harsh in this high desert area, but to them it&amp;rsquo;s all worth it.  Here everyone is free to be themselves or figure out who that self might be or become.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone we met was just so friendly and caring, we felt almost like we just belonged here.  The natural setting, the people, the fresh air, the solitude combine to make this a very healing atmosphere to spend time in.  It&amp;rsquo;s a wonderful place to create art, whether it be with paint, music, percussion, cooking, collage, or arranging rocks on the ground, and to just find your expression.  If ever there was a place I could call Vagabondia, it&amp;rsquo;s here.  Don&amp;rsquo;t fit the normal city businessperson life?  Here may be where you could belong or reinvent yourself and claim a new name.  There&amp;rsquo;s no end to the possibilities here for doing good for others, the community, and for yourself, to grow and expand your personal and cultural horizons, even to be forced to learn and grow because of the conditions of life and living here.  Wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be an easy road, but few things really worth it are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Ancient Way Cafe and El Morro RV Park and surrounding businesses like the Old School Gallery and the Inscription Rock Trading and Coffee Co., with workers and customers coming from &amp;ldquo;nearby&amp;rdquo; towns, all seemed to blend to make a close community.  In my last post I mentioned most of the new friends we&amp;rsquo;ve made &amp;ndash; well, I wish I could develop friendships with them, but alas, we leave today after a final breakfast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, I probably have formed an idealistic impression of everything I&amp;rsquo;m talking about, but is that all bad, since I&amp;rsquo;m here and gone?  Vagabondia is an ideal in itself, after all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my favorite sayings &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(S)he who returns from a journey is not the same as (s)he who left. &amp;ndash;Chinese proverb&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;is certainly true here.  I will never be the same, having crossed the paths, however briefly, of those I met here.  Farewell and thank you all!  May all good things flow your way!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Tiki BaRV WAS heading for Mesa Verde to discover the ancient cliff dwellings and hike the paths the ancients took &amp;ndash; after a brief night in a motel to keep from freezing our pipes &amp;ndash; BUT our LP gas had some kind of a problem.  We seem to be running in circles, and we&amp;rsquo;re once again in Albuquerque camped in a park next door to Camping World.  Now the gas problem fixed itself.  Sheesh!  Stay tuned to see if we ever get out of NM or if we are stuck in a perpetual Groundhog Day movie!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers, everybody!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;imgur-embed-pub&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34; data-id=&#34;a/KOjZl&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;//imgur.com/a/KOjZl&#34;&gt;View post on imgur.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//s.imgur.com/min/embed.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tails from the Tiki Bar</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/tails-tiki-bar/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/tails-tiki-bar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[written 5/25/2011]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, tails &amp;ndash; great, furry, wagging, flagging tails!  We visited the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wildspiritwolfsanctuary.org/index.php&#34;&gt;Wild Spirit Wolf Sanctuary&lt;/a&gt; today (Wednesday) after a long, leisurely hike at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nps.gov/elmo/index.htm&#34;&gt;El Morro&lt;/a&gt;, the historic inscription rock with signatures and sentiments of travelers to this only sure watering hole dating from the 1600s and petroglyphs up to 1000 years old and native ruins atop a high bluff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The wolves were awesome with their amber eyes and musical howls.  The whole place erupted in greeting (chow time, new meat? LOL) as we began our tour with Mikel from Sweden.  Mikel and his girlfriend Jane, who was &amp;ldquo;giftshop girl&amp;rdquo; that day so didn&amp;rsquo;t get to give tours, came all the way from Sweden just to volunteer at the wolf sanctuary.  She said there are only a few over 200 wolves left in Sweden, and their government is allowing hunting of them again.  They are here to learn for 6 months and take back knowledge to join the fight to save Swedish wolves from extinction. Lofty goals for for these great 20-somethings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back to the wolves in their large, somewhat sculpted enclosures for each male/female pair (neutered, not breeding pairs!) and two &amp;ldquo;packs.&amp;rdquo;  Many of their names were changed because they get too many named Dakotas, Cheyennes, etc.  All their animals are captive-bred wolves or wolf-dogs with sad stories of money-grubbing breeders and owners who suddenly discovered their wild animal wasn&amp;rsquo;t suitable for their household. Ya think?!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://50.22.11.21/~dixonbui/vagabondians.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/Wolf2.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone size-full wp-image-2952&#34; src=&#34;http://50.22.11.21/~dixonbui/vagabondians.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/Wolf2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Wolf2-540x195&#34; width=&#34;540&#34; height=&#34;195&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you breed a wolf and a dog, you never know how much wolf will be in each of the several pups.  All in a litter can be totally different.  We learned about wolf vs. dog behaviors and physical build.  It was fascinating. This sanctuary runs totally on voluntary donations of meat, money, and time, and workers live on property.  If you come to NM, be sure to come see the wolves!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are still at the El Morro RV Park with the Ancient Way Cafe.  The cast of characters here is fabulous.  This little artsy community in the middle of nowhere mostly take chosen names over their given names, and they are a very colorful, tight-knit group.  We have Maqui, the camp manager with Guido, the big fuzzy dog; Red Wulf Running Bare &amp;ndash; yes, bare, the baker; Standing Feather the chef, Amy the waitress; Rosie, another cook; Genevieve, who runs the gallery across the street; and the many other locals that come into the cafe.  Many of the community  just did a production of a play, Sordid Lives, up in Gallup and received rave reviews.  I only wish we had been able to be there.  Descriptions and photos just aren&amp;rsquo;t enough.  I love this place!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Roxi is working on getting a better wine selection for the bar and developing some signature cocktails.  She and Speedy send their love and wish you all well!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vive les Français!</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/vive-le-francais/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/vive-le-francais/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Saturday evening (May 14) we returned to camp at the Bernalillo, NM KOA to discover a van full of French youth at the spot next to ours. (L-R &amp;ndash; John, Salome, Julien, Regis)  We introduced ourselves and had a nice long chat, exchanging information and tips.  They have been in Canada for the last year on a work visa, working odd jobs for awhile in Vancouver, then eventually at the ski facilities at Whistler.  Although they are all from France, they didn&amp;rsquo;t know each other until they met in Vancouver! They are now taking a brief tour through the U.S. before going home.  Two of them flew back to Montreal Tuesday to make the connection to Paris, the other two are driving back to Montreal in their van.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately for us, their English is excellent!  We enjoyed the conversation, and whatever they cooked that evening smelled so amazingly delicious I almost invited myself over for dinner.  They have somehow managed to transport four people and all of their gear across half of Canada, down through the upper MidWest, back over to Oregon and California, and eventually here to New Mexico in a GMC Safari van.  Regis and Julien shared a tent, the John and Salome shared an inflatable bed they somehow managed to set up inside the van.  They were kind enough to let us take some pictures of their gear organization and themselves (see below).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They are blogging about their adventures, mostly in French with some English thrown in.  You can read more at &lt;a title=&#34;COBElife&#39;s Great Adventure&#34; href=&#34;http://www.travelpod.com/travel-blog/cobelife/1/tpod.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;COBE life&lt;/a&gt;.  Au revoir!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;imgur-embed-pub&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34; data-id=&#34;a/SoYcO&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;//imgur.com/a/SoYcO&#34;&gt;View post on imgur.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//s.imgur.com/min/embed.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Bigger Tent -- on Wheels</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/bigger-tent-wheels/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/bigger-tent-wheels/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There is a saying in the RV world, especially true for those who intend to travel full-time:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Buy your third RV first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course most people start with a small travel trailer and graduate to a larger fifth-wheel.  Others start with a little Class C motor home (built on a van chassis) and end up driving one of those monster buses.  I think it is safe to say that Dixie and I are one of the very few to even attempt to travel full-time in nothing but a car and a tent.  As you know, the car required a quick upgrade to an SUV due to sheer overload.  But the tent worked fine, except that it quickly became obvious that steering clear of bad weather put us in a motel room far too often.  So we started looking at an upgrade and eventually found a used Jayco 14SO popup tent camper in decent condition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have seen this unit referred to as &amp;lsquo;the palace&amp;rsquo; and for good reason.  It might sound silly at first, but in the popup tent camper world, this Jayco unit is the king-sized luxury model.  The main box is 14 feet long, 19 if you include the hitch.  But when the beds are folded out the length is a crazy 26 feet.  The width also increases due to a large slide-out!  I wasn&amp;rsquo;t too sure about this one at first.  It seemed a bit large to haul with my mid-sized SUV.  But when I drove 20 miles on the Interstate from Camping World to the KOA Kampground I decided that it wasn&amp;rsquo;t so bad.  We need to do something to the awning to keep it from bouncing too high in crosswinds, and you can&amp;rsquo;t drive 70mph with this thing, but the Montero Sport didn&amp;rsquo;t seem to mind too badly.  It remains to be seen how it handles on steeper inclines, but it&amp;rsquo;s nice to be able to see over the top with the rear-view mirror!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dealer gave it new tires/wheels and helped fix a few minor issues, but as we&amp;rsquo;ve been using it we&amp;rsquo;ve discovered a few more.  Nothing major, just handy-man stuff.  The setup isn&amp;rsquo;t bad, and one of the locals thought for sure we were seasoned travelers!  We have a fresh water tank, water pump, connection for city water, a water heater, and a small gas furnace.  We also have a toilet/shower combo.  The sink drains directly to the outside, the shower water drains to a grey water tank.  But the one thing that sets this unit apart from most others is the toilet.  The black water doesn&amp;rsquo;t go into a tank and you can&amp;rsquo;t connect this to a sewer connection in a full hook-up site.  This unit is equipped with a cassette toilet.  It holds around 5 gallons of black water.  When it is full, you simply open the outside hatch, slide the unit out and walk it over to the dump station and empty it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which brings up one strange problem.  As great as this unit is, you can&amp;rsquo;t get to the toilet cartridge access door to empty the black water while you have the main screen door in place.  It seems as if it was designed assuming that you would never need to empty the black water until you were leaving the campground.  Only when the main door is removed can the small external half-door close, and only when that door closes can you get full access to the toilet cartridge.  Seems like the kind of thing they should use in camper design class under &amp;ldquo;things not to do.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After we picked it up from the dealer we drove it straight back to the KOA where we had been staying and drove into a nice pull-through site.  It was our 7th day in a row, so it was a free night!  We have spent the last two days reorganizing and rearranging and fixing and setting up and cleaning.  It is finally ready for travel, and we&amp;rsquo;ve got six months worth of travel left for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A long time ago, back when we were planning on five year&amp;rsquo;s worth of RV travel, we had settled on a nickname for our trailer.  And even though we ended up with a popup, I think the nickname still fits.  See &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.www.vagabondians.dev/tiki-barv-reality&#34; title=&#34;Tiki BaRV Reality&#34;&gt;Dixie&amp;rsquo;s latest dispatch&lt;/a&gt; for more information on the TikiBaRV.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Tiki BaRV -- a Reality!</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/tiki-barv-reality/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/tiki-barv-reality/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Tiki BarV is open!  Roxi is an excellent little proprietress serving up her special concoctions and showing off Speedy the snake to unsuspecting patrons.  She loves the traveling life and adventure.  Come see us if we come near your neck of the woods!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tent-sweet-tent lost its appeal fairly quickly.  It wasn&amp;rsquo;t bad, but all our stuff was jumbled in the back of the Montero, and I could never find what I needed without digging and many expletives.  For me, expletives mean I&amp;rsquo;m stressed, and that&amp;rsquo;s what we&amp;rsquo;re out here to get away from, right?  So we looked around and found this HUGE popup palace, and finally got it pretty well organized.   &amp;#8212; Ahhhh!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, how do we get rid of all that nice camping gear so we have room in the Montero and don&amp;rsquo;t have to lug an extra 200 pounds or so around the country?  We&amp;rsquo;re open to ideas, so please comment!  We have the tent and a ground tarp, suitcase kitchen, Coleman 2-burner gas stove , two double-height twin air beds, and an instant-up screen shelter.  I put up a CraigsList ad and will pull it if it doesn&amp;rsquo;t sell and run it at the next place.  Maybe a flea market, set it all up and hope it sells without wasting all day there.  Thoughts?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s kind of nice to have a &amp;ldquo;home&amp;rdquo; again.  The weather doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter quite so much, so we should be able to avoid the motels that we&amp;rsquo;ve been relying on too heavily so far, although if you come out to Abq, the Sandia Peak Inn is a great little budget motel with a wonderful owner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re both ready to leave Abq and start on this big adventure of ours.  Finally!  We&amp;rsquo;ve been trapped here by my surgery and getting the camper organized.  We&amp;rsquo;ve done a few cool local things, Sandia Peak drive and Bosque del Apache, but sitting here in the KOA isn&amp;rsquo;t our dream life.  We&amp;rsquo;re off tomorrow to head for Grants, NM, where we will see some very interesting things.  Stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tonight is celebration night, clam chowder, salmon patties, wine and cheese and crackers, with music from the computer!  Whoopeeeee!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://50.22.11.21/~dixonbui/vagabondians.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/meal.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone size-full wp-image-2962&#34; src=&#34;http://50.22.11.21/~dixonbui/vagabondians.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/meal.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;meal&#34; width=&#34;535&#34; height=&#34;258&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers, everybody!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Communications on the Road:  Update</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/communications-road-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/communications-road-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since my last post on communicating on the road, we have had a major change in plans.  Yeah, stop me if you&amp;rsquo;ve heard this one before. LOL  A car (or now, our SUV) won&amp;rsquo;t carry a satellite dish very well (especially since it will be packed to the roof with camping gear) so we are being forced to change our plans for internet on the road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the resources we utilized when researching this issue are the many full-time RV travelers out there.  And somewhere along the way we decided to go with Millenicom.  Basically we are now using the Millenicom plan which comes with a free USB cell data stick and 20GB per month of data.  Eventually we will probably pick up some type of wifi hotspot (like the Cradlepoint CTR350 router) so that our iPhones/iPads/MacBook Airs, etc. can all get online even when we are driving down the road.  This would be especially handy when we are in an area where AT&amp;amp;T is roaming.  Sure, you can still make a voice call (who does that any more?) but if your Words With Friends app tries to connect to the network you start running into an interesting little-known data cap.  AT&amp;amp;T has roaming agreements for voice that is so cheap that they don&amp;rsquo;t pass the costs along to you.  Not so for data!  According to AT&amp;amp;T we can use no more than 24MB of data when we are roaming.  That is like 8 songs on Pandora&amp;rsquo;s streaming radio, or 20 photos on Facebook.  If you go over, they might just simply shut your data plan off!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, even though Millenicom uses a Verizon data plan with no such roaming limits for data, that doesn&amp;rsquo;t help if you can&amp;rsquo;t get a signal.  We already hit a long stretch of I-40 from Amarillo to Albuquerque where we couldn&amp;rsquo;t get connected at all.  Our friend Steve Miller showed us his amp recently and how it worked during storm chasing, so we will probably be adding a cell signal repeater/amplifier to our gear arsenal in the near future.  FYI, I&amp;rsquo;m writing this article using my laptop and the Millenicom data stick from the KOA on the north side of Albuquerque, New Mexico.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to New Mexico (again)</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/mexico-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/mexico-again/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As we planned our trip out and selected places to stop and visit, New Mexico received several pins on the map.  Most were in the southern or western parts of the state, but I think both of us regarded New Mexico as the true start of our trip, new territory to be explored.  And then we began talking about places we had been before, and as it turns out we&amp;rsquo;re not exactly strangers to the land of enchantment!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure that I was here first.  When I was two or three my parents let me come along to some church meetings at Glorieta.  Just a year or two later, Dixie accompanied her mom to New Mexico.  She remembers meeting Chief Sunny Skies.  (I thought this sounded like someone playing a good joke on the tourists, but evidently there was such a person!)  In 1970 Dixie and her dad camped out at Alamogordo Reservoir (now known as Sumner Lake State Park).  Why someone from Dallas would pick that spot for a vacation is beyond me though&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the late 1970&amp;rsquo;s I traveled to Carlsbad for a band competition and saw several classmates from my elementary and Junior High days in west Texas.  And at least once at a time which I can not recall I visited the caverns there.  Finally, in 1980 I spent the summer in Glorieta.  And that is the story of our prior history with New Mexico before Dixie and I met in 1989.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since then we&amp;rsquo;ve only been here twice.  Once, in 1992 or so we visited Carlsbad Caverns and Guadalupe Peak.  And in the mid-90&amp;rsquo;s somewhere in there we went skiing at Angel Fire.  We flew in on Southwest Airlines to Albuquerque and then rented a car and drove to the ski area.  We came up that same roadway today, I-25.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So &amp;#8212; while New Mexico still feels new and unexplored, we have been here before.  Maybe we&amp;rsquo;re just seeing it with new eyes?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>