<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Napa Valley on Vagabondians</title>
    <link>http://vagabondians.com/tags/napa-valley/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Napa Valley on Vagabondians</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright &amp;#169; by Glenn and Dixie Dixon</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vagabondians.com/tags/napa-valley/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Napa Valley</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/napa-valley/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/napa-valley/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our trip to Napa Valley didn&amp;rsquo;t start as we had planned. After leaving the wonderful &lt;a title=&#34;Park Sierra&#34; href=&#34;http://www.parksierra.net/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Escapee&amp;rsquo;s SKP Park Sierra&lt;/a&gt; north of Fresno we made the long haul drive out of the San Joaquin valley and then north on I-5. We made the usual pit stops for gas and snacks and bathroom visits, and we made decent time. We were slowing down to make the last turn from Hwy 12 to Hwy 29 when the trailer brakes clamped down and caused the tires to screech. WTF? We took it easy until we found a place to pull over and I got out to inspect things. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t pretty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Evidently one of the wheels on the left side had overheated and the grease was oozing out and slinging everywhere. We had some choices to make. After some discussion and some online searching we decided to backtrack a bit and drive the trailer over to the Camping World in Vacaville and park it. After we did that, we holed up in a nearby Motel 6 for the night. The next morning we were at the front doors when Camping World opened for business and talked to the service department. They were very busy and would take awhile to get to it so we went back to the motel and packed and checked out. Regardless the outcome on the trailer, this particular Motel 6 wasn&amp;rsquo;t worth extra nights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually we talked to a service rep and got the bad news. Evidently the bearings weren&amp;rsquo;t quite done correctly at the previous Camping World and when they overheated they took out the brake system with them. Two of the brake pads were cracked in half. All of them had excess grease in the drum. We finally opted to replace the entire brake system, just to be sure. Unfortunately the parts would not be in until Wednesday, so we found a half-way decent hotel and booked five days. I guess there are worse places to break down than Napa Valley, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next morning we drove north through the valley up to Calistoga and then began working our way back south, one winery at a time. We shared tastings in order to pace ourselves, and it helped to save money too as most of the wineries along the main road charge anywhere from $7 to $25 just to sip a little.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262588787091282&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262588787091282&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Calistoga was having a farmer&amp;rsquo;s market so we checked it out for a few minutes. An all-female group (&lt;a title=&#34;Sweet Burgundy&#34; href=&#34;http://www.myspace.com/sweetburgundy&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Sweet Burgundy&lt;/a&gt;) was playing acoustic tunes &amp;ndash; bass, rhythm and lead guitars. The town itself was just totally cute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262588997091261&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262588997091261&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our first winery was &lt;a title=&#34;Chateau Montelena&#34; href=&#34;http://montelena.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Chateau Montelena&lt;/a&gt;. It is the quintessential winery, with a main building looking much like its European predecessors. Their claim to fame is their 1973 Chardonnay which beat the French wines at an infamous blind tasting in Paris in 1976. You can get the basics and a lot of good entertainment from the movie version of events:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can get the full story in the book:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Montelena also has beautiful grounds, with a small lake and gazebos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262590947091066&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262590947091066&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262591977090963&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262591977090963&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sheer amount of acreage in this part of the state planted as vineyards is staggering. All of the valley floor and half the hillsides were completely covered, edge to edge with grapevines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262594457090715&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262594457090715&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next stop was the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.freemarkabbey.com//index.cfm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Freemark Abbey&lt;/a&gt; winery.  It was one of the wineries which had participated in the Judgment of Paris, and the only winery entered in both white and red wine categories.  It didn&amp;rsquo;t really fare that well, but we actually enjoyed some of their current selection!  We also met a couple who were having their first-ever wine tasting!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262592993757528&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262592993757528&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we left, we decided to try the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.adozenvintners.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;tasting room next door&lt;/a&gt;.  Nothing fancy here, no paths lined with stone walls, no chateau, just a plain little commercial building.  But they represented a dozen local smaller wineries.  The tasting was cheap, and since we did indeed buy some of their wine it was free!  The gentleman doing the pouring was Tim and he was a partner in one of the wines we tasted.  It was very nice, but out of our budget range.  What &lt;em&gt;was&lt;/em&gt; in our budget was an entire case of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eagleandrose.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Eagle and Rose&lt;/a&gt; Sangiovese on sale for $50!  Score!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262593480424146&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262593480424146&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next stop was &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.grgich.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Grgich Hills Estate&lt;/a&gt;.  Mike Grgich was the guy who actually did most of the work on the Chateau Montelena Chardonnay that won all the awards back in 1976, or at least that is the story.  I&amp;rsquo;m sure the high-dollar Chardonnay he still makes is good, but we weren&amp;rsquo;t wowed.  Very nice facility and staff though!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262593703757457&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262593703757457&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last stop of the day was at &lt;a href=&#34;http://folieadeux.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Folie a Deux&lt;/a&gt;, makers of one of our favorites &amp;ndash; Menage a Trois.  Very interesting building, wonderful grounds, knowledgeable staff and good wines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262596000423894&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262596000423894&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a few days of sightseeing in San Francisco we returned to the valley again, but I&amp;rsquo;ll save that for another post!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/media/set/?set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/media/set/?set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tales from the Tiki Bar:  Napa Valley, baby!</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/tales-tiki-bar-napa-baby/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/tales-tiki-bar-napa-baby/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Highway 29 from Napa to Calistoga will take you through a river of wine.  If each winery is a boulder, it&amp;rsquo;s a rapid run of gargantuan proportions. The term &amp;ldquo;highway&amp;rdquo; is kind of a misnomer too.  It&amp;rsquo;s a two-lane road winding through gorgeous wineries at about 35 mph. Sometimes it&amp;rsquo;s just a long line of cars, but mostly it kept moving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262594200424074&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262594200424074&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We decided to run the road to the far end and start from there.  As we drove we made a list of places we might want to stop and taste.  There&amp;rsquo;s even Old Faithful Geyser of California on the edge of Calistoga.  We decided to pass that one up in anticipation of the granddaddy of old faithful geysers at Yellowstone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We began the serious part of the jaunt at Calistoga, which is a cute town in its own right, full of shops and tasting rooms and a foodie&amp;rsquo;s delight.  The public market/farmers market was in full swing.  Not large, but colorful, and everything from fresh turnips and flowers to arts and crafts and African woven baskets and fans to gourmet treats and even a pretty good trio of ladies singing and playing instruments.  Just behind them, a nice creek with a bridge and a local chocolate lab taking a nice swim to cool off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262589513757876&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262589513757876&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262589730424521&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262589730424521&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First stop was Chateau Montelena of &lt;em&gt;Bottle Shock&lt;/em&gt; fame.  It was a great movie with lots of &amp;ldquo;poetic license&amp;rdquo; involved.   We were told the book has the real story, so now I must read.  We shared a tasting of 5 superb wines for $20 there and ended up buying a bottle of red zinfandel to save for our 21st anniversary in September.  A tasting there includes your own private pour person instead of one person covering 10-15 people, and she was fun and knowledgeable. The grounds were beautiful, including a lake with a path to two gazebo islands with beautifully set tables to rent for occasions.  They had a large Coastal Redwood they planted in 1990 that was now about 150 ft. high, I think.  In about 500-1000 years it will be among the giants, if conditions are right there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262592250424269&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262592250424269&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262590947091066&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262590947091066&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lunch was next on the list, tasty burgers and fries at a quaint little place there in Calistoga.  Next!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Freemark Abbey winery.  We met a nice young couple tasting next to us who were fairly new to wine and this was their first winery.  The wines and conversation were lively between us and our pour person. (I just like that title I made up.  What are they really called?)  The best was a bonus taste of their dessert white wine.  A little taste of heaven trickling down your throat!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262592993757528&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262592993757528&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hm, what&amp;rsquo;s this, A Dozen Vintners next door?  We can get an overview of several boutique wineries in one place.  We&amp;rsquo;re the only ones there and our host, Tim Mertz, was perfectly awesome!  The shared tasting was, I think, $10, waived if you purchase something, and off we went.  I don&amp;rsquo;t remember how many wines, maybe eight &amp;ndash; or fifteen?  Who knows!  It was a delightful afternoon of wine and conversation.  We stayed there quite some time and left with a case -yes, case! &amp;ndash; of a nice sangiovese for 50 bucks (!) that was one of the last on sale.  Tasted it at the end so we know it was pretty good.  I hope.  Nexsht!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262593480424146&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262593480424146&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe we ought to walk around a bit before going into the next winery?  The slow drive brought us to Grgich Hills Estate (not a drunken typo). The vintner was also involved in the &lt;em&gt;Bottle Shock&lt;/em&gt; saga.  It was very pretty and they had some nicely priced gift boxes and souvenirs and an exhibit about their famous wine.  We weren&amp;rsquo;t overly impressed with the actual wines, good, not excellent.  Back out into the perfect summer day.  Are we done yet?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262593833757444&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262593833757444&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nope.  Just *had* to stop in at Folie a Deux/Napa Cellars where they make one of our favorites, *Menage a Trois.  *The shared tasting there was only $7, and they had samples of some really brilliant dipping sauces.  Yum!  Our pour guy there was fun too.  And we got double tastes of two wines, before-and-after glasses, one out of the newly opened bottle and one run through the Vinturi Red Wine Aerator.  We thought we could actually taste a slight difference &amp;ndash; but by that time, who really knows!  We spent some time on the parklike grounds among the grapevines with actual fruit hanging before taking off for home.  It was sunny, about 75 degrees, slight cool breeze, bright green grass, grapevines, blooming flowers and lavender&amp;hellip;..aaaaaah, perfection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262595023757325&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262595023757325&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A VOTRE SANTE&lt;/em&gt;!  CHEERS!  SALUTE!  &lt;em&gt;clink&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_0:6d6904fc67a34897a8c2b08f006285ca&#34;&gt;**&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;** {#product-name}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262596513757176&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=262596513757176&amp;amp;#038;set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/media/set/?set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;notif_t=like&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/media/set/?set=a.262588720424622.87451.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;notif_t=like&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>