<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mexico on Vagabondians</title>
    <link>http://vagabondians.com/tags/mexico/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mexico on Vagabondians</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright &amp;#169; by Glenn and Dixie Dixon</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vagabondians.com/tags/mexico/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>2013 -- A Brief Summary</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/2013-a-brief-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/2013-a-brief-summary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So 2013 was a pretty interesting year. We started in Mexico, visited Belize, spent five months back in Texas, visited Nicaragua, visited Costa Rica, then ended up right back in Mexico! We&amp;rsquo;ve spent the last few weeks in sunny Merida. So far, that&amp;rsquo;s the most countries we&amp;rsquo;ve ever visited in one year. In 2014 we&amp;rsquo;ll visit at least Mexico and Guatemala, not sure beyond that. So &amp;ndash; let&amp;rsquo;s do this!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Halloween Parade in San Cristobal de las Casas, Mexico</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/halloween-parade-in-san-cristobal-de-las-casas-mexico/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/halloween-parade-in-san-cristobal-de-las-casas-mexico/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div id=&#34;fb-root&#34;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;fb-post&#34; data-href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/photo.php?v=10153445211535437&#34; data-width=&#34;466&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;fb-xfbml-parse-ignore&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/photo.php?v=10153445211535437&#34;&gt;Post&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/dixonge&#34;&gt;Glenn Dixon&lt;/a&gt;.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Burn Rate</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/burn-rate/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/burn-rate/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Planning and goal-setting have never been our strong suits. The fact that we were able to get out of debt, sell all our stuff, get out of our house and save up a lot of money is almost miraculous given our track record. So I&amp;rsquo;m going to cut myself some slack when it comes to timing. The fact is that when we quit our jobs we didn&amp;rsquo;t have an income in place to pay for our travels. Up until very recently approximately 99% of our travel expenses have come out of our savings. It was a plan, but perhaps not the best plan. If we were a start-up business, or a rocket, you would say that our burn rate was unsustainable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The alternative would have been to wait until either our savings were greater, or an income was in fact in place. But we had inertia, and bravado, and our jobs began to absolutely drive us crazy! So our &amp;lsquo;Plan B&amp;rsquo; was never firm, but it was enough for us. We always knew that if our passive/freelance income ideas never materialized we could do something a little more traditional. Teaching English, managing a guesthouse, working on a cruise ship &amp;#8212; all these ideas were in the back of our minds as options, and all of them would be better than going back to the States and getting a &amp;lsquo;real&amp;rsquo; J-O-B. We also knew that at some point we might become uncomfortable with how low our savings balance became. Did we really want to slide into our pension years with $0.00 left in the bank? Doubtful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vagabondians.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/08/burn-rate.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-medium wp-image-3410&#34; src=&#34;http://vagabondians.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/08/burn-rate-300x134.png&#34; alt=&#34;burn rate&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;134&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, that day of discomfort has come. We have officially become uneasy about our bank account balance.  The chart above is from a spreadsheet we update to keep track of where we are. The red line is a worst-case scenario. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t go to zero, but it is tracking our cash plus some other non-liquid assets. If we stay on that path, we&amp;rsquo;d actually get to our official &amp;lsquo;retirement&amp;rsquo; date with almost nothing left. And as you can see by the green line, we&amp;rsquo;re not on target. At this point our projection would be to crash and burn well before our target date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is good news and bad news to go along with this. The good news is that Glenn has finally discovered that people will actually pay decent money to get help with their web sites. In just the last few months we&amp;rsquo;ve made more from that one source than all of our &amp;lsquo;internet marketing&amp;rsquo; attempts to date. The bad news is that we feel like we need to &amp;lsquo;settle down&amp;rsquo; somewhere for more than just a couple of months so that we can work on the business end of things, marketing stuff. Word of mouth is great, but we need to gain some consistency before we can continue with our plans of traveling through South America. Mexico spoiled us with their six-month easily renewable visas and low cost of living. Central America has, so far, proven to be quite expensive, especially Costa Rica! The other day we spent $16 on a medium-sized pizza with possibly the thinnest crust I&amp;rsquo;ve ever seen. And as we move south the visas are all 90 days with unlikely renewals and increasing fees. So we have decided to back up a step or two. Specifically, we&amp;rsquo;re going back to Mexico!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More specifically, we&amp;rsquo;re going back to San Cristobal de las Casas. No other city has welcomed us like it did. We have friends and hangouts there, and the cost of living is so cheap! We plan on staying a minimum of six months, and quite possibly an entire year. While we are there we&amp;rsquo;ll work on the business sites and marketing, and Dixie will probably start teaching English and putting her TEFL certificate to use. Glenn will also get down to work on the ebook projects. It&amp;rsquo;s not a complete change of plans, more like a pit stop. Eventually we&amp;rsquo;ll get back out on the road and hopefully we&amp;rsquo;ll be able to travel in a more comfortable, sustainable style.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, we&amp;rsquo;ll still be enjoying the wonderful culture of the state of Chiapas and traveling into the surrounding area. Chamula, Canyon de Sumidero, Arcotete, Tonina and Palenque will be visited. And when we need to reset our visa, we&amp;rsquo;ll visit Lake Atitlan again and Antigua in nearby Guatemala. So now you know where to find us for the next year, and we&amp;rsquo;ll be renting something with a guest room so you need to start planning your Mexican vacation now! It&amp;rsquo;s cheap and it comes with a free tour guide.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>San Cristobal, Guatemala and … China?</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/san-cristobal-guatemala-and-china/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/san-cristobal-guatemala-and-china/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignleft&#34; style=&#34;border: 0px;&#34; title=&#34;SanCris-Guat.jpg&#34; src=&#34;http://vagabondians.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/SanCris-Guat.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;SanCris Guat&#34; width=&#34;210&#34; height=&#34;280&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple of weeks ago we reached a milestone, the end of our first six months in Mexico. We can&amp;rsquo;t believe it has been that long already! Six months is also the standard time limit for a tourist visa. In order to extend your stay, you have to spend at least seventy-two hours outside the country before re-entry, at which time you can renew your visa for another six months. So that is what we did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright&#34; style=&#34;border: 0px;&#34; title=&#34;SanCris-Guat (1).jpg&#34; src=&#34;http://vagabondians.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/SanCris-Guat-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;SanCris Guat  1&#34; width=&#34;210&#34; height=&#34;280&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We took an all-day shuttle which dropped us off at the border after making sure all of our passports and visas were stamped out. Then we simply walked down the street to the Guatemalan side of town and had them stamp us all in. After that, we got into a different shuttle and finished the trip to Panajachel. We stayed in Pana for three nights and visited a couple of the other towns on Lake Atitlan while we were there. Dixie will post a full trip report with lots of pictures real soon!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we left we had a few decisions to make. Initially we had planned to just move to Guatemala and stay about 90 days before moving on south, but a few things came up that caused us to hesitate. One brief possibility was a seven month housesitting opportunity in southern France, in the Provence region. Not only is this a part of France we have long wanted to visit, but it is only a couple of hours south of where one of Dixie&amp;rsquo;s cousins lives, in Lyon. We considered shifting our travel plans and flying to Europe, but there were some obstacles. First, most of Europe is in what is called the Schengen Zone. Your typical tourist visa is for ninety days, and that is for the entire Schengen Zone! If you move around enough and occasionally visit the U.K. you can stretch that out, but it&amp;rsquo;s tricky. In the end they selected someone else, but we also looked at several other opportunities in southern Spain. We already know basic Spanish, enough to live here for six months, so that is also appealing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One reason we thought of changing our plans is that there simply aren&amp;rsquo;t that many housesitting opportunities south of here. A couple in Costa Rica, maybe one in Nicaragua, one in Panama, and… that&amp;rsquo;s about it! Every housesitting site that we use shows a global map. North America and Europe are just &lt;em&gt;full&lt;/em&gt; of pins, and quite a few pins are scattered around SouthEast Asia, but South America and Africa are just empty. So if we do continue going south from here we will compensate by living 2-3 months at a time in each place and finding cheap rent. In the meantime we are staying put in San Cristobal. It&amp;rsquo;s just so nice here, and we have some expat friends, and we&amp;rsquo;ll be paying about $212 in rent for a studio apartment with a beautiful courtyard, wifi and hot water. The previous tenant is now living here and will leave some furniture for us. We&amp;rsquo;ll have a small kitchen and fridge and a bathroom all &lt;em&gt;inside&lt;/em&gt; the apartment, which ought to be a nice change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignleft&#34; style=&#34;border: 0px;&#34; title=&#34;shenzhen-night.jpg&#34; src=&#34;http://vagabondians.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/shenzhen-night1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Shenzhen night&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;201&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But tomorrow I will be taking a phone call from China. An interesting opportunity came up recently and I applied for it. A couple of expats run a business in Shenzhen, just north of Hong Kong. They make all kinds of apparel products and they are going to hire an intern for 90 days. In exchange for 4-5 hours a day, five days a week I would get a free apartment w/ wifi and a stipend, free laundry and lunches most days and possibly a cook! I would be running their website and working with their staff to do some creative stuff with photography and video, plus marketing in general. Tomorrow is a screening call, and I have no idea how many other candidates they are looking at, but hopefully we&amp;rsquo;ll know by tomorrow night what the possibilities are. Sure, it&amp;rsquo;s a job, and it is nice to not have to work, but flying to that part of the world is expensive and having a group of people on hand to help you get settled would be a big bonus. And who knows, maybe it turns into something I really love doing and becomes a full-time job? I&amp;rsquo;m still in China, learning Cantonese! Seems like an adventure to us.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scooter Ride to Las Grutas</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/scooter-ride-to-las-grutas/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/scooter-ride-to-las-grutas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; style=&#34;border: 0px;&#34; title=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7112/7777222084_6cbd5f94be_n.jpg&#34; src=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7112/7777222084_6cbd5f94be_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7112/7777222084_6cbd5f94be_n.jpg&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hey!  Let&amp;rsquo;s take the scooters out and see the caves, Las Grutas!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So Shelley, the owner of &lt;a title=&#34;Croozy Scooters&#34; href=&#34;http://croozyscooters.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Croozy Scooters&lt;/a&gt;, got us &amp;ndash; consisting of Dixie, Mandy, Shelley&amp;rsquo;s son Justin, his sweetie Sam, and Shelley &amp;ndash; all fitted out with scooters and helmets, and away we went through the streets of San Cristobal and out to the highway out of town.  Beautiful ride, once we left the city traffic, and we cruised on down the road, with Mandy in the lead since she knew where we were going.  At one point Mandy and Dixie looked back and decided to pull over and wait to see if the rest would catch up from whatever delayed them.  Soon, here they came.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/48315294@N00/7777113978&#34; title=&#34;View &#39;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8439/7777113978_c9d2e4d928_n.jpg&#39; on Flickr.com&#34;&gt; &lt;img style=&#34;float: left;&#34; title=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8439/7777113978_c9d2e4d928_n.jpg&#34; src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8439/7777113978_c9d2e4d928_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8439/7777113978_c9d2e4d928_n.jpg&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/48315294@N00/7777098698&#34; title=&#34;View &#39;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8443/7777098698_c18fd9349f_n.jpg&#39; on Flickr.com&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;float: left;&#34; title=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8443/7777098698_c18fd9349f_n.jpg&#34; src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8443/7777098698_c18fd9349f_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8443/7777098698_c18fd9349f_n.jpg&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shelley and Ozzie all snug like a hot dog! Shelley, Justin, and Sam catching up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We went quite some way out of town and took the exit for Las Grutas and paid our 5 pesos each to get into the park.  The ride through the woods on a gravel road, alone, was worth the trip.  We parked and locked up our bikes and explored the little park.  They have some tall slides made of concrete with lots of kids sliding down on little butt-sized pieces of cardboard and then running back up to the top.  Many people opt for a horseback ride into the wooded areas.  Very inexpensive here.  Others hike.  There are many taco shops, quesadilla shops, other food shops all in a row under the big shelter, so we had lunch after the cave walk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/48315294@N00/7777158796&#34; title=&#34;View &#39;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7125/7777158796_c95b773988_n.jpg&#39; on Flickr.com&#34;&gt;&lt;img title=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7125/7777158796_c95b773988_n.jpg&#34; src=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7125/7777158796_c95b773988_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7125/7777158796_c95b773988_n.jpg&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/48315294@N00/7777165174&#34; title=&#34;View &#39;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8285/7777165174_161f1ee624_n.jpg&#39; on Flickr.com&#34;&gt;&lt;img title=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8285/7777165174_161f1ee624_n.jpg&#34; src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8285/7777165174_161f1ee624_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8285/7777165174_161f1ee624_n.jpg&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/48315294@N00/7777168842&#34; title=&#34;View &#39;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7130/7777168842_89cf753855_n.jpg&#39; on Flickr.com&#34;&gt;&lt;img title=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7130/7777168842_89cf753855_n.jpg&#34; src=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7130/7777168842_89cf753855_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7130/7777168842_89cf753855_n.jpg&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We bought our tickets to see the cave for 10 pesos each (75 cents) and trooped inside.  I expected some cute little cave like a gang of Texas outlaws might hole up in, hiding from the sheriff.  This was actually a large cave with active water deposits being made and stalactites and stalagmites and pools, some lit up with electric lights.  It had a wide path with heavy bright railings.  Very nice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/48315294@N00/7777179866&#34; title=&#34;View &#39;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8288/7777179866_8e600db248_n.jpg&#39; on Flickr.com&#34;&gt;&lt;img title=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8288/7777179866_8e600db248_n.jpg&#34; src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8288/7777179866_8e600db248_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8288/7777179866_8e600db248_n.jpg&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/48315294@N00/7777184042&#34; title=&#34;View &#39;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8433/7777184042_7517ff647a_n.jpg&#39; on Flickr.com&#34;&gt;&lt;img title=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8433/7777184042_7517ff647a_n.jpg&#34; src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8433/7777184042_7517ff647a_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8433/7777184042_7517ff647a_n.jpg&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img title=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8425/7777195068_9e1da8a4e4_n.jpg&#34; src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8425/7777195068_9e1da8a4e4_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8425/7777195068_9e1da8a4e4_n.jpg&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; /&gt;&lt;img title=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8429/7777204926_7b711014ba_n.jpg&#34; src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8429/7777204926_7b711014ba_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8429/7777204926_7b711014ba_n.jpg&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/48315294@N00/7777198972&#34; title=&#34;View &#39;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7116/7777198972_3107d41f09_n.jpg&#39; on Flickr.com&#34;&gt;&lt;img title=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7116/7777198972_3107d41f09_n.jpg&#34; src=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7116/7777198972_3107d41f09_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7116/7777198972_3107d41f09_n.jpg&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/48315294@N00/7777225812&#34; title=&#34;View &#39;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7264/7777225812_b8ae7fbec2_n.jpg&#39; on Flickr.com&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7264/7777225812_b8ae7fbec2_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7264/7777225812_b8ae7fbec2_n.jpg&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The caves go quite a way further, but it goes beneath a military base, so there is a blockage.  Probably good since they also have artillery practice all the time, entertaining us with many explosions.  Mexicans sure do love their explosions (referring to all the heavy firework aerial bombs we&amp;rsquo;re entertained with nightly and in the mornings at 6:00 and all hours in between)!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We emerged from the caves and had a nice quesadilla lunch and we were on our way.  The trip back was going so well, and we had almost made it back to town when disaster hit.  Sam was third in line, I was behind her, and Shelley was bringing up the rear.  Sam got a little far off onto the shoulder and hit some deep gravel, going all out on the scooter downhill, probably 40-45 mph, she fishtailed, got &amp;ldquo;the wobble&amp;rdquo;, and flashed out toward the far oncoming lane, but she spun around and crashed in our lane.  Thankfully all the vehicles behind us had just passed us up so no squishing happened.  She lost a lot of skin on both palms and had some road rash on her forearm, side, and some on her leg and foot.  Shelley and I were almost panicking, and she was the one holding it together as she had me pour water on the palms to get the dirt off.  Then Shelley tore up a towel and wrapped her up.  About this time Mandy and Justin decided something was wrong and came back.  We managed to get Sam back into town and return to pick up her scooter.  She&amp;rsquo;s one tough chick!  And she stood up and survived the torture the doctor put her through at the hospital!  Can you say alcohol poured on raw live meat!?!   But all is well, and she&amp;rsquo;s nearly healed now, and she has a great story to tell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moral of the story:  Don&amp;rsquo;t get into gravel and wear helmet AND GLOVES when riding motorcycles, scooter, and bicycles!  If she&amp;rsquo;d had a jacket on, most of the road rash could also have been avoided.  But we all just opted on the helmets that day.  Dress for the wreck and then don&amp;rsquo;t have one!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All&amp;rsquo;s well that ends well!  Cheers!   She&amp;rsquo;s one tough chick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the whole set of photos:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[slickr-flickr tag=&amp;ldquo;grutas&amp;rdquo;]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On The Road Again</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/on-the-road-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/on-the-road-again/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; title=&#34;Bus Terminal&#34; src=&#34;https://fbcdn-sphotos-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash3/600165_10151896098365437_1236436281_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;550&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And now, at long last, the next phase of our journey begins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last few weeks have been busy. Our homeowner dropped in for a two-week stay and initiated a flurry of activity! We ran around getting automobile repair estimates and looking for replacement kitchen sinks and cleaning the house in preparation for the new property managers to take pictures. We also showed the home to a potential renter and took both dogs and both cats to the vet. In addition to that, we picked up some utensils and cookware and a portable electric stove top. We also got the house ready for the new housesitter and went over all of the details with her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whew!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://fbcdn-sphotos-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash4/376442_10151896099480437_403310213_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;540&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So Tuesday morning we had a driver pick us up and deliver us to the main bus station in eastern Guadalajara, near Tonala. We rode in amazing comfort on a Primera Plus coach and stopped only once. The whole trip lasted just over four hours. The seats lean back twice as far as on the standard economy fare airline seat, and they have footrests that fold down from the seat in front. Lights and air vents are overhead. Each seat has its own audio jack where you can listen to one of several stations or just pick up the audio from the on-board movie. I watched Transformers 2 in Spanish. Interesting. There are also men&amp;rsquo;s and women&amp;rsquo;s restrooms in the back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://fbcdn-sphotos-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash3/600382_10151896100380437_1848917125_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;540&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we stopped at Leon it began to rain, but by the time we were halfway to Guanajuato the skies had cleared. At one point our bus was selected (randomly?) for an inspection by some nice people from the Mexican army. The first one on board announced the inspection and seemed to generally calm everyone. He then walked through and inspected everyone&amp;rsquo;s bags and purses. I presume he was looking for weapons, drugs and/or explosives. And just in case you thought his calm demeanor was a sign of weakness, a second soldier stepped into the doorway and watched while resting his hand on the grip of his H&amp;amp;K G3 Battle Rifle. That&amp;rsquo;s a big gun!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://fbcdn-sphotos-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash4/306606_10151897024320437_59276117_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;540&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Very soon we were on our way again and we arrived in Guanajuato only slightly behind schedule. We took a taxi directly to our intended destination, the Hostel Alonso. We were so excited &amp;ndash; our very first night in a hostel! And so far it has not disappointed one bit. Our room is private and on the second floor. The shower is also the toilet. The toilets do not have seats. Supposedly this has something to do with scorpions, but I think I&amp;rsquo;d rather not know for sure&amp;hellip; The bed is just about as firm as it can get. We are, so far, sharing the facilities with two Japanese girls and two other couple from parts unknown. We are, also, unsurprisingly the oldest people in the building, by far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://fbcdn-sphotos-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash4/314072_10151896101395437_1880566886_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;540&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://fbcdn-sphotos-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash4/396623_10151896102090437_627351429_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;540&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://fbcdn-sphotos-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-snc7/376323_10151897024460437_1622543814_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We strolled the city a couple of times, mainly the area around the Jardin de la Union. We walked by Casa de Pita, the B&amp;amp;B we used on our first visit back in 2008. We bought a coca light and an agua at the nearby tienda just for old times sake. We had a decent dinner at a restaurant, a latte at a local coffee shop and picked up some drinks and snacks at an Oxxo convenience store. All set for the night!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://fbcdn-sphotos-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash3/530797_10151896104440437_57620121_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;540&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://fbcdn-sphotos-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-snc6/250820_10151896102585437_88422294_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;540&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is the rainy season in this part of Mexico. It starts in mid-June and ends later in the year. Normally they say that the rain arrives with San Antonio and departs with San Francisco. No, not the cities &amp;#8212; those are days honoring the saints. Dia de San Antonio is June 13, Dia de San Francisco is October 10. The rain started in Chapala right around June 11, and it hasn&amp;rsquo;t stopped since. Mostly it rains in the middle of the night, but here and there you get it during the day as well. It rained last night so hopefully we can walk around all day without worrying about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More pictures soon, and most will be added to Facebook. You can see the whole album here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&#34;Guanajuato&#34; href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/media/set/?set=a.10151896097500437.874894.648515436&amp;type=1&amp;l=8d63902558&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Guanajuato&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clothes Shopping in the Big City -- Guadalajara, Jalisco, MX</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/clothes-shopping-in-the-big-city-guadalajara/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/clothes-shopping-in-the-big-city-guadalajara/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://a1.sphotos.ak.fbcdn.net/hphotos-ak-snc6/s720x720/150736_10150977957908993_677503992_11925514_1748571729_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;100&#34; align=&#34;left&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today was a big treat &amp;ndash; my neighborhood friend Yolanda took me shopping all around the city center area near the big cathedral in downtown Guadalajara.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are so many stores for everything you can imagine.  There&amp;rsquo;s even a building the size of Sears or Penney&amp;rsquo;s, multiple floors, that is full, full, full of nothing but jewelry shops.  Lots of police all around that one &amp;ndash; with big dogs, beautiful Belgian Malinois.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://a2.sphotos.ak.fbcdn.net/hphotos-ak-snc6/166042_10150977898108993_677503992_11925393_513595731_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;75&#34; align=&#34;right&#34; /&gt;There are some expensive fru-fru stores, but we didn&amp;rsquo;t go to those.  I&amp;rsquo;m on a budget, and I need things for the heat and the beach.  My heavy dark pants and tops aren&amp;rsquo;t going to cut it anymore.  Usually I shop and shop and buy nothing, but today was a good day, starting with a nice little comfy artsy top for 130 pesos ($9.40).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://a7.sphotos.ak.fbcdn.net/hphotos-ak-snc7/577487_10150977899458993_677503992_11925396_2052232393_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;100&#34; align=&#34;left&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://a5.sphotos.ak.fbcdn.net/hphotos-ak-ash3/545641_10150977898958993_677503992_11925395_94931201_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;100&#34; align=&#34;left&#34; /&gt;Next we went to another store where I bought a fluffy dressy blouse for 180 pesos ($13.02) and an open-knit ziz-zag top for 130 pesos ($9.40).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://a2.sphotos.ak.fbcdn.net/hphotos-ak-prn1/525668_10150977900988993_677503992_11925401_559430124_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;100&#34; align=&#34;right&#34; /&gt;We went in three shoe shops before they had my choice of sandals for my big size 8 feet.  Those set me back 160 pesos ($11.57).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://a2.sphotos.ak.fbcdn.net/hphotos-ak-snc7/303448_10150977899833993_677503992_11925398_1629554372_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;75&#34; align=&#34;left&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://a8.sphotos.ak.fbcdn.net/hphotos-ak-snc7/74758_10150977900273993_677503992_11925399_248805157_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;75&#34; align=&#34;left&#34; /&gt;Got a nice jersey sundress for 120 pesos ($8.68) and some decorated jeans for 150 pesos ($10.85).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We wandered through the huge multi-story market with stalls and stalls of everything from cow feet and ankles to veggies to little birds to clothing and purses and toys and pink guitars in green cases to mariachi suits adult to baby size.  I really don&amp;rsquo;t know how &lt;img src=&#34;http://a8.sphotos.ak.fbcdn.net/hphotos-ak-ash3/560219_10150977897493993_677503992_11925392_494293446_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; align=&#34;right&#34; /&gt; you would cook a cow hoof with about 10 inches of leg, but apparently somebody does.  And I have a local friend who loves to eat chicken feet that are sold everywhere you buy chicken.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I bought a nice leather belt for Glenn for 180 pesos ($13.02) and Yo bought some little purses to give as gifts on her trip back to Canada in a couple of weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://a8.sphotos.ak.fbcdn.net/hphotos-ak-ash2/149730_10150977900583993_677503992_11925400_2141177313_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;75&#34; align=&#34;right&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also bought a cotton skirt that I didn&amp;rsquo;t really want that bad, but she kept coming down on the price.  It wasn&amp;rsquo;t the price I objected to but finally I felt I had to buy it.  It will be great in the beach heat though.  Not $250 pesos ($18.08) but 190 pesos ($13.74).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://a7.sphotos.ak.fbcdn.net/hphotos-ak-ash2/156498_10150977894693993_677503992_11925382_1860967956_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;100&#34; align=&#34;left&#34; /&gt;We went into the big cathedral and sat for a few minutes looking at the beautiful carving work on the arches and the stained glass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had lunch at Yo&amp;rsquo;s favorite restaurant downtown, El Mexicano, and arrachera that was really good, though not as good as the one we had in Tlaquepaque.  It&amp;rsquo;s thin flank steak, marinated and cooked to tender perfection.  So good!  We have it wherever we go and judge each restaurant on it.&lt;img src=&#34;http://a4.sphotos.ak.fbcdn.net/hphotos-ak-snc7/582389_10150977896943993_677503992_11925390_900779950_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;175&#34; align=&#34;right&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So amazingly I bought eight major clothing items and spent a whopping $89.69 US.  Do that in Dallas!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MY TIKI BAR KITCHEN -- 1</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/my-tiki-bar-kitchen-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/my-tiki-bar-kitchen-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I know, tiki is so South Pacific and we’re in Mexico &amp;ndash; but it’s also retro American kitsch that evokes silliness and warmth and friends having cocktails at sunset. So grab your tiki mug and just go with me!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_m5djr07vUY1qzu24w.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what could be so different about food prep in Mexico? What’s the big deal? Well, for me, it is quite different and a challenge. I can’t really put my finger on one thing or one area and explain it to anyone, so there will be several articles in this series about food purchase, preparation, and cooking &amp;ndash; and some authentic Mexican recipes that I find easy and tasty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Disclaimer: First off, I’m no cocinera! I can cook basic stuff fairly well at home in the US. But when I came to Mexico, I found so many differences in the food and how it cooks and what’s available, that I had to stop and regroup and ask for help from an expert &amp;ndash; our Mexican housekeeper. (She came with the house-sit job &amp;ndash; score!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re going to explore shopping and cooking here in the state of Jalisco, Mexico.  From what I hear, this vast country has many styles, and each state is different. Hang onto your hats &amp;ndash; it&amp;rsquo;s not Tex Mex!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;May the roof above us never fall in, and may the friends gathered below it never fall out.-Unknown&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ninety Days In Mexico -- Travelers or Livers?</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/ninety-days-in-mexico-travelers-or-livers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/ninety-days-in-mexico-travelers-or-livers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Random thought of the day:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not a traveler, I&amp;rsquo;m a liver!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_m42d0tPyZt1qzndqu.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;193&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No, not that kind of liver! I should probably explain&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most everyone doing what we are doing refers to it as travel. If we have a blog, we&amp;rsquo;re &amp;lsquo;travel bloggers.&amp;rsquo; If someone asks what we do, family and friends tell them we are traveling. But we&amp;rsquo;ve been taking care of this house here in Chapala, Mexico for three months now. That&amp;rsquo;s not traveling! We live here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_m42dqbkErx1qzndqu.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;219&#34; align=&#34;left&#34; /&gt;Sure, it&amp;rsquo;s only temporary. In July we are going to travel across half of Mexico and go visit some people that will be housesitting in Antigua, Guatemala. We&amp;rsquo;ll be taking the wonderful first-class buses they have here in Mexico. Tons of legroom, reclining seats, your very own video screen with tons of movie selection. We will stop in Guanajuato and San Miguel again, and we&amp;rsquo;ll probably check out a pyramid and maybe a volcano. After spending a few days in Guatemala we can renew our visas and return to Mexico.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then we will spend a month taking care of some pets at a yoga retreat near Puerto Escondido.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So sure, some travel is involved, but then we stop and move in to some home or building and stay for an extended period. Technically most people refer to this as slow travel. Maybe it could also be called fast living! No, wait &amp;ndash; that doesn&amp;rsquo;t sound right either&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But seriously &amp;ndash; by the time this is all over we will have spent seven or eight or more months in Mexico. That ain&amp;rsquo;t travelin&amp;rsquo;, that&amp;rsquo;s livin&amp;rsquo;!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day Trip!  Tlaquepaque/Guadalajara</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/day-trip-tlaquepaque-guadalajara/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/day-trip-tlaquepaque-guadalajara/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our friends in the neighborhood, Jean-Pierre and Yolanda Luisser, French-Canadians from Quebec, invited us to join them on a day trip to Guadalajara on Sunday, March 25. Oh, boy! A trip to the big city with someone who knows where to go and what to see &amp;ndash; and most importantly, how to drive in that crazy place! So we set out about 10 in the morning, first stop Tlaquepaque, a town on the outskirts that I first heard about on The Travel Channel long ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://fbcdn-sphotos-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-prn1/526280_10150842926778993_677503992_11703252_2078959908_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;548&#34; height=&#34;411&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We parked in a parking lot with a shade, a big plus, and walked in. There’s a main drag with lots of art work installed in addition to all the art and wares set up in doorways and down the sidewalks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://fbcdn-sphotos-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash3/545696_10150842929348993_677503992_11703272_817768460_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;546&#34; height=&#34;727&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://fbcdn-sphotos-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash3/562625_10150842930948993_677503992_11703285_598043878_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;551&#34; height=&#34;413&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We came to a little courtyard where some artists had their tables set up with all kinds of really interesting things. An artist carving little buildings and streets from wood to intricate jewelry made of paper to painted ostrich eggs and jewelry made of natural plant parts. Yo bought paper earrings to match her top, and I bought some big fun seed pod earrings, each original handmade purchase under $4.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://fbcdn-sphotos-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash3/526274_10150842927968993_677503992_11703262_2134521238_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;550&#34; height=&#34;412&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We oooh’d and aaaah’d over many different shops, but Jean-Pierre took us into the tequila shops for tastes of their wares. Wow! Some very interesting flavors. And we bought a tequila flavored with membrillo, a beautiful aperitif or dessert liquor. I almost got some chocolate liquor from the second shop that was out of this world but restrained myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next stop was lunch where they introduced us to a very fine arrachera, which is a marinated steak, thin like the Mexicans do it, but cooked to perfection and, oh, so gooooood, and the grilled marinated shrimp were scrumptious! Now, wherever we go we have to try the arrachera! Three places so far, but that was the best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://fbcdn-sphotos-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash3/523969_10150842932913993_677503992_11703313_1477186929_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;549&#34; height=&#34;411&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://fbcdn-sphotos-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-snc7/485655_10150842933258993_677503992_11703319_905966958_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;550&#34; height=&#34;412&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Onward to Guadalajara. Jean-Pierre has been down here a while and drives like a Mexican, which is to say he’s fearless! And they know where the interesting things are. Downtown is popular on the weekends and there is a huge market covering a couple of city blocks and three stories tall! Glenn forgot to wear his hat, so we went in search of un sombrero nuevo. I bought one for about $7.25, and we finally found one for Glenn at about $18, and fine hats they are! They guy selling the men’s hats had spent a bit of time in California, so Glenn got to use his cholo impersonation on him &amp;ndash; ha!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://fbcdn-sphotos-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-snc7/581238_10150842942193993_677503992_11703371_1155888420_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;557&#34; height=&#34;417&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://fbcdn-sphotos-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-prn1/560278_10150842942463993_677503992_11703376_420311012_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;550&#34; height=&#34;412&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we wandered around the big city, we saw some clowns entertaining a small crowd and wandered up.  Oops!  We&amp;rsquo;ve been spotted and dragged into the show!  But Yolanda and I each got a nice little balloon flower and gave multiple almost-kisses to the clown on the cheek and mugged for the crowd. Silly gringas!  And we saw a monk floating over his rug &amp;ndash; woo-woo &amp;ndash; and he had big Jerry Lewis teeth through which to give his sage advice to the onlookers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://fbcdn-sphotos-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-snc7/295243_10150842951663993_677503992_11703414_1117240413_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;550&#34; height=&#34;732&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://fbcdn-sphotos-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-prn1/535231_10150842943653993_677503992_11703383_1681778862_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;552&#34; height=&#34;414&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We finished up on the way back with a trip to Costco and then headed home. We took a back road to avoid some traffic and got to enjoy sunset in some small villages along the way. A great trip &amp;ndash; and a big thank you to our friends for a fine day!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can see all of the photos from the day &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/media/set/?set=a.10150842926278993.471576.677503992&amp;type=3&amp;l=6c76603fd0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;right here&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>