<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>San Cristobal De Las Casas on Vagabondians</title>
    <link>http://vagabondians.com/tags/san-cristobal-de-las-casas/</link>
    <description>Recent content in San Cristobal De Las Casas on Vagabondians</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright &amp;#169; by Glenn and Dixie Dixon</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vagabondians.com/tags/san-cristobal-de-las-casas/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Halloween Parade in San Cristobal de las Casas, Mexico</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/halloween-parade-in-san-cristobal-de-las-casas-mexico/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/halloween-parade-in-san-cristobal-de-las-casas-mexico/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div id=&#34;fb-root&#34;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;fb-post&#34; data-href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/photo.php?v=10153445211535437&#34; data-width=&#34;466&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;fb-xfbml-parse-ignore&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/photo.php?v=10153445211535437&#34;&gt;Post&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/dixonge&#34;&gt;Glenn Dixon&lt;/a&gt;.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Burn Rate</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/burn-rate/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/burn-rate/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Planning and goal-setting have never been our strong suits. The fact that we were able to get out of debt, sell all our stuff, get out of our house and save up a lot of money is almost miraculous given our track record. So I&amp;rsquo;m going to cut myself some slack when it comes to timing. The fact is that when we quit our jobs we didn&amp;rsquo;t have an income in place to pay for our travels. Up until very recently approximately 99% of our travel expenses have come out of our savings. It was a plan, but perhaps not the best plan. If we were a start-up business, or a rocket, you would say that our burn rate was unsustainable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The alternative would have been to wait until either our savings were greater, or an income was in fact in place. But we had inertia, and bravado, and our jobs began to absolutely drive us crazy! So our &amp;lsquo;Plan B&amp;rsquo; was never firm, but it was enough for us. We always knew that if our passive/freelance income ideas never materialized we could do something a little more traditional. Teaching English, managing a guesthouse, working on a cruise ship &amp;#8212; all these ideas were in the back of our minds as options, and all of them would be better than going back to the States and getting a &amp;lsquo;real&amp;rsquo; J-O-B. We also knew that at some point we might become uncomfortable with how low our savings balance became. Did we really want to slide into our pension years with $0.00 left in the bank? Doubtful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vagabondians.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/08/burn-rate.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-medium wp-image-3410&#34; src=&#34;http://vagabondians.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/08/burn-rate-300x134.png&#34; alt=&#34;burn rate&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;134&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, that day of discomfort has come. We have officially become uneasy about our bank account balance.  The chart above is from a spreadsheet we update to keep track of where we are. The red line is a worst-case scenario. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t go to zero, but it is tracking our cash plus some other non-liquid assets. If we stay on that path, we&amp;rsquo;d actually get to our official &amp;lsquo;retirement&amp;rsquo; date with almost nothing left. And as you can see by the green line, we&amp;rsquo;re not on target. At this point our projection would be to crash and burn well before our target date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is good news and bad news to go along with this. The good news is that Glenn has finally discovered that people will actually pay decent money to get help with their web sites. In just the last few months we&amp;rsquo;ve made more from that one source than all of our &amp;lsquo;internet marketing&amp;rsquo; attempts to date. The bad news is that we feel like we need to &amp;lsquo;settle down&amp;rsquo; somewhere for more than just a couple of months so that we can work on the business end of things, marketing stuff. Word of mouth is great, but we need to gain some consistency before we can continue with our plans of traveling through South America. Mexico spoiled us with their six-month easily renewable visas and low cost of living. Central America has, so far, proven to be quite expensive, especially Costa Rica! The other day we spent $16 on a medium-sized pizza with possibly the thinnest crust I&amp;rsquo;ve ever seen. And as we move south the visas are all 90 days with unlikely renewals and increasing fees. So we have decided to back up a step or two. Specifically, we&amp;rsquo;re going back to Mexico!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More specifically, we&amp;rsquo;re going back to San Cristobal de las Casas. No other city has welcomed us like it did. We have friends and hangouts there, and the cost of living is so cheap! We plan on staying a minimum of six months, and quite possibly an entire year. While we are there we&amp;rsquo;ll work on the business sites and marketing, and Dixie will probably start teaching English and putting her TEFL certificate to use. Glenn will also get down to work on the ebook projects. It&amp;rsquo;s not a complete change of plans, more like a pit stop. Eventually we&amp;rsquo;ll get back out on the road and hopefully we&amp;rsquo;ll be able to travel in a more comfortable, sustainable style.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, we&amp;rsquo;ll still be enjoying the wonderful culture of the state of Chiapas and traveling into the surrounding area. Chamula, Canyon de Sumidero, Arcotete, Tonina and Palenque will be visited. And when we need to reset our visa, we&amp;rsquo;ll visit Lake Atitlan again and Antigua in nearby Guatemala. So now you know where to find us for the next year, and we&amp;rsquo;ll be renting something with a guest room so you need to start planning your Mexican vacation now! It&amp;rsquo;s cheap and it comes with a free tour guide.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>San Cristobal, Guatemala and … China?</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/san-cristobal-guatemala-and-china/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/san-cristobal-guatemala-and-china/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignleft&#34; style=&#34;border: 0px;&#34; title=&#34;SanCris-Guat.jpg&#34; src=&#34;http://vagabondians.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/SanCris-Guat.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;SanCris Guat&#34; width=&#34;210&#34; height=&#34;280&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple of weeks ago we reached a milestone, the end of our first six months in Mexico. We can&amp;rsquo;t believe it has been that long already! Six months is also the standard time limit for a tourist visa. In order to extend your stay, you have to spend at least seventy-two hours outside the country before re-entry, at which time you can renew your visa for another six months. So that is what we did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright&#34; style=&#34;border: 0px;&#34; title=&#34;SanCris-Guat (1).jpg&#34; src=&#34;http://vagabondians.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/SanCris-Guat-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;SanCris Guat  1&#34; width=&#34;210&#34; height=&#34;280&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We took an all-day shuttle which dropped us off at the border after making sure all of our passports and visas were stamped out. Then we simply walked down the street to the Guatemalan side of town and had them stamp us all in. After that, we got into a different shuttle and finished the trip to Panajachel. We stayed in Pana for three nights and visited a couple of the other towns on Lake Atitlan while we were there. Dixie will post a full trip report with lots of pictures real soon!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we left we had a few decisions to make. Initially we had planned to just move to Guatemala and stay about 90 days before moving on south, but a few things came up that caused us to hesitate. One brief possibility was a seven month housesitting opportunity in southern France, in the Provence region. Not only is this a part of France we have long wanted to visit, but it is only a couple of hours south of where one of Dixie&amp;rsquo;s cousins lives, in Lyon. We considered shifting our travel plans and flying to Europe, but there were some obstacles. First, most of Europe is in what is called the Schengen Zone. Your typical tourist visa is for ninety days, and that is for the entire Schengen Zone! If you move around enough and occasionally visit the U.K. you can stretch that out, but it&amp;rsquo;s tricky. In the end they selected someone else, but we also looked at several other opportunities in southern Spain. We already know basic Spanish, enough to live here for six months, so that is also appealing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One reason we thought of changing our plans is that there simply aren&amp;rsquo;t that many housesitting opportunities south of here. A couple in Costa Rica, maybe one in Nicaragua, one in Panama, and… that&amp;rsquo;s about it! Every housesitting site that we use shows a global map. North America and Europe are just &lt;em&gt;full&lt;/em&gt; of pins, and quite a few pins are scattered around SouthEast Asia, but South America and Africa are just empty. So if we do continue going south from here we will compensate by living 2-3 months at a time in each place and finding cheap rent. In the meantime we are staying put in San Cristobal. It&amp;rsquo;s just so nice here, and we have some expat friends, and we&amp;rsquo;ll be paying about $212 in rent for a studio apartment with a beautiful courtyard, wifi and hot water. The previous tenant is now living here and will leave some furniture for us. We&amp;rsquo;ll have a small kitchen and fridge and a bathroom all &lt;em&gt;inside&lt;/em&gt; the apartment, which ought to be a nice change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignleft&#34; style=&#34;border: 0px;&#34; title=&#34;shenzhen-night.jpg&#34; src=&#34;http://vagabondians.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/shenzhen-night1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Shenzhen night&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;201&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But tomorrow I will be taking a phone call from China. An interesting opportunity came up recently and I applied for it. A couple of expats run a business in Shenzhen, just north of Hong Kong. They make all kinds of apparel products and they are going to hire an intern for 90 days. In exchange for 4-5 hours a day, five days a week I would get a free apartment w/ wifi and a stipend, free laundry and lunches most days and possibly a cook! I would be running their website and working with their staff to do some creative stuff with photography and video, plus marketing in general. Tomorrow is a screening call, and I have no idea how many other candidates they are looking at, but hopefully we&amp;rsquo;ll know by tomorrow night what the possibilities are. Sure, it&amp;rsquo;s a job, and it is nice to not have to work, but flying to that part of the world is expensive and having a group of people on hand to help you get settled would be a big bonus. And who knows, maybe it turns into something I really love doing and becomes a full-time job? I&amp;rsquo;m still in China, learning Cantonese! Seems like an adventure to us.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scooter Ride to Las Grutas</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/scooter-ride-to-las-grutas/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/scooter-ride-to-las-grutas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; style=&#34;border: 0px;&#34; title=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7112/7777222084_6cbd5f94be_n.jpg&#34; src=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7112/7777222084_6cbd5f94be_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7112/7777222084_6cbd5f94be_n.jpg&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hey!  Let&amp;rsquo;s take the scooters out and see the caves, Las Grutas!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So Shelley, the owner of &lt;a title=&#34;Croozy Scooters&#34; href=&#34;http://croozyscooters.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Croozy Scooters&lt;/a&gt;, got us &amp;ndash; consisting of Dixie, Mandy, Shelley&amp;rsquo;s son Justin, his sweetie Sam, and Shelley &amp;ndash; all fitted out with scooters and helmets, and away we went through the streets of San Cristobal and out to the highway out of town.  Beautiful ride, once we left the city traffic, and we cruised on down the road, with Mandy in the lead since she knew where we were going.  At one point Mandy and Dixie looked back and decided to pull over and wait to see if the rest would catch up from whatever delayed them.  Soon, here they came.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/48315294@N00/7777113978&#34; title=&#34;View &#39;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8439/7777113978_c9d2e4d928_n.jpg&#39; on Flickr.com&#34;&gt; &lt;img style=&#34;float: left;&#34; title=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8439/7777113978_c9d2e4d928_n.jpg&#34; src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8439/7777113978_c9d2e4d928_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8439/7777113978_c9d2e4d928_n.jpg&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/48315294@N00/7777098698&#34; title=&#34;View &#39;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8443/7777098698_c18fd9349f_n.jpg&#39; on Flickr.com&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;float: left;&#34; title=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8443/7777098698_c18fd9349f_n.jpg&#34; src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8443/7777098698_c18fd9349f_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8443/7777098698_c18fd9349f_n.jpg&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shelley and Ozzie all snug like a hot dog! Shelley, Justin, and Sam catching up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We went quite some way out of town and took the exit for Las Grutas and paid our 5 pesos each to get into the park.  The ride through the woods on a gravel road, alone, was worth the trip.  We parked and locked up our bikes and explored the little park.  They have some tall slides made of concrete with lots of kids sliding down on little butt-sized pieces of cardboard and then running back up to the top.  Many people opt for a horseback ride into the wooded areas.  Very inexpensive here.  Others hike.  There are many taco shops, quesadilla shops, other food shops all in a row under the big shelter, so we had lunch after the cave walk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/48315294@N00/7777158796&#34; title=&#34;View &#39;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7125/7777158796_c95b773988_n.jpg&#39; on Flickr.com&#34;&gt;&lt;img title=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7125/7777158796_c95b773988_n.jpg&#34; src=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7125/7777158796_c95b773988_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7125/7777158796_c95b773988_n.jpg&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/48315294@N00/7777165174&#34; title=&#34;View &#39;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8285/7777165174_161f1ee624_n.jpg&#39; on Flickr.com&#34;&gt;&lt;img title=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8285/7777165174_161f1ee624_n.jpg&#34; src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8285/7777165174_161f1ee624_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8285/7777165174_161f1ee624_n.jpg&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/48315294@N00/7777168842&#34; title=&#34;View &#39;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7130/7777168842_89cf753855_n.jpg&#39; on Flickr.com&#34;&gt;&lt;img title=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7130/7777168842_89cf753855_n.jpg&#34; src=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7130/7777168842_89cf753855_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7130/7777168842_89cf753855_n.jpg&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We bought our tickets to see the cave for 10 pesos each (75 cents) and trooped inside.  I expected some cute little cave like a gang of Texas outlaws might hole up in, hiding from the sheriff.  This was actually a large cave with active water deposits being made and stalactites and stalagmites and pools, some lit up with electric lights.  It had a wide path with heavy bright railings.  Very nice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/48315294@N00/7777179866&#34; title=&#34;View &#39;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8288/7777179866_8e600db248_n.jpg&#39; on Flickr.com&#34;&gt;&lt;img title=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8288/7777179866_8e600db248_n.jpg&#34; src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8288/7777179866_8e600db248_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8288/7777179866_8e600db248_n.jpg&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/48315294@N00/7777184042&#34; title=&#34;View &#39;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8433/7777184042_7517ff647a_n.jpg&#39; on Flickr.com&#34;&gt;&lt;img title=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8433/7777184042_7517ff647a_n.jpg&#34; src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8433/7777184042_7517ff647a_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8433/7777184042_7517ff647a_n.jpg&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img title=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8425/7777195068_9e1da8a4e4_n.jpg&#34; src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8425/7777195068_9e1da8a4e4_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8425/7777195068_9e1da8a4e4_n.jpg&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; /&gt;&lt;img title=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8429/7777204926_7b711014ba_n.jpg&#34; src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8429/7777204926_7b711014ba_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8429/7777204926_7b711014ba_n.jpg&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/48315294@N00/7777198972&#34; title=&#34;View &#39;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7116/7777198972_3107d41f09_n.jpg&#39; on Flickr.com&#34;&gt;&lt;img title=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7116/7777198972_3107d41f09_n.jpg&#34; src=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7116/7777198972_3107d41f09_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7116/7777198972_3107d41f09_n.jpg&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/48315294@N00/7777225812&#34; title=&#34;View &#39;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7264/7777225812_b8ae7fbec2_n.jpg&#39; on Flickr.com&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7264/7777225812_b8ae7fbec2_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7264/7777225812_b8ae7fbec2_n.jpg&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The caves go quite a way further, but it goes beneath a military base, so there is a blockage.  Probably good since they also have artillery practice all the time, entertaining us with many explosions.  Mexicans sure do love their explosions (referring to all the heavy firework aerial bombs we&amp;rsquo;re entertained with nightly and in the mornings at 6:00 and all hours in between)!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We emerged from the caves and had a nice quesadilla lunch and we were on our way.  The trip back was going so well, and we had almost made it back to town when disaster hit.  Sam was third in line, I was behind her, and Shelley was bringing up the rear.  Sam got a little far off onto the shoulder and hit some deep gravel, going all out on the scooter downhill, probably 40-45 mph, she fishtailed, got &amp;ldquo;the wobble&amp;rdquo;, and flashed out toward the far oncoming lane, but she spun around and crashed in our lane.  Thankfully all the vehicles behind us had just passed us up so no squishing happened.  She lost a lot of skin on both palms and had some road rash on her forearm, side, and some on her leg and foot.  Shelley and I were almost panicking, and she was the one holding it together as she had me pour water on the palms to get the dirt off.  Then Shelley tore up a towel and wrapped her up.  About this time Mandy and Justin decided something was wrong and came back.  We managed to get Sam back into town and return to pick up her scooter.  She&amp;rsquo;s one tough chick!  And she stood up and survived the torture the doctor put her through at the hospital!  Can you say alcohol poured on raw live meat!?!   But all is well, and she&amp;rsquo;s nearly healed now, and she has a great story to tell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moral of the story:  Don&amp;rsquo;t get into gravel and wear helmet AND GLOVES when riding motorcycles, scooter, and bicycles!  If she&amp;rsquo;d had a jacket on, most of the road rash could also have been avoided.  But we all just opted on the helmets that day.  Dress for the wreck and then don&amp;rsquo;t have one!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All&amp;rsquo;s well that ends well!  Cheers!   She&amp;rsquo;s one tough chick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the whole set of photos:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[slickr-flickr tag=&amp;ldquo;grutas&amp;rdquo;]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>