<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Centralamerica on Vagabondians</title>
    <link>http://vagabondians.com/categories/centralamerica/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Centralamerica on Vagabondians</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright &amp;#169; by Glenn and Dixie Dixon</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vagabondians.com/categories/centralamerica/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Saripiqui River and Canopy Tour</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/saripiqui-river-canopy-tour/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/saripiqui-river-canopy-tour/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a last-gasp effort to see something of the beautiful country of Costa Rica, and with a deal on a tour from a friend, I ventured out alone while Glenn continued to recover from his minor back injury.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&#34;Nice orchid&#34; href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/48315294@N00/9497546273/&#34; rel=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; title=&#34;Nice orchid&#34; src=&#34;http://farm6.staticflickr.com/5448/9497546273_a2b8787d9a_z.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Nice orchid&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;480&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;While being driven out of town alone in a large tour van, via my splotchy Spanish, I finally understood he was taking me to meet another van.  Eventually by the side of the road there was a driver named Carlos and a personable, knowledgeable English/Spanish guide, also named Carlos, and a nice Brazilian couple, and we ventured forth.  Conversation went pretty well between Portuguese, Spanish, and English, and the drive was beautiful as Carlos pointed out the different ecological zones, rain forest, cloud forest, and over the continental divide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/48315294@N00/9497413937/&#34; title=&#34;Canopy tour and lunch grounds&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; title=&#34;Canopy tour and lunch grounds&#34; src=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7425/9497413937_a3104f4e48_z.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Canopy tour and lunch grounds&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;480&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Arriving at a remote property, we went through a gate, down a path, and arrived under a big palapa where there was fresh fruit laid out for us, the sweetest papaya I&amp;rsquo;ve ever had, succulent pineapple, and some fresh bananas.  There were four very cute bats hanging out above, watching us devour our treats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/48315294@N00/9497550527/&#34; title=&#34;Firefly Forest Proboscis Bats hanging from palapa ovrhead&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; title=&#34;Firefly Forest Proboscis Bats hanging from palapa ovrhead&#34; src=&#34;http://farm4.staticflickr.com/3788/9497550527_12969dbc74_z.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Firefly Forest Proboscis Bats hanging from palapa ovrhead&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;480&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just down the path we met our tour boat, and &amp;ndash; after some tinkering with the engine &amp;ndash; off we went down the Sarapiqui River, our guide pointing out the wildlife while the driver brought us right in close for pictures.  Lizards and monkeys and crocodiles, oh my!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/48315294@N00/9500310444/&#34; title=&#34;Granddaddy croc&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; title=&#34;Granddaddy croc&#34; src=&#34;http://farm6.staticflickr.com/5445/9500310444_a2451417dc_z.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Granddaddy croc&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;480&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A pleasant hour later, we climbed the stairs into the jungle for ziplining and lunch.  I was the only taker for the canopy tour, so the Brazilians relaxed and photographed birds while I was geared and helmeted up, led to my horse, and away we went, two walking along the road and three riding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/48315294@N00/9497402681/&#34; title=&#34;Me and my horse to the ziplines&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; title=&#34;Me and my horse to the ziplines&#34; src=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7387/9497402681_783dbaca3e_z.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Me and my horse to the ziplines&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;480&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After about 10-15 minutes we arrived at the beginning of the zip course.  I looked up the ladder and, holy crap!  About 50 feet up that ladder was the first platform. Boy, did my lack of Jazzercizing show!  &lt;em&gt;gasp&lt;/em&gt;  I must have climbed halfway up the Empire State Building between all the high ladders at each platform.  At the end I didn&amp;rsquo;t want it to be the last, but I really couldn&amp;rsquo;t have survived many more ladders!  My two hunky-boy guides were a lot of fun and totally professional, much attention paid to safety on the well-maintained zip course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/48315294@N00/9497405195/&#34; title=&#34;Made it up the ladder&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; title=&#34;Made it up the ladder&#34; src=&#34;http://farm4.staticflickr.com/3759/9497405195_a30a980fe3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Made it up the ladder&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was strongly suggested that canopy tour participants not take their cameras, because the guides would take pictures, so I have none, except a couple I sneaked of the slide show afterwards.  I found it really strange that nobody actually hit me up to buy the pictures.  Such a difference from other countries where there would have been a hard sell. The only animals I saw in the jungle were a pretty orange poison dart frog along the trail and a few battalions of ginormous mosquitoes.  Amazingly, they didn&amp;rsquo;t seem to be too hungry; just a couple toothy vampires.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/48315294@N00/9500267584/&#34; title=&#34;Blue jeans poison dart frog&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; title=&#34;Blue jeans poison dart frog&#34; src=&#34;http://farm6.staticflickr.com/5496/9500267584_7ece833a8f_z.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Blue jeans poison dart frog&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;480&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lunch was typical Costa Rican fare: beans and rice/rice and beans, some pieces of grilled chicken, some salad-y stuff, and a very sweet fruit drink.  Our guide then led us down to a small building where they housed several local species of snakes, from a couple of large boas to some highly venomous vipers, the dreaded fer-de-lance and a pretty yellow eyelash viper. We were told that they only keep them for a little while and then release them as they catch new ones.  The collection was smaller than usual at this time. Next door was another greenhouse building where lots of blue jeans poison dart frogs lived. So cute!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/48315294@N00/9500188100/&#34; title=&#34;DSCN1151&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; title=&#34;DSCN1151&#34; src=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7325/9500188100_3f09621c32_z.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;DSCN1151&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;480&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We got back on the road and experienced an absolute downpour for about half the drive back, up from the river into the cloud forest and back down into drenched San Jose. Enjoy the slide show!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[slickr-flickr tag=&amp;ldquo;saripiqui&amp;rdquo;]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grand Tour of the Islets, Granada, Nicaragua</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/grand-tour-of-the-islets-granada-nicaragua/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/grand-tour-of-the-islets-granada-nicaragua/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When the Mombacho Volcano erupted thousands of years ago, it threw huge rocks into Lake Nicaragua forming 365 islets, very large to very small.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vagabondians.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/07/isletas.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-medium wp-image-2581&#34; src=&#34;http://vagabondians.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/07/isletas.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;isletas&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;168&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a community of about 1200 people living on them, mostly fishermen. Some islands have fabulous houses of the mega wealthy and others have humble cinder block simple dwellings, yet others are simply lush greenery and trees.  Many have hotels and cabanas and houses you can rent or buy.  For a price, a big price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/48315294@N00/9515374813/&#34; title=&#34;Ahhhh&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; title=&#34;Ahhhh&#34; src=&#34;http://farm3.staticflickr.com/2808/9515374813_7488cd049b.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Ahhhh&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lake Managua is huge, but usually calm, and we decided to take the tour boat all the way around the peninsula, touring through many of the islands.  It was a beautiful day, not too hot, and we took off to see what we would see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[slickr-flickr tag=&amp;ldquo;isletas&amp;rdquo;]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Love Your Enemas</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/love-your-enemas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/love-your-enemas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Warning: this post might get a bit graphic. You probably shouldn&amp;rsquo;t read it while eating. You might not want to read it at all! You know how old people can&amp;rsquo;t seem to have a conversation without over-sharing about their bodily functions? Yeah, that&amp;rsquo;s how this is going to go. Alternate titles for this post that I considered:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Enema Within&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;line-height: 1.714285714; font-size: 1rem;&#34;&gt;Public Enema #1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;line-height: 1.714285714; font-size: 1rem;&#34;&gt;Sworn Enemas&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;line-height: 1.714285714; font-size: 1rem;&#34;&gt;Enema at the Gates&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;line-height: 1.714285714; font-size: 1rem;&#34;&gt;Sleeping with the Enema&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My Own Worst Enema&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;line-height: 1.714285714; font-size: 1rem;&#34;&gt;Enema Territory&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Know Thy Enema&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enema Agent&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can you see where this is going? OK, you&amp;rsquo;ve been warned!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were many titles that I could have used for this. If I were a smart travel blogger I probably would have entitled it something like &amp;ldquo;Five Medical Emergency Lessons I Learned in Costa Rica.&amp;rdquo; Instead, I&amp;rsquo;m going with a joke. I hope you appreciate the humor. &lt;img src=&#34;http://v2j.vagabondians.com/wp-includes/images/smilies/simple-smile.png&#34; alt=&#34;:)&#34; class=&#34;wp-smiley&#34; style=&#34;height: 1em; max-height: 1em;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It all started out innocently enough. Dixie and I have generally been on a low-carb diet off and on for the last several years. We have removed most processed foods from regular consumption when possible. While we were in Mexico in 2012 we both lost weight, then promptly regained it when we revisited the states earlier this year. That should probably tell you something. After returning overseas to Nicaragua and Costa Rica we set out to re-lose our excess pounds and in the process we ran across a very interesting diet concept. The basic gist of it is that our bodies naturally guide our appetite based on traditional evolutionary patterns of &amp;lsquo;feast and famine.&amp;rsquo; It&amp;rsquo;s only in the last 10-15,000 years or so that agriculture and animal husbandry smoothed out this process. In the last hundred years or so food has become global and seasons have almost been made obsolete. All foods, all the time, right on your local grocery store shelf.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And yet our bodies are still trying to operate based on a feast or famine scenario. To the part of the brain controlling this, it seems like a lifelong feast has set in, and it keeps the dial turned up to &amp;lsquo;more&amp;rsquo; because surely that famine period will hit any day now. And yet it never does. So we eat too much, just a little every day. The diet in question attempts to turn the dial down by tricking the body. It attempts to game the system by sneaking calories in without any flavor so that the body doesn&amp;rsquo;t associate flavor with those calories. This somehow tricks your body and reduces your appetite. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure I understand all of the mechanisms involved, but it was enough encouragement for us to try it. Theoretically we could eat anything we wanted, but we still avoided highly-processed foods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now there are a few different ways to get calories into your body without strong flavors. The original method is to use sugar water, because for some reason the sweet taste doesn&amp;rsquo;t trigger higher appetite. But it&amp;rsquo;s a hassle, requires a lot of sugar, and Dixie is Type II diabetic on a small dose of Metformin. So sugar is out for her, and we like to do things together. The other option is to use extra light olive oil. In this case the calories all come from fat. After about a week we were both eating a lot less and losing weight. Unfortunately I missed a couple of warning signs and ended up in quite the predicament.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this is where it gets a bit graphic. Again, you&amp;rsquo;ve been warned!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The warning signs that I missed were that my bowel movements became rather solid, more so than usual. On Wednesday morning I went ahead and took my normal four tablespoons of olive oil, but by the afternoon things came to a standstill. Lots of pressure, many attempts, no movement. I did a lot of googling for constipation solutions. In fact, I was well beyond constipation. I should have been googling &amp;lsquo;fecal impaction.&amp;rsquo; Instead, we went to the pharmacy and got some laxative pills. I took one that evening. I didn&amp;rsquo;t sleep well, with a couple of additional attempts in the middle of the night. Thursday morning I took another pill and observed that I was also unable to urinate! I sent Dixie back to the pharmacy for suppositories. The first one lasted fifteen minutes, the second one stayed in place. Neither produced the desired results. I was approaching desperation! Dixie went on another errand and returned with small bottle and a dangerous looking nozzle attachment. It was an enema recommended by the pharmacist. It contained a small amount of sodium solution and 13.4 grams of Sorbitol.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../images/2013/08/EnemaInstructions.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Behold, the Enema&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, sorbitol, the sweetener in items all over the grocery store. It&amp;rsquo;s very prominent in low-carb products. I stopped eating anything containing sorbitol or any other sweetener ending in &amp;lsquo;itol&amp;rsquo; years ago because they caused me quite the intestinal distress, as in diarrhea. But diarrhea sounded pretty good right about now. So I put a towel on the shower floor and proceeded. I&amp;rsquo;ll spare you at least &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; of the details, but things went generally well, especially for my first-ever self-administered enema. I intended to wait as close to fifteen minutes as I could before I had to rush to the toilet. I really did &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; want to have to do a second enema, and I also didn&amp;rsquo;t want to go to the clinic or hospital.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I lasted almost five, and somewhere between the laxative pills, the suppositories and the enema it was just enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end (ha!) it was fairly painful, but at least things were moving. It took about thirty minutes before I became confident that I was out of the danger zone and would not, in fact, die. And then I peed for the first time in a long time and that was also quite a relief! I was exhausted but way more excited about basic bodily functions than normal. I still am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what are the lessons? There ought to be several things learned here, it seems, but I&amp;rsquo;m not sure what they all are yet. Here are my thoughts so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure that my body can not tolerate as much fat as it used to. I had my gallbladder removed almost a decade ago, and the bile that it produces is very important for the digestion of fat. It&amp;rsquo;s even possible that my massive gallstones were originally caused by a &amp;lsquo;slow liver&amp;rsquo; which means that too much fat in my diet will cause all manner of digestion problems and irritation. Evidently this includes impaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, if I ever get into this predicament again, I might be stupid. But just in case, if I do, I&amp;rsquo;m just going straight for the enema.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beyond that, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure. I&amp;rsquo;m just glad to be alive, and I&amp;rsquo;m glad to be free of pain and pressure. I&amp;rsquo;m also a bit gun-shy on making drastic changes to my diet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that was my week. How was yours?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nicaragua in Color</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/nicaragua-in-color/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/nicaragua-in-color/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Vagabondians adventures in lovely, hot, muggy, friendly Nicaragua! Enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[slickr-flickr tag=&amp;ldquo;granada&amp;rdquo;]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Escape from Managua, Nicaragua</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/escape-from-managua-nicaragua/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/escape-from-managua-nicaragua/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;width: 1034px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/48315294@N00/9240886396&#34;&gt;&lt;img title=&#34;The malecon in Managua, Nicaragua&#34; src=&#34;http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5333/9240886396_92b01f58c2_b.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The malecon in Managua, Nicaragua&#34; width=&#34;1024&#34; height=&#34;768&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;
    The malecon in Managua, Nicaragua
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img class=&#34;alignnone alignleft&#34; title=&#34;The malecon in Managua, Nicaragua&#34; src=&#34;http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5333/9240886396_92b01f58c2_b.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The malecon in Managua, Nicaragua&#34; width=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;0&#34; /&gt;Yeah, we should have known that when the guidebooks say it&#39;s not worth hanging in Managua, they are probably right. We walked around. We took a taxi to see the park at the volcano that overlooks the city but were thwarted. There was some kind of official visitation going on there, and they turned us away. We had the taxi take us to the Xolotlan malecon, where there was a fee to get in of about $.50 each. We walked around looking at big Lake Managua and had a decent lunch with beers for cheap at one of the nice cafes there. We saw a Sponge Bob and friend that were in need of a bath and a Barney walking around getting cordobas for posing with park visitors. The lake cruise boat came and went a couple of times. A nice diversion at the lake, but hardly worth coming all the way to Managua for if you&#39;re a tourist.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;width: 1034px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/48315294@N00/9240829598&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; title=&#34;Our first Nicaraguan beer - The Malecon, Managua, Nicaragua&#34; src=&#34;http://farm8.static.flickr.com/7436/9240829598_b623bb2d36_b.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Our first Nicaraguan beer - The Malecon, Managua, Nicaragua&#34; width=&#34;1024&#34; height=&#34;768&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;
    Our first Nicaraguan beer -- The Malecon, Managua, Nicaragua
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The taxi to the bus station the next morning went to the other end of Managua, and the scenery didn&amp;rsquo;t change. A poor city with little to offer for tourism, though they seem to be working on that some. The bus ride out showed us somewhat of a downtown area with business people bustling around a little more modern buildings, but it was not what I would call big city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;width: 778px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/48315294@N00/9238132185&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; title=&#34;Sign in our bathroom, Casa de los Abuelos, Managua, Nicaragua&#34; src=&#34;http://farm8.static.flickr.com/7409/9238132185_61d6790e23_b.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Sign in our bathroom, Casa de los Abuelos, Managua, Nicaragua&#34; width=&#34;768&#34; height=&#34;1024&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;
    Sign in our bathroom, Casa de los Abuelos, Managua, Nicaragua
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eager to escape, we rose early after our second night in the fairly expensive ($35 US) humble hotel in Managua. The owner and staff were very nice and helpful, however, and I would definitely recommend it if you must go to Managua: Hostal Casa de los Abuelos. English spoken there!   Both bus stations in Managua are most definitely &amp;ldquo;third-world.&amp;rdquo; But the transportation is cheap and, um, efficient. If you don&amp;rsquo;t get a (cramped) seat on the bus you want, you can still get on and ride on a stool in the aisle &amp;ndash; and you can bring your puppy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;width: 810px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a title=&#34;Puppy Bus&#34; href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/48315294@N00/9342700271/&#34;&gt;&lt;img title=&#34;Puppy Bus&#34; src=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7451/9342700271_61afa736c5_c.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Puppy Bus&#34; width=&#34;800&#34; height=&#34;600&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;
    Puppy, on the bus to Matagalpa, Nicaragua
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;
  The owner of this puppy lives in Matagalpa and was extremely nice and helped us get a taxi to take us to a budget hostal. He sincerely wanted us to like his city. We even ran into him on the street later on and had a quick conversation before he went to his meeting. Matagalpa is a bustling little city, definitely more attractive than Managua, but it&#39;s no San Cristobal de las Casas &amp;#8212; we got so spoiled there! There are few tourists here with little to draw them, in the rainy season at least. I&#39;m not that eager to hike in the mud or tour coffee plantations. Call me wimpy. We are staying at the Hotel la Profe, which is an upgrade at less than half the price of Managua ($14US). We even have hot water and a fan on the ceiling! Also a nice little porch room to sit and compute.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a title=&#34;The relaxing patio&#34; href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/48315294@N00/9342817313/&#34; rel=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; title=&#34;The relaxing patio&#34; src=&#34;http://farm4.staticflickr.com/3734/9342817313_fb83a17943_c.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The relaxing patio&#34; width=&#34;800&#34; height=&#34;600&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a title=&#34;Beautiful courtyard of la Profe&#34; href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/48315294@N00/9345602878/&#34; rel=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; title=&#34;Beautiful courtyard of la Profe&#34; src=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7453/9345602878_ee6c5a4266_c.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Beautiful courtyard of la Profe&#34; width=&#34;800&#34; height=&#34;600&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We stayed for two nights, enjoyed a local coffee shop for cafe con leche and wifi. Then we headed back down out of the mountains into Granada. Apparently, we like more touristy places where we can meet more travelers!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[slickr-flickr tag=&amp;ldquo;matagalpa&amp;rdquo;]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Price of Free Tickets</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/the-price-of-free-tickets/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/the-price-of-free-tickets/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When we travel, we seek adventure. But sometimes you should be careful what you ask for&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://vagabondians.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/Family.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-2491&#34; src=&#34;http://vagabondians.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/Family.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Family&#34; width=&#34;1024&#34; height=&#34;768&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;After saying goodbye to my parents and then my brother and his wife, we walked into the terminal at DFW Airport. The flight information we had indicated Gate E4, near where we were dropped off. Unfortunately we discovered that the Spirit Air ticket counter was actually on the other end of Terminal E, around Gate 27. So we rented a cart and took a walk. We detoured around a section under construction, exiting to the sidewalk at about Gate 21 and re-entering the building at Gate 30. We were missing a section! Eventually we found the Spirit counter down past Gate 32 and got our boarding passes. After we walked away we discovered that Dixie had passes for both legs, but I only had one. I returned to the counter and received my extra pass without much delay. I&#39;m glad I discovered the error when I did, otherwise I would have walked a 5K to fix it. We were surprised to discover that in spite of the fact that we did not reserve our seats online we were sitting next to each other, with a window seat for both legs. Dixie was happy.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We proceeded through security, where TSA agents took special interest in our bags. I suspect it was because of our one-way tickets, or our destination, or maybe the fact that I had a bag full of electronics gear. Two hard drives, a router, two sets of mini-speakers, headphones, a camera and a plastic bag with enough adapters and cables to assemble my own mini-Skynet. He dug through it, then indicated to me that he was going to swab it. Was he asking permission? What if I said no? LOL I assume he was looking for traces of explosives. Dixie&amp;rsquo;s bag was delayed while they tried to figure out if a pair of scissors was legal. They were (yay?).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We then proceeded through a maze of construction tunnels and underground passageways and long people-movers until we got to our gate, E27. At the time I thought it was a new addition to the airport, but I could never figure out exactly where we were. I could see a major American Airlines hangar out the window, but I thought that was on the west side of the airport, and Terminal E is on the east side. I had to do some research on this, but as it turns out we were actually in the old Delta satellite terminal! When they moved their major hub to Atlanta they abandoned this building and it sat unused for eight years. It is now fully remodeled and all nine gates are exclusively for Spirit Air planes. It is very nice! There are sundries, books, a Starbucks, a Dickey&amp;rsquo;s BBQ, a bar. There are also lots of comfy chairs out away from the gates, very handy if you have an extended layover or get stuck in a weather delay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vagabondians.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/FB_IMG_13725412799713928.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-2493&#34; src=&#34;http://vagabondians.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/FB_IMG_13725412799713928.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;FB_IMG_13725412799713928&#34; width=&#34;1024&#34; height=&#34;768&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vagabondians.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/FB_IMG_13725426329598574.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-2494&#34; src=&#34;http://vagabondians.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/FB_IMG_13725426329598574.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;FB_IMG_13725426329598574&#34; width=&#34;1024&#34; height=&#34;768&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;
  As we sat at the gate it became evident that things were were not going to go smoothly. A flight to Denver was scheduled to depart at 4:55pm. Our Ft. Lauderdale was scheduled for 5:00pm. Both flights had a status of &#39;on time.&#39; After the Denver flight boarded, the truth appeared on the departure board -- 5:50PM. The gate attendants announced that we were overbooked and asked for volunteers to give up their seats in exchange for round trip tickets. I think someone took them up on the offer. We then boarded and finally got into the air around 6:15.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://vagabondians.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/FB_IMG_13725479641120244.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-2495 alignleft&#34; style=&#34;margin-left: 5px; margin-right: 5px;&#34; src=&#34;http://vagabondians.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/FB_IMG_13725479641120244.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;FB_IMG_13725479641120244&#34; width=&#34;225&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;
  We arrived in Fort Lauderdale almost two hours late. But we still arrived at our departure gate almost an hour before the flight, standing room only in Terminal H. It felt like we were already in Nicaragua. Lots of people, many having chosen spots on the floor to sleep. About ten minutes later our gate crew started asking for volunteers to give up their seats. At first the only inducement mentioned was a meal voucher. No one bit. Eventually someone figured out that there were no other good &#34;next available flight&#34; options, so they upped the ante. A free night&#39;s lodging was added. Still no go. Then they offered a free round trip ticket. That seemed to do the trick.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One spanish speaker beat me to the gate, asked some questions then walked off to consult with others. I asked about the details, then asked about the round trip ticket. I was trying to make sure both Dixie and I would get one. The gate attendant evidently thought I was trying to play hardball, and said &amp;ldquo;OK, two round-trip tickets for each of you.&amp;rdquo; SOLD!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We both filled out voucher forms. At some point we were told that this was conditional, that we still might be boarded on the flight, and we understood that. We were instructed to go back past security to the Spirit ticket counter and ask for a supervisor. We made the long walk, waited in line, then asked a customer service person for the supervisor and she took our boarding passes and vouchers into a back room. After about twenty minutes Xomorro (&amp;lsquo;Shomorrow&amp;rsquo;) came out and told us that there were problems. The only way to get us to Managua was to fly to Panama the next day on Copa Air out of Miami, then the day after that we would fly to Nicaragua. We told her that wasn&amp;rsquo;t a problem at all! She was relieved, and a bit confused. We explained that we were traveling through Central and South America. Evidently not too many people do that. LOL&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She then explained the following things that we would get at no extra cost to us:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One night at a Ft. Lauderdale hotel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One meal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A cab to Miami International the next day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A flight to Panama&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A night at a Panama hotel for the 16-hr layover&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A flight to Managua, Nicaragua&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When she went back into the back office to finalize things, we were excited! An adventure for sure, a good way to start the trip. Plus, an extra country stamped on our Passports. And then she came back out and ruined everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Evidently, the plane was, incredibly &amp;#8212; 30 minutes after &amp;lsquo;final&amp;rsquo; boarding &amp;#8212; still sitting at the gate, and the captain decided they had room and could wait for us. Xomorra was apologetic and seemed incredulous that they would do this. We had to go back through security, walk all the way down to the end of the terminal again. The gate attendant apologized profusely and took down our confirmation number and promised to give us one free round-trip each. Then we walked on to the plane full of tired, cranky people. And what a lovely and warm reception we got! It felt incredibly frustrating trying to explain all of what just happened with a facial expression. We did get to tell our story to a couple of people around us, plus a flight attendant. The rest of the plane were probably just staring daggers at us. I hope they at least think we&amp;rsquo;re really rich or important people who pulled strings. Of course if that were true, we would have been sitting in the front of the plane, not the exit row.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The plane finally left the gate about fifteen minutes later. The flight was originally scheduled to arrive in Nicaragua at 12:23AM. As we taxied to the terminal the pilot announced that it was 2:15. We cleared immigration after someone escorted Dixie to an ATM. We had forgotten about the entry fee ($10 US each). Customs was quick and painless. The taxi driver found the hostal without too much delay and we were in bed by 3:00am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first it seemed like we would lie awake forever, our brains unable to shut down. The small window unit struggled to overcome the intense humidity. Eventually our brains were lulled to sleep by the ambient symphony of a light rain and air-conditioning throbs and window pane rattles and the occasional chirping of the geckos who watched over us. We slept the sleep of the dead.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We Woke up in Nicaragua!</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/we-woke-up-in-nicaragua/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/we-woke-up-in-nicaragua/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Waking up in Nicaragua is different!  Bird calls outside the window.  Lots of them &amp;ndash; including a polite rooster across the drainage ditch who waited until after the sun was up to crow only one series of cock-a-doodle-doos.  (The Mexican ones crow constantly for any reason, not just good-morning!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;attachment_2558&#34; style=&#34;width: 1034px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://vagabondians.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/mangos.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-full wp-image-2558&#34; src=&#34;http://vagabondians.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/mangos.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Mangos outside our hostel&#34; width=&#34;1024&#34; height=&#34;768&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;
    Mangos outside our hostel
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;
  In just a few minutes I have seen some fat brown birds, several great kiskadees, numerous doves, some beautiful dusky blue birds resembling blue budgies in pet stores but larger, and a gorgeous yellow and black bird with a bright orange hood.  And here we are in the middle of Managua, the bustling capitol of Nicaragua, though we are in a poorer barrio, not downtown.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;attachment_2559&#34; style=&#34;width: 1034px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://vagabondians.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/casadelosabuelos.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-full wp-image-2559&#34; src=&#34;http://vagabondians.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/casadelosabuelos.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;View of the courtyard from our door&#34; width=&#34;1024&#34; height=&#34;768&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;
    View of the courtyard from our door
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sitting in the hostal kitchen with the sounds of cars and horse carts going by outside.  Thus begins our newest adventure in a new country!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visit to Guatemala</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/visit-to-guatemala/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/visit-to-guatemala/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since our visas for Mexico were about to expire, we had to take a little trip over the border for at least 72 hours, so we chose the nearest border, Guatemala.  We&amp;rsquo;d heard good things about Panajachel on Lake Atitlan, so that&amp;rsquo;s where we decided to head.  Friends told us the best way to go is on a shuttle instead of taking a bus line as one bus line will take you to the border and then you have to pick up another, and you are left to your own devices in accomplishing the border crossing.  With the shuttle, the driver makes sure everyone gets through immigration and onto the shuttle in the next country.  Much easier to avoid all kinds of scams from people offering to &amp;ldquo;help&amp;rdquo; you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/48315294@N00/7895464908&#34; title=&#34;View &#39;Glenn waits for the shuttle&#39; on Flickr.com&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8318/7895464908_2ca09b608a_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Glenn waits for the shuttle&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/48315294@N00/7895466276&#34; title=&#34;View &#39;Clouds in the mountains&#39; on Flickr.com&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8453/7895466276_a2edc2aed3_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Clouds in the mountains&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The drive in the Mexican countryside was just beautiful, and we arrived at the border crossing around noon.  The crossing went smoothly, except for one guy that had overstayed his visa and had to go find an ATM to get enough cash to pay the daily fines.  We were then driven about 10 minutes to the actual border and pointed toward the entry station for Guatemala where we walked over with all our luggage and got stamped in with a visa for Guatemala.  Our new driver was waiting and got us all safely into his van and we were off again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/48315294@N00/7895470854&#34; title=&#34;View &#39;Waiting to go to our Guatemalan shuttle&#39; on Flickr.com&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8316/7895470854_bd8c7d10a2_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Waiting to go to our Guatemalan shuttle&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The scenery was equally beautiful, green jungle and croplands butting up together.  The fields went right up the steepest mountain slopes, some terraced, some not.  Lots of corn.  Right off, I noticed that Guatemalan women almost all wear the traditional skirt and top, similar to that of the indigenous women in San Cristobal; and unlike San Cris, it&amp;rsquo;s very common for them to carry their heavy loads balanced on their heads.  The indigenous in San Cris usually wrap their loads and/or their babies in their rebozos on their backs and tied diagonally around their torsos.  The Guatemalans do both.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/48315294@N00/7895478870&#34; title=&#34;View &#39;Guatemalan ladies&#39; on Flickr.com&#34;&gt;&lt;img title=&#34;Guatemalan ladies&#34; src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8297/7895478870_8147990e98_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Guatemalan ladies&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We finally arrived in Panajachel and after checking 3 hotels on the main drag, elected to stay at Hotel Chaparral.  Pretty place and a huge 2nd-floor room with 3 full-size beds was about $22 US a night.  Internet was included, but it only worked well out on the bench outside our room, though that&amp;rsquo;s a pleasant place to be.  Also down on the table in the courtyard.  Ahhh!  We had a nice steak dinner and wine at a little restaurant down the road.  We spent more than we intended, since the Quetzal is worth double the Peso and we didn&amp;rsquo;t check, but the food was good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/48315294@N00/7895474630&#34; title=&#34;View &#39;Our room in Pana&#39; on Flickr.com&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8034/7895474630_4c5c403277_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Our room in Pana&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;   &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/48315294@N00/7895493632&#34; title=&#34;View &#39;Hotel Chaparral&#39; on Flickr.com&#34;&gt;&lt;img title=&#34;Hotel Chaparral&#34; src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8452/7895493632_300d2ca77d_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Hotel Chaparral&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next morning we decided to stroll down and see this beautiful lake we&amp;rsquo;d heard about, the biggest in Guatemala, sporting 3 volcanos around the edge.  Truly beautiful!  In the mornings the water is so calm and serene, and we watched launches and fishing boats and dugout canoes traversing.  Afternoon trips are a bit more exciting as the winds pick up and the lake gets wavy.  If you&amp;rsquo;re prone to motion sickness, come back home early!  Myself, I loved it all and insisted my window be open even if I was getting splashed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/48315294@N00/7895488014&#34; title=&#34;View &#39;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8300/7895488014_2784f68c46_n.jpg&#39; on Flickr.com&#34;&gt;&lt;img title=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8300/7895488014_2784f68c46_n.jpg&#34; src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8300/7895488014_2784f68c46_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8300/7895488014_2784f68c46_n.jpg&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/48315294@N00/7895486244&#34; title=&#34;View &#39;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8444/7895486244_d99418bb81_n.jpg&#39; on Flickr.com&#34;&gt;&lt;img title=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8444/7895486244_d99418bb81_n.jpg&#34; src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8444/7895486244_d99418bb81_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8444/7895486244_d99418bb81_n.jpg&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We walked around and explored and figured out the launch situation and decided to go to San Marcos the next morning.  There is a river that enters the lake near the docks.  Lots of guys working separating gravel from little river rock to bigger rocks for sale for construction and gardens.  The river had come through at some point and ripped huge pieces of bank out, including some buildings and roads.  We had a nice exploratory walk around town and on the main drag.  We discovered the people selling things to tourists in Pana are extremely persistent compared to the indigenous in San Cris.  Instead of going to the next person after you say, No, gracias, they pester you for a while to see if they can wear you down.  Guess it works on some or they wouldn&amp;rsquo;t do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/48315294@N00/7895491322&#34; title=&#34;View &#39;Road ends - gone&#39; on Flickr.com&#34;&gt;&lt;img title=&#34;Road ends - gone&#34; src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8042/7895491322_4dd780b105_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Road ends - gone&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One lady who spotted me and made a bee line to the back of the restaurant just would not go away, so I offered her a Quetzal for a picture.  She got all huffy and said that a Quetzal &amp;ldquo;no compra nada!&amp;rdquo; (doesn&amp;rsquo;t buy anything).  She wanted 10Q, but I finally convinced her for 5 Q.  She let Glenn test the weight of her head bundle, and he said it weighed about 20 pounds!  These ladies do work hard walking all day with their arms laden with textiles and more in the bundle on their head.  I had finally just accepted the fact that the street sellers were part of the tourist experience so I could interact with them and not be intimidated.  Another lady who spoke some English said, &amp;ldquo;Oh, I remember you, how are you?  What&amp;rsquo;s your name?&amp;rdquo; all friendly-like.  When I still wouldn&amp;rsquo;t buy her stuff, she said, &amp;ldquo;Never buy!&amp;rdquo; and turned around and strode away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/48315294@N00/7895546288&#34; title=&#34;View &#39;Persistence pays off&#39; on Flickr.com&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8169/7895546288_cdaecf0bce_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Persistence pays off&#34; width=&#34;240&#34; height=&#34;320&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We caught the launch to San Marcos to explore that town on the second morning.  We were &amp;ldquo;serenaded&amp;rdquo; by a guy practicing his rap tunes with his iPod in his ears.  Sorry, but, dude, don&amp;rsquo;t quit your day job!  The launch stopped twice on the way to pick up and deliver passengers.  Seems that about everybody uses them, and the price for locals is about half or less what they charge tourists, which is about $3.75 each for a trip to whatever stop around the edge you choose.  Each stop had what used to be covered deck areas to wait that were about a foot and a half underwater and had new walkways above the water level.  Many who built too close to the water have lost their homes to rising lake levels in recent years, mostly expats that wanted to be too close to the water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/48315294@N00/7895543208&#34; title=&#34;View &#39;Lake Atitlan has been rising&#39; on Flickr.com&#34;&gt;&lt;img title=&#34;Lake Atitlan has been rising&#34; src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8443/7895543208_0f137ef124_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Lake Atitlan has been rising&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;San Marcos had basically one walkway from the docks up to the small town that was lined with New-Age-y shops and various healing centers and some little restaurants.  Very quaint and nice.  We walked around town for about half an hour and saw most of what was there outside the residential areas, and then we had lunch down a little side path on the main walkway.  A little place with two or three tables called Maya Jovenes (Young Maya) that was owned and run by a smart young Mayan guy named Marco who was a wonderful chef and also spoke English pretty well.  Very nice little place to hang out for lunch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/48315294@N00/7895511196&#34; title=&#34;View &#39;Owner/chef at Maya Jovenes&#39; on Flickr.com&#34;&gt;&lt;img title=&#34;Owner/chef at Maya Jovenes&#34; src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8300/7895511196_fbe02c8094_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Owner/chef at Maya Jovenes&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/48315294@N00/7895509040&#34; title=&#34;View &#39;Excellent crepes and sandwich&#39; on Flickr.com&#34;&gt;&lt;img title=&#34;Excellent crepes and sandwich&#34; src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8440/7895509040_830f9851fe_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Excellent crepes and sandwich&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That evening, after a rough-and-tumble launch ride back, when we were on our computers, a huge BOOOOOMMMMM  startled us.  Being familiar with the Mexican Catholics and their love of exploding &amp;ldquo;mortar shells&amp;rdquo; in the air at all hours, we weren&amp;rsquo;t alarmed.  I heard a marching band in the distance and went out &amp;ndash; oh, boy, a parade!  It consisted of the marching band from a Christian school and their team of flag girls dancing routines, a van in the lead with loudspeakers to announce whatever &amp;ndash; couldn&amp;rsquo;t catch anything they said &amp;ndash; and a couple of &amp;ldquo;floats&amp;rdquo; with girls on couches in the back of the trucks.  The whole thing moved extremely slowly, so took about a half hour to go by.  Then the band stopped and marched in place and played for literally hours at the far end of the main drag.  How exciting!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/48315294@N00/7895517064&#34; title=&#34;View &#39;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8314/7895517064_4b633b5788_n.jpg&#39; on Flickr.com&#34;&gt;&lt;img title=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8314/7895517064_4b633b5788_n.jpg&#34; src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8314/7895517064_4b633b5788_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8314/7895517064_4b633b5788_n.jpg&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/48315294@N00/7895514810&#34; title=&#34;View &#39;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8436/7895514810_4102682947_n.jpg&#39; on Flickr.com&#34;&gt;&lt;img title=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8436/7895514810_4102682947_n.jpg&#34; src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8436/7895514810_4102682947_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8436/7895514810_4102682947_n.jpg&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/48315294@N00/7895513684&#34; title=&#34;View &#39;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8172/7895513684_937405f5f7_n.jpg&#39; on Flickr.com&#34;&gt;&lt;img title=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8172/7895513684_937405f5f7_n.jpg&#34; src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8172/7895513684_937405f5f7_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8172/7895513684_937405f5f7_n.jpg&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our last day we took the launch over to San Pedro.  This town has a reputation for being sort of a hippie town with lots of pot smoked and laid-back characters around.  It seemed to be a bigger town with fewer tourists and street sellers.  Very nice vibe and lots of nice murals on lots of buildings and shops.  We had lunch at The Burrito Factory run by a hippie-type fellow that lived in the back.  He had a gorgeous deck over the edge of the lake that was his backyard when the restaurant is closed.  He was not kidding that he has the biggest burritos in Guatemala.  We split one and were both absolutely stuffed with his tasty concoction.  We lounged there under the shade and enjoyed the lake for quite a while before leaving to get back before the waves got bad.  Unfortunately, the waves were early, but it was a fun ride.  We agreed that if we go back, we will skip Pana and head straight for San Pedro, maybe stay there a few weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/48315294@N00/7895540498&#34; title=&#34;View &#39;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8437/7895540498_0662235c52_n.jpg&#39; on Flickr.com&#34;&gt;&lt;img title=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8437/7895540498_0662235c52_n.jpg&#34; src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8437/7895540498_0662235c52_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8437/7895540498_0662235c52_n.jpg&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/48315294@N00/7895542368&#34; title=&#34;View &#39;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8450/7895542368_c2583c8def_n.jpg&#39; on Flickr.com&#34;&gt;&lt;img title=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8450/7895542368_c2583c8def_n.jpg&#34; src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8450/7895542368_c2583c8def_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8450/7895542368_c2583c8def_n.jpg&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next morning we had to catch our shuttle at 6:30 a.m. for a beautiful ride back to the border and back home to San Cris with our shiny new visas.  On the drive back I made a game of trying to get pics of the gas stations and their &amp;ldquo;signs&amp;rdquo; showing one was up ahead.  If you see a stack of plastic jerrycans of different sizes with prices written on them in marks-a-lot, there&amp;rsquo;s a &amp;ldquo;gas station&amp;rdquo; just ahead.  There are no traditional gas stations outside larger cities.  It seems that families assign young boys to sell gas beside the road.  You can buy a little or a lot, and the kid will run up, pour in your choice, collect the money, and you&amp;rsquo;re off again.  They have these in Mexico as well, as our taxi bought a small amount of gas this way when we went to Oventic, but in Guatemala they are plentiful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/48315294@N00/7895552288&#34; title=&#34;View &#39;Gas station&#39; on Flickr.com&#34;&gt;&lt;img title=&#34;Gas station&#34; src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8319/7895552288_612c59ff81_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Gas station&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/48315294@N00/7895551406&#34; title=&#34;View &#39;Gas station signs&#39; on Flickr.com&#34;&gt;&lt;img title=&#34;Gas station signs&#34; src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8034/7895551406_8db3407cd5_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Gas station signs&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At last we arrived back in San Cristobal after another 10-11 hour shuttle ride.  Ahh, home, sweet home &amp;ndash; at least for a little while.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are ALL the pictures &amp;#8212; just click one to see a bigger version or to start slideshow mode&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[slickr-flickr tag=&amp;ldquo;atitlan&amp;rdquo;]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>