<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Guadalajara on Vagabondians</title>
    <link>http://vagabondians.com/tags/guadalajara/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Guadalajara on Vagabondians</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright &amp;#169; by Glenn and Dixie Dixon</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vagabondians.com/tags/guadalajara/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>On The Road Again</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/on-the-road-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/on-the-road-again/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; title=&#34;Bus Terminal&#34; src=&#34;https://fbcdn-sphotos-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash3/600165_10151896098365437_1236436281_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;550&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And now, at long last, the next phase of our journey begins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last few weeks have been busy. Our homeowner dropped in for a two-week stay and initiated a flurry of activity! We ran around getting automobile repair estimates and looking for replacement kitchen sinks and cleaning the house in preparation for the new property managers to take pictures. We also showed the home to a potential renter and took both dogs and both cats to the vet. In addition to that, we picked up some utensils and cookware and a portable electric stove top. We also got the house ready for the new housesitter and went over all of the details with her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whew!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://fbcdn-sphotos-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash4/376442_10151896099480437_403310213_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;540&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So Tuesday morning we had a driver pick us up and deliver us to the main bus station in eastern Guadalajara, near Tonala. We rode in amazing comfort on a Primera Plus coach and stopped only once. The whole trip lasted just over four hours. The seats lean back twice as far as on the standard economy fare airline seat, and they have footrests that fold down from the seat in front. Lights and air vents are overhead. Each seat has its own audio jack where you can listen to one of several stations or just pick up the audio from the on-board movie. I watched Transformers 2 in Spanish. Interesting. There are also men&amp;rsquo;s and women&amp;rsquo;s restrooms in the back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://fbcdn-sphotos-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash3/600382_10151896100380437_1848917125_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;540&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we stopped at Leon it began to rain, but by the time we were halfway to Guanajuato the skies had cleared. At one point our bus was selected (randomly?) for an inspection by some nice people from the Mexican army. The first one on board announced the inspection and seemed to generally calm everyone. He then walked through and inspected everyone&amp;rsquo;s bags and purses. I presume he was looking for weapons, drugs and/or explosives. And just in case you thought his calm demeanor was a sign of weakness, a second soldier stepped into the doorway and watched while resting his hand on the grip of his H&amp;amp;K G3 Battle Rifle. That&amp;rsquo;s a big gun!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://fbcdn-sphotos-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash4/306606_10151897024320437_59276117_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;540&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Very soon we were on our way again and we arrived in Guanajuato only slightly behind schedule. We took a taxi directly to our intended destination, the Hostel Alonso. We were so excited &amp;ndash; our very first night in a hostel! And so far it has not disappointed one bit. Our room is private and on the second floor. The shower is also the toilet. The toilets do not have seats. Supposedly this has something to do with scorpions, but I think I&amp;rsquo;d rather not know for sure&amp;hellip; The bed is just about as firm as it can get. We are, so far, sharing the facilities with two Japanese girls and two other couple from parts unknown. We are, also, unsurprisingly the oldest people in the building, by far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://fbcdn-sphotos-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash4/314072_10151896101395437_1880566886_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;540&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://fbcdn-sphotos-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash4/396623_10151896102090437_627351429_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;540&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://fbcdn-sphotos-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-snc7/376323_10151897024460437_1622543814_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We strolled the city a couple of times, mainly the area around the Jardin de la Union. We walked by Casa de Pita, the B&amp;amp;B we used on our first visit back in 2008. We bought a coca light and an agua at the nearby tienda just for old times sake. We had a decent dinner at a restaurant, a latte at a local coffee shop and picked up some drinks and snacks at an Oxxo convenience store. All set for the night!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://fbcdn-sphotos-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash3/530797_10151896104440437_57620121_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;540&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://fbcdn-sphotos-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-snc6/250820_10151896102585437_88422294_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;540&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is the rainy season in this part of Mexico. It starts in mid-June and ends later in the year. Normally they say that the rain arrives with San Antonio and departs with San Francisco. No, not the cities &amp;#8212; those are days honoring the saints. Dia de San Antonio is June 13, Dia de San Francisco is October 10. The rain started in Chapala right around June 11, and it hasn&amp;rsquo;t stopped since. Mostly it rains in the middle of the night, but here and there you get it during the day as well. It rained last night so hopefully we can walk around all day without worrying about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More pictures soon, and most will be added to Facebook. You can see the whole album here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&#34;Guanajuato&#34; href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/media/set/?set=a.10151896097500437.874894.648515436&amp;type=1&amp;l=8d63902558&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Guanajuato&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clothes Shopping in the Big City -- Guadalajara, Jalisco, MX</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/clothes-shopping-in-the-big-city-guadalajara/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/clothes-shopping-in-the-big-city-guadalajara/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://a1.sphotos.ak.fbcdn.net/hphotos-ak-snc6/s720x720/150736_10150977957908993_677503992_11925514_1748571729_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;100&#34; align=&#34;left&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today was a big treat &amp;ndash; my neighborhood friend Yolanda took me shopping all around the city center area near the big cathedral in downtown Guadalajara.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are so many stores for everything you can imagine.  There&amp;rsquo;s even a building the size of Sears or Penney&amp;rsquo;s, multiple floors, that is full, full, full of nothing but jewelry shops.  Lots of police all around that one &amp;ndash; with big dogs, beautiful Belgian Malinois.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://a2.sphotos.ak.fbcdn.net/hphotos-ak-snc6/166042_10150977898108993_677503992_11925393_513595731_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;75&#34; align=&#34;right&#34; /&gt;There are some expensive fru-fru stores, but we didn&amp;rsquo;t go to those.  I&amp;rsquo;m on a budget, and I need things for the heat and the beach.  My heavy dark pants and tops aren&amp;rsquo;t going to cut it anymore.  Usually I shop and shop and buy nothing, but today was a good day, starting with a nice little comfy artsy top for 130 pesos ($9.40).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://a7.sphotos.ak.fbcdn.net/hphotos-ak-snc7/577487_10150977899458993_677503992_11925396_2052232393_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;100&#34; align=&#34;left&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://a5.sphotos.ak.fbcdn.net/hphotos-ak-ash3/545641_10150977898958993_677503992_11925395_94931201_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;100&#34; align=&#34;left&#34; /&gt;Next we went to another store where I bought a fluffy dressy blouse for 180 pesos ($13.02) and an open-knit ziz-zag top for 130 pesos ($9.40).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://a2.sphotos.ak.fbcdn.net/hphotos-ak-prn1/525668_10150977900988993_677503992_11925401_559430124_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;100&#34; align=&#34;right&#34; /&gt;We went in three shoe shops before they had my choice of sandals for my big size 8 feet.  Those set me back 160 pesos ($11.57).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://a2.sphotos.ak.fbcdn.net/hphotos-ak-snc7/303448_10150977899833993_677503992_11925398_1629554372_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;75&#34; align=&#34;left&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://a8.sphotos.ak.fbcdn.net/hphotos-ak-snc7/74758_10150977900273993_677503992_11925399_248805157_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;75&#34; align=&#34;left&#34; /&gt;Got a nice jersey sundress for 120 pesos ($8.68) and some decorated jeans for 150 pesos ($10.85).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We wandered through the huge multi-story market with stalls and stalls of everything from cow feet and ankles to veggies to little birds to clothing and purses and toys and pink guitars in green cases to mariachi suits adult to baby size.  I really don&amp;rsquo;t know how &lt;img src=&#34;http://a8.sphotos.ak.fbcdn.net/hphotos-ak-ash3/560219_10150977897493993_677503992_11925392_494293446_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; align=&#34;right&#34; /&gt; you would cook a cow hoof with about 10 inches of leg, but apparently somebody does.  And I have a local friend who loves to eat chicken feet that are sold everywhere you buy chicken.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I bought a nice leather belt for Glenn for 180 pesos ($13.02) and Yo bought some little purses to give as gifts on her trip back to Canada in a couple of weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://a8.sphotos.ak.fbcdn.net/hphotos-ak-ash2/149730_10150977900583993_677503992_11925400_2141177313_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;75&#34; align=&#34;right&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also bought a cotton skirt that I didn&amp;rsquo;t really want that bad, but she kept coming down on the price.  It wasn&amp;rsquo;t the price I objected to but finally I felt I had to buy it.  It will be great in the beach heat though.  Not $250 pesos ($18.08) but 190 pesos ($13.74).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://a7.sphotos.ak.fbcdn.net/hphotos-ak-ash2/156498_10150977894693993_677503992_11925382_1860967956_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;100&#34; align=&#34;left&#34; /&gt;We went into the big cathedral and sat for a few minutes looking at the beautiful carving work on the arches and the stained glass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had lunch at Yo&amp;rsquo;s favorite restaurant downtown, El Mexicano, and arrachera that was really good, though not as good as the one we had in Tlaquepaque.  It&amp;rsquo;s thin flank steak, marinated and cooked to tender perfection.  So good!  We have it wherever we go and judge each restaurant on it.&lt;img src=&#34;http://a4.sphotos.ak.fbcdn.net/hphotos-ak-snc7/582389_10150977896943993_677503992_11925390_900779950_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;175&#34; align=&#34;right&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So amazingly I bought eight major clothing items and spent a whopping $89.69 US.  Do that in Dallas!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day Trip!  Tlaquepaque/Guadalajara</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/day-trip-tlaquepaque-guadalajara/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/day-trip-tlaquepaque-guadalajara/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our friends in the neighborhood, Jean-Pierre and Yolanda Luisser, French-Canadians from Quebec, invited us to join them on a day trip to Guadalajara on Sunday, March 25. Oh, boy! A trip to the big city with someone who knows where to go and what to see &amp;ndash; and most importantly, how to drive in that crazy place! So we set out about 10 in the morning, first stop Tlaquepaque, a town on the outskirts that I first heard about on The Travel Channel long ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://fbcdn-sphotos-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-prn1/526280_10150842926778993_677503992_11703252_2078959908_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;548&#34; height=&#34;411&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We parked in a parking lot with a shade, a big plus, and walked in. There’s a main drag with lots of art work installed in addition to all the art and wares set up in doorways and down the sidewalks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://fbcdn-sphotos-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash3/545696_10150842929348993_677503992_11703272_817768460_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;546&#34; height=&#34;727&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://fbcdn-sphotos-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash3/562625_10150842930948993_677503992_11703285_598043878_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;551&#34; height=&#34;413&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We came to a little courtyard where some artists had their tables set up with all kinds of really interesting things. An artist carving little buildings and streets from wood to intricate jewelry made of paper to painted ostrich eggs and jewelry made of natural plant parts. Yo bought paper earrings to match her top, and I bought some big fun seed pod earrings, each original handmade purchase under $4.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://fbcdn-sphotos-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash3/526274_10150842927968993_677503992_11703262_2134521238_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;550&#34; height=&#34;412&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We oooh’d and aaaah’d over many different shops, but Jean-Pierre took us into the tequila shops for tastes of their wares. Wow! Some very interesting flavors. And we bought a tequila flavored with membrillo, a beautiful aperitif or dessert liquor. I almost got some chocolate liquor from the second shop that was out of this world but restrained myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next stop was lunch where they introduced us to a very fine arrachera, which is a marinated steak, thin like the Mexicans do it, but cooked to perfection and, oh, so gooooood, and the grilled marinated shrimp were scrumptious! Now, wherever we go we have to try the arrachera! Three places so far, but that was the best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://fbcdn-sphotos-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash3/523969_10150842932913993_677503992_11703313_1477186929_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;549&#34; height=&#34;411&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://fbcdn-sphotos-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-snc7/485655_10150842933258993_677503992_11703319_905966958_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;550&#34; height=&#34;412&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Onward to Guadalajara. Jean-Pierre has been down here a while and drives like a Mexican, which is to say he’s fearless! And they know where the interesting things are. Downtown is popular on the weekends and there is a huge market covering a couple of city blocks and three stories tall! Glenn forgot to wear his hat, so we went in search of un sombrero nuevo. I bought one for about $7.25, and we finally found one for Glenn at about $18, and fine hats they are! They guy selling the men’s hats had spent a bit of time in California, so Glenn got to use his cholo impersonation on him &amp;ndash; ha!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://fbcdn-sphotos-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-snc7/581238_10150842942193993_677503992_11703371_1155888420_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;557&#34; height=&#34;417&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://fbcdn-sphotos-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-prn1/560278_10150842942463993_677503992_11703376_420311012_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;550&#34; height=&#34;412&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we wandered around the big city, we saw some clowns entertaining a small crowd and wandered up.  Oops!  We&amp;rsquo;ve been spotted and dragged into the show!  But Yolanda and I each got a nice little balloon flower and gave multiple almost-kisses to the clown on the cheek and mugged for the crowd. Silly gringas!  And we saw a monk floating over his rug &amp;ndash; woo-woo &amp;ndash; and he had big Jerry Lewis teeth through which to give his sage advice to the onlookers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://fbcdn-sphotos-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-snc7/295243_10150842951663993_677503992_11703414_1117240413_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;550&#34; height=&#34;732&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://fbcdn-sphotos-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-prn1/535231_10150842943653993_677503992_11703383_1681778862_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;552&#34; height=&#34;414&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We finished up on the way back with a trip to Costco and then headed home. We took a back road to avoid some traffic and got to enjoy sunset in some small villages along the way. A great trip &amp;ndash; and a big thank you to our friends for a fine day!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can see all of the photos from the day &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/media/set/?set=a.10150842926278993.471576.677503992&amp;type=3&amp;l=6c76603fd0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;right here&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>