<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Texas on Vagabondians</title>
    <link>http://vagabondians.com/tags/texas/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Texas on Vagabondians</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright &amp;#169; by Glenn and Dixie Dixon</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vagabondians.com/tags/texas/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>If You Can&#39;t Stand The Heat, Get Out of Texas</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/if-you-cant-stand-the-heat-get-out-of-texas/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/if-you-cant-stand-the-heat-get-out-of-texas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As we approach our final few days in Texas our home state has decided to give us a warm send-off. VERY warm. Today&amp;rsquo;s high will reach 101-104. Friday it will hit 103-109, depending on which weather source you look at.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vagabondians.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/TXweather.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-2480&#34; src=&#34;http://vagabondians.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/TXweather.png&#34; alt=&#34;TXweather&#34; width=&#34;784&#34; height=&#34;192&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So to escape the heat, we&amp;rsquo;ll be traveling to Central America. Yes, that&amp;rsquo;s right, the place with the hot oceans and tropical jungles &amp;#8212; much closer to the equator than Texas &amp;#8212; and yet, also much cooler! The city we plan on visiting first is Matagalpa, Nicaragua. The elevation is only slightly above 2000 feet, and yet the temperature range for this time of year is typically 70-83. By going &lt;em&gt;south&lt;/em&gt; we will be losing 15-20 degrees! Strange, isn&amp;rsquo;t it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;width: 610px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://www.nicaragua-magazine.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/Best-Matagalpa-Attractions-Waterfall-shadow.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;600&#34; height=&#34;401&#34; /&gt;

  &lt;p class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;
    Waterfalls in Matagalpa
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key, of course, is altitude. We will be leaving the 604 ft. elevation of North Texas and going to the 2352 ft. elevation of central Nicaragua. It&amp;rsquo;s the heart of coffee country, and we will arrive at the beginning of the rainy season. We&amp;rsquo;re really looking forward to the cooler, wetter weather. I certainly hope Texas comes out of the drought soon &amp;#8212; maybe next year?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vagabondians.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/lakeaustin.jpeg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-2481&#34; src=&#34;http://vagabondians.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/lakeaustin.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;jwj Lake Levels 0733&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;316&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Just a quick update</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/just-a-quick-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/just-a-quick-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yep, we&amp;rsquo;re still in Texas!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actually, Dixie made a trip to Michigan to see her sister. I&amp;rsquo;m still in Texas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dixie has finished her TEFL certificate classes, and I am busy working on WordPress sites for various clients. We hope to be back on the road by the first week in June, probably headed for Nicaragua unless plans shift. Still have lots of changes to make to the site here and lots of photos and video yet to post. We&amp;rsquo;ll get caught up on all that eventually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Taste of Texas old style</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/a-taste-of-texas-old-style/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/a-taste-of-texas-old-style/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-thumbnail wp-image-2327&#34; src=&#34;{{ Site.BaseURL }}/images/2013/03/859157_10152561540140437_1144931359_o.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;D/FW Airport&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We won&amp;rsquo;t be back in Texas for very long, but one thing we want to do a bit differently this visit is to see some sights, things we haven&amp;rsquo;t seen before, in spite of living here for most of our lives. In other words,we&amp;rsquo;re going to visit Texas like a tourist!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;![Framed][1]
We went along with our friends Steve and Joyce to see the home show in Fort Worth. It&amp;rsquo;s sort of a tradition. Of course we don&amp;rsquo;t own a home anymore, and all of our rentals are overseas, so we&amp;rsquo;re not really the target audience. But Dixie really likes home shows. She got a free massage and a couple of TENS unit massages.She also got an application of some sort of miracle face cream, but only under one eye. It was kinda like a partial spa day. She sampled dips and listened to product spiels worthy of their own infomercial. Me, I just walked around taking pictures and sending them to Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;![Framed 2][2]The home show was at the Fort Worth Convention Center. There were two other groups using the facilities on the same weekend. One was a conference for some MLM product, Lumi. They had high-dollar BMW&amp;rsquo;s parked out front and were giving the attendees rides. I presume that these are some sort of incentive that you can theoretically attain if you sign up enough people underneath you. Also at the convention center was a &lt;a href=&#34;http://dfw.cbslocal.com/2013/03/15/bigfoot-hunters-gather-in-fort-worth-this-weekend/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;BigFoot conference&lt;/a&gt;. Tempting, but we had a whisky tasting and distillery tour to attend!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-thumbnail wp-image-2336&#34; src=&#34;{{ Site.BaseURL }}/images/2013/03/Whiskey-Distillery-20.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Whiskey Distillery 20&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, Texas has a bourbon whiskey distillery! The first one in north Texas, one of very few outside ofKentucky. They describe themselves as &amp;lsquo;artisan&amp;rsquo; and we really enjoyed the tour. Currently the only product available is a blended whiskey. I&amp;rsquo;m not a big fan of straight whiskey so I can&amp;rsquo;t comment intelligently on the taste, which each tour participant was given. They are also barreling TONS of bourbon, which will be aged for two years. I think the first bottling will be in late 2013 or early 2014.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s all for now &amp;ndash; enjoy the pics!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; src=&#34;{{ Site.BaseURL }}/images/2013/03/Home-Show-22-Version-2.jpg&#34; class=&#34;attachment-thumbnail&#34; alt=&#34;Framed&#34; aria-describedby=&#34;gallery-1-2329&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; src=&#34;{{ Site.BaseURL }}/images/2013/03/Home-Show-24-Version-2.jpg&#34; class=&#34;attachment-thumbnail&#34; alt=&#34;Framed 2&#34; aria-describedby=&#34;gallery-1-2330&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;375&#34; height=&#34;500&#34; src=&#34;{{ Site.BaseURL }}/images/2013/03/Home-Show-29-Version-2.jpg&#34; class=&#34;attachment-thumbnail&#34; alt=&#34;Special Guest: Chewbacca&#34; aria-describedby=&#34;gallery-1-2331&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[1]: {{ Site.BaseURL }}/images/2013/03/Home-Show-18.jpg
 [2]: {{ Site.BaseURL }}/images/2013/03/Home-Show-29-Version-2.jpg&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back in Texas for a Bit</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/back-in-texas-for-a-bit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/back-in-texas-for-a-bit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So after we left Belize we flew back to Texas. We are here visiting friends and family for a bit, and trying to finish up some projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dixie is doing a lot of homework in preparation for her TEFL certificate so that she can teach English somewhere. She is thinking that it will be nice to have a reason to get out of the casa, meet new people and make a little money at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Glenn is still working on our first book, and is also working on a major site overhaul (you may have noticed some things changing around here) and thinks he may have come up with a new way of telling our stories that we hope you will enjoy. Here is a little sample for you from a recent weekend with some friends &amp;ndash; hope you enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://vagabondians.jux.com/2013texas/1066740/&#34;&gt;A Taste of Texas&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[1]: {{ Site.BaseURL }}/images/2013/03/Whiskey-Distillery-25.jpg&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Well We&#39;re Leavin&#39; on a Jet Plane…</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/leavin-jet-plane/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/leavin-jet-plane/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;We’ve been so busy over the last few months that I don’t think I’ve had the chance for all of this to sink in yet. Living in a ‘foreign’ country for a few months really isn’t that earth-shattering. Millions have done it before, and millions will do it in the future. I try to look at it that way. However, if you add the fact that we will continue to do this for the foreseeable future, with only occasional trips back home, our adventure becomes much more unusual!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we flew from DFW to LAX in Los Angeles, and then on to the Guadalajara airport, I made some notes. Here they are, rather unfiltered, a bit of a raw travelogue, as it were. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;so-far-so-good:d6fdfb7bd1d09d497288a33ebd861d76&#34;&gt;So far, so good!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On board the plane, waiting for everyone else to board. Busy flight. PACKED! The last people getting on right now are being forced to take their overhead bags to the back, or they are having to scour the bins for a spot where they can cram their bag in somewhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having given up our phones and having cancelled our cell data plan with Millenicom, I miss being able to pop in to Facebook and say silly things like “Hey, we’re getting on the plane now!” I’m not sure &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; the world will live without my live play-by-play commentary of such momentous occasions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright&#34; style=&#34;margin: 5px;&#34; title=&#34;I&#39;ve looked at rainbows from both sides now&#34; src=&#34;https://fbcdn-sphotos-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash4/420901_10151301707525437_648515436_22943658_1789912786_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;272&#34; height=&#34;363&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The weather forecast was for scattered showers and a potential for thunderstorms, but it looks like we managed to luck out so far, at least on the D/FW Airport end of things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last few stragglers are wandering around in the aisle, to the point where an attendant announced something to the effect of “We’re ready to go to Los Angeles, just as soon as you idiots in the aisle will sit down!” The last one seems to be a problem child – “UHRL crew” on her t-shirt. I’m lookin&amp;rsquo; that one up later!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also had someone who evidently got on board without properly checking in. The attendant announced “Would the passenger in 25B please identify yourself by using the call button.” They asked a second time. I swear they said the passenger name was Atta. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;WTF???&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Finally an attendant had to come back and talk to them. He took their boarding pass up front, and evidently everything was fine. No Air Marshall was called upon. &lt;em&gt;Whew!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So as soon as we got in the air we were above the fog bank lying on top of the D/FW Metromess. We’ve passed a few storm tops, but nothing severe so far (15 minutes in) and only occasional minor turbulence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignleft&#34; style=&#34;margin: 5px;&#34; title=&#34;clouds from above&#34; src=&#34;https://fbcdn-sphotos-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash4/403001_10151301707975437_648515436_22943660_406038730_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;285&#34; height=&#34;381&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just had to scold Dixie. They announced that the movie was starting, so we plugged in our earbuds. We got a short preview, then a blank screen for several seconds. Dixie said “They hijacked the movie!” entirely too loud. I pointed out that she might not want to say the word ‘hijack’ on an airplane…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So – the movie was “&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Margin_Call&#34;&gt;Margin Call&lt;/a&gt;” – interesting, very slow-paced. Not sure what I think about it exactly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It feels a bit strange, this floating in the air. I’ve flown enough that it doesn’t feel new any more, but not enough that I don’t still marvel at the fact that I am 38,000 feet above sea level and looking down at mountains. That part still feels quite foreign, unnatural. I can certainly understand those who might eschew flying for ground transportation, like &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_Madden#Fear_of_flying&#34;&gt;John Madden and his infamous bus&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Guy next to me must be a Mac fanboy like myself – he put an Apple logo sticker over the Dell logo on his laptop! LOL He calls this a ‘Dapple.’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright&#34; style=&#34;margin: 5px;&#34; title=&#34;backpackin&#39; it&#34; src=&#34;https://fbcdn-sphotos-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash4/416907_10151301707790437_648515436_22943659_884868799_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;302&#34; height=&#34;403&#34; /&gt;LAX was crowded. No seats available anywhere! Finally parked against a wall like backpackers and grabbed a couple of burgers. First celebrity sighting – &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Della_Reese&#34;&gt;Della Reese&lt;/a&gt;. She came through on her scooter, an assistant in tow. Straight through to Virgin Airlines. Must be nice…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alaska Air was much more proactive than American in controlling carry-on luggage issues. They asked if they could take our overhead bags and check them for us. We ended up leaving them at the end of the entrance ramp. The main difference on this leg was the seats. Much nicer than American! For most of the flight to Guadalajara you could see the Pacific Ocean out the right-side windows, then later the Baja Peninsula. Finally made it to Guadalajara airport. Surprise of surprises, our two checked bags from LAX &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; our main checked bag from DFW all made it just fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In closing, immigration was quick and easy, customs not so much. We got ‘selected’ for an inspection. It was rather painless, didn’t take too long. We only exchanged $100 at the airport due to the poor exchange rates their, but we needed the pesos for the taxi. You pay at the booth and get a receipt. You take the receipt to the curb and only authorized cab companies will take that for payment. Our taxi driver was friendly, but he knew less English than we knew Spanish (which isn’t saying much) so there wasn’t much conversation. It was just as good, because we were tired. We forgot to print out our housesitting address/instructions so he drove with my laptop in the passenger seat. I had the instructions pulled up from an email, worked great. At long last we were deposited in front of our casa and got to meet Fiona, the housesitter we’re replacing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More initial thoughts on Mexico coming soon! [To see the entire photo album on Facebook, &lt;a title=&#34;Mexico&#34; href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/media/set/?set=a.10151301705880437.810817.648515436&amp;type=3&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S. In case you were wondering, this is the song that the title of this post refers to&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One More Week Until Mexico</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/one-more-week-until-mexico/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/one-more-week-until-mexico/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What would you do if you had only one week left in the country you were born and raised in?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know what we&amp;rsquo;re going to do &amp;ndash; work! Looks like we&amp;rsquo;ll be able to fit our stuff into our Rick Steves carry-on bags, but there are a lot of little leftover pieces and parts. So today is eBay day!  We plan on heading to Denton on Friday. Glenn will be seeing some old co-workers for the first time in a long time, and we are trying to work in a few other people as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We ended up renting a car which we&amp;rsquo;ll drop off at the airport when we are ready to depart next week. Our homeowner sent us a few car parts to take with us, so we&amp;rsquo;ll have one bag to check, which gives us a bit of extra room for miscellaneous items if we can&amp;rsquo;t fit them in the overhead bags. Speaking of bags&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The picture you see attached to this article is from 2008. We packed for our trip to Mexico using two bags each. One overhead, one under the seat. All carry-on, no checked bags. This time we&amp;rsquo;re doing the same thing (not counting the checked bag of car parts) but there is one major difference between now and 2008 &amp;#8212; this time we&amp;rsquo;re not going for ten days, we&amp;rsquo;re going for several months! Basically, this is everything we own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OK, enough chit-chat &amp;ndash; time to get busy!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anywhere in Texas, RFD</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/texas-rfd/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/texas-rfd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sorry, I just really, REALLY love that old Louis Prima song.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And yes, we&amp;rsquo;re back in Texas! I sometimes forget that not everyone is following along via Facebook and Twitter. But you really should! That is where you get the latest updates, the minutiae.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously I have not been very good at keeping up with the photos and travel tales. So many to do! But I have some ideas rattling around in my head about how to catch up and keep up, and we&amp;rsquo;re gonna need it! Oh my, the plans we have&amp;hellip;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, as I think you probably already know, we are planning on staying here for a couple of months. We will see my parents and brother, and we have lots of friends to reunite with and catch up on. Dixie is already planning a weekend with her bestest friend in the world for her friend&amp;rsquo;s birthday. Big girls&amp;rsquo; night out with the Jazzercise gang too. We also have friends everywhere from south Arlington to Denton to see again. Wine Squared, I&amp;rsquo;m thinking of you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then there&amp;rsquo;s the work part. We&amp;rsquo;ve emptied the pop-up, now we need to clean and sell it. We also have lots of camping crap to sell, and eventually we&amp;rsquo;ll sell the SUV too. And then we hop on a plane with a one-way ticket to&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, that&amp;rsquo;s a good question, isn&amp;rsquo;t it? Frankly it all depends. One part of our overall plan that has changed a little bit is that we are going to further increase our fun factor while reducing our expenses by housesitting! And so our next destination really depends on which housesitting opportunities work out first. Maybe Lake Chapala in central Mexico? And we probably have something lined up for Costa Rica in July or August. We get to use someone&amp;rsquo;s house, and they don&amp;rsquo;t have to worry about the house looking vacant. Pets get fed and walked, lawns get watered. It&amp;rsquo;s a win-win!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that&amp;rsquo;s all for now, stay tuned for updates!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And for those unfamiliar check out the amazing Louis Prima and his crazy &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0013AJBK6/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B0013AJBK6&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=selfservehost-20&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Anywhere In Texas, RFD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amarillo -- May 1 and 2</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/amarillo-1-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/amarillo-1-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After escaping the rain in Lawton and the scary lady with a hammer, we stopped for a couple of days of work in Amarillo at the La Quinta East. I wrote stuff, Dixie wrote stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While we were there someone posted a picture of a ridiculous looking plane that was supposedly at the Amarillo Airport. Steve Miller said it should still be there, so we took a break to go see it. And there it was! Twice as tall as Southwest Airlines&amp;rsquo; 737&amp;rsquo;s. Very odd looking. No wonder they call it the Flying Guppy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/PBkMAQD.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Guppy vs. 737&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seems that NASA acquired this thing to haul things around, like pieces of space shuttle or, in this case, a Bell Osprey. The nose of the plane swings to the right like a door, then you slide stuff inside. Strange, but true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I was there I noticed another car pull up behind ours and the driver appeared to be writing down our temporary tag numbers. I wandered back over there and the driver asked what I was doing. I looked back at the plane, looked at him, looked back at the plane and pointed at it and said &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s a flying guppy!&amp;rdquo; He acted like this was no big deal. I asked him who he was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m Floyd.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I should have just laughed. Instead I said &amp;ldquo;Oh&amp;rdquo; and just walked back to take more pictures. I kinda thought he might have been with the FAA or the airport, but no, he&amp;rsquo;s just an idiot who thought he had caught the next al Qaeda plot in action. Targeting the flying guppy. In Amarillo. What a maroon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I got photos of the plane, we discovered what appeared to be an old abandoned terminal building. The sign said &amp;ldquo;English Field.&amp;rdquo; After taking several photos we drove to the east side of the airport and discovered what appeared to be an old military complex. Large water towers with the typical checkered paint job, now fading. Lots of streets and curbs but very few buildings left. I took a lot more pictures, and we enjoyed some of the wildlife that now occupies this area, mainly jackrabbits and birds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/ZhQW4mp.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Rabbits everywhere!&#34; /&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/xBHdP4M.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Swallow swarm&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After we got back to the hotel I Googled it and discovered that English Field was the commercial airport back in the day, and that the runways now being used by Amarillo International used to be part of an Army Air Field started up back in World War II. Since then thousands of jet crew and mechanics were trained there, the B-17 Flying Fortress flew out of there, and it also used to be a SAC base and boot camp. All the military stuff is long gone, but the runways make it ideal for things like space shuttles and flying guppies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/AwFBNaZ.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Abandoned terminal&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day we met an old friend and storm-chasing buddy Steve Miller for lunch. We ended up spending 3-4 hours getting caught up on self-employment, love lives and storm chasing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the full photo album:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;imgur-embed-pub&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34; data-id=&#34;a/9703M&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;//imgur.com/a/9703M&#34;&gt;View post on imgur.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//s.imgur.com/min/embed.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Us vs. Mother Nature</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/vs-mother-nature/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/vs-mother-nature/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But Mousie, thou art no thy lane,&lt;br /&gt;
In proving foresight may be vain:&lt;br /&gt;
The best-laid schemes o&amp;rsquo; mice an&amp;rsquo; men&lt;br /&gt;
Gang aft agley,&lt;br /&gt;
An&amp;rsquo; lea&amp;rsquo;e us nought but grief an&amp;rsquo; pain,&lt;br /&gt;
For promis&amp;rsquo;d joy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;To a Mouse&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; Robert Burns &amp;ndash; 1785&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our first &amp;lsquo;detour&amp;rsquo; was not due to construction but due to time.  We attempted to do a wee bit too much all at once.  That is how we ended up spending a couple of weeks with my parents before finally driving off.  That is also how we ended up spending an additional week finding a larger vehicle to trade our car for!  But at long last we took off and started our journey with a week or two of storm-chasing.  Unfortunately for us (and a lot of other people) this year&amp;rsquo;s weather pattern is much cooler and wetter than normal, at least in the eastern part of the United States.  And that brings about our second detour!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our initial planned route had us chasing a bit and then driving through the upper midwest to Ohio and Michigan.  Unfortunately the entire Mississippi and Ohio River basins and surrounding areas are all at record flood levels! (see maps below) Many campgrounds are flooded and closed.  And while we might still be able to find places to stay, who wants to camp outside when storm after storm keeps blowing through?  Not us, no thanks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we finally gave up on chasing storms through the piney woods of East Texas and parked ourselves in the Wichita Mountains National Wildlife Refuge for a few days.  It was very windy but sunny and not too cold.  No wildfires broke out while we were there, and we spent a few days hiking and thinking.  And one thing we have concluded is that to avoid further trip delays and miserable camping we will need to change our travel plans and follow our planned route in reverse!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After walking through our plans and doing a bit of analysis we think we can still achieve our main goals without getting caught in drastic summer desert heat or mountain snows.  And as if to reinforce our decision, mother nature brought another round of rain including southwest Oklahoma!  Fortunately I saw this coming in the weather forecast and we skedaddled on over to Amarillo for a few days.  We&amp;rsquo;ll stay just long enough to wait out tonight&amp;rsquo;s cold snap and then mosey on over to southern New Mexico.  Hopefully this time we can find some place to camp that gets at least one bar of Verizon data service!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;attachment_2935&#34; style=&#34;width: 679px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption alignleft&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://vagabondians.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/USA-Flood-Conditions.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-full wp-image-2935&#34; src=&#34;http://vagabondians.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/USA-Flood-Conditions.png&#34; alt=&#34;USA-Flood-Conditions&#34; width=&#34;669&#34; height=&#34;373&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;
    Current water flow measuring stations at or above flood stage
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;attachment_2901&#34; style=&#34;width: 675px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption alignleft&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://vagabondians.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/Original-Route.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-full wp-image-2901&#34; src=&#34;http://vagabondians.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/Original-Route.png&#34; alt=&#34;Original-Route&#34; width=&#34;665&#34; height=&#34;365&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;
    Our original route starting in Texas -- see the problem?
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Still Homeless, But Living in an SUV</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/still-homeless-but-living-in-an-suv/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/still-homeless-but-living-in-an-suv/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently we wrote about [escaping the system][1] and some of the difficulties we&amp;rsquo;ve faced.  One obstacle that we faced was simply time itself.  Late last year we began fine-tuning our strategy and a target time-frame for quitting our jobs.  Eventually we settled on late March.  We drew up a timeline and marked off all of the things we needed to do by that date.  Initially this included purchasing and moving into a travel trailer.  We eventually decided against that, which had both positive and negative results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main reason for dropping the trailer idea was that we decided to start traveling overseas sooner.  The expense and hassle of a trailer doesn&amp;rsquo;t make sense for a seven month journey, but ditching the trailer had some unexpected consequences.  One thing we had not fully appreciated was just how much room even a mid-sized trailer has.  Moving from 750 square feet to less than 200 sounds challenging, but it is nothing compared to moving into a passenger sedan!  The Hyundai Sonata has an amazing amount of cargo space, and Glenn is quite the packing genius, but we were still discarding items up until the very last minute.  Rear-view visibility was minimal but workable.  But the one thing we didn&amp;rsquo;t even consider was weight!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After spending a wonderful evening at a bed and breakfast we scooted off to Denton to deliver a gun and some proofreading work in exchange for money.  But on the drive up a couple of things became obvious.  First, the rear suspension in the Sonata was almost fully compressed.  Minor dips on the highway caused it to bottom out with a slightly disconcerting dull thunk.  And with the bulk of the weight behind the rear axle, the front end was raised slightly and this caused a lot of extra sway.  We foolishly believed that all we needed was some beefier suspension, but in fact no one makes those for sedans.  And why would they?  Sedans have weight limits that kick in regardless of how low the vehicle rides, and we were probably over that limit.  The solution to this dilemma slowly dawned on us.  We needed a bigger vehicle!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems pretty obvious now, in retrospect, but it took some time for us to reach this conclusion.  We&amp;rsquo;re stubborn like that sometimes.  We didn&amp;rsquo;t want any extra delays or expenses, but there is just no way that car was going to make it over the Rocky Mountains and through the deserts for 9,000 miles.  So we began the search for a compact SUV.  We initially targeted the Hyundai Santa Fe for cargo space, cost and familiarity reasons.  Trips to west Dallas and Denton proved fruitless.  We did get a nice deal on a Mercedes but decided to pass on it due to the finicky and costly maintenance issues.  Finally we found a Mitsubishi Montero Sport at a fancy-shmancy luxury sports car dealership near the Addison Airport.  The manager/owner is Arwaan, and he and most of the employees appeared to all be from Pakistan.  The Montero was a trade-in, and it was pretty much just what we needed.  They gave us a fair trade-in offer and Arwaan pointed out that it would have been more if our speedometer still worked.  He also pointed out that we would pay much less on taxes since the end result was a purchase price of only $2000.  They got it inspected and changed the oil and we proceeded to fill up the cargo bay while the heat reached 92.  Glenn almost got heat stroke while Dixie was lining up the insurance over the phone.  But soon all of our possessions were in the back of the Montero, and we came to some startling realizations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first realization was that we still have a lot of stuff!  The fact that we filled up the cargo area and still had difficulty maintaining rear-view mirror visibility was sobering.  The second realization was that the Sonata has a crazy amount of cargo space!  The Montero has more, but if you want to see out of the windows it doesn&amp;rsquo;t have &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; much more than the Sonata.  But we also knew that we could take our time and repack in cooler weather and probably make things fit better.  So we did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also replaced the nearly bald rear tires with new ones that match the front tires.  The front tires were fairly new, so now we are all set for a road trip.  Glenn also cleaned the glaze off of the headlights and cleaned the interior a bit and replaced the air filter.  Everything else seems to work fine.  So we&amp;rsquo;re almost ready to go, finally!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In one sense, it seems obvious that we would need something as big as an SUV to do what we are doing.  But considering all of the things we have done this year, from selling most of our possessions to selling two vehicles to quitting our jobs to moving out of an apartment &amp;#8212; well, we were bound to miss a thing or two.  And we did!  We probably should have included more transition time in our initial plans.  It is frustrating to still be here in Texas when by now we were expecting to be traversing the plains in search of the elusive tornado.  But our original timeline was probably a bit optimistic, so we&amp;rsquo;re not going to beat ourselves up over it.  We still have one more issue that we need to resolve that is partially preventing us from traveling too far, and we will write about that in greater detail in the near future&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[1]: {{ Site.BaseURL }}/escaping-system&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>