<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Washington on Vagabondians</title>
    <link>http://vagabondians.com/tags/washington/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Washington on Vagabondians</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright &amp;#169; by Glenn and Dixie Dixon</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://vagabondians.com/tags/washington/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Washington to Montana</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/washington-montana/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/washington-montana/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We finally bid farewell to Rand and Angie and packed up for our departure from Seattle. Before we actually hit the road, we borrowed some caulk from the garage and recaulked the main seam down the middle of the roof. It had developed a small hole and water tended to puddle right near this hole. Fortunately we have experienced almost no rain on the entire trip so far!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; title=&#34;This is how Glenn does roof repair!&#34; src=&#34;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-aR-zTcfqnH8/TmexY-34xZI/AAAAAAAABrc/9mwUaHNywkc/s640/P1150047.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;507&#34; height=&#34;381&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We drove south and then east on I-90. After passing through the Cascades we entered the great Columbia Plateau, a large depression where so much of the earth&amp;rsquo;s mantle flooded out in great lava flows that the crust eventually collapsed downward. A massive earth-scale turning of the soil, if you will. It is now a semi-arid savanna full of grasses and shrubs. I was a bit surprised as it reminded me of parts of New Mexico. Not exactly what I was expecting in the great Pacific Northwest!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We crossed the Columbia River at a small lake created by the Wanapum dam near Vantage. Shortly after our crossing, we took a scenic turnout and snapped a few pictures of the river below. A bonus was the wild horse sculpture on a nearby hillside! We stayed one night in an RV park near Moses Lake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; title=&#34;Vantage Bridge on I-90&#34; src=&#34;https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-rUOv9gAaoxY/TmexdJql8iI/AAAAAAAABro/Z1FGnzaBUy4/s640/P1150068.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;518&#34; height=&#34;389&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; title=&#34;Horse sculpture&#34; src=&#34;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-bNcZZNlh5BQ/TmexfSsuETI/AAAAAAAABrw/zqWtS7VCtOc/s640/P1150075.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;512&#34; height=&#34;384&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next morning we packed again and took off, stopping after only 17 miles in Moses Lake itself. We got gas and breakfast, and upon returning to the vehicle I noticed that I had left the AC power adapter for the Coleman cooler on top of the Montero. Oops! Somehow it had managed to stay put. Disaster averted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; title=&#34;oops&#34; src=&#34;https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-MsqS7mtOiJ0/Tmexg5bN8wI/AAAAAAAABpA/3XeUGHEMhtQ/s640/IMG_0544.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;512&#34; height=&#34;384&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eastern Washington had another surprise for us, dust devils! And unlike most of these we typically see in Texas or New Mexico, these were tall rope-like funnels. They were very reminiscent of landspouts, just without the clouds above. At one point we saw several of these all in one area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; title=&#34;Dust devil&#34; src=&#34;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-lH8nnWgVi2M/TmexjJaz1FI/AAAAAAAABr4/d8ZK-zEQBtw/s512/P1150081.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;384&#34; height=&#34;512&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Spokane we stopped to see someone whom I only knew only from the internet. Gregg Thurman was someone who introduced me to investing in options. He trades almost exclusively in Apple stock, so we share an interest in both investing and Mac gear. We stopped by his antique car restoration shop and he gave us a tour of his wonderful old cars, and his project Mustang/GT, as well as his awesome Ford GT, one of only 4000 ever made. We&amp;rsquo;re both talkers, so Dixie ended up wandering around and taking pictures. We only stayed for a couple of hours and then took off to the east since our destination for the night was in Montana!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; title=&#34;Dixie inspecting an antique&#34; src=&#34;https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-z7eqf5IdH1I/TmexmWhdEuI/AAAAAAAABsE/C09TpuOSw78/s640/P1150095.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;512&#34; height=&#34;384&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; title=&#34;Packard Clipper&#34; src=&#34;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-fySjTKtFQk0/Tmexse0KdzI/AAAAAAAABsc/I3gZIUb3rno/s640/P1150111.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;512&#34; height=&#34;384&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; title=&#34;Gregg and Glenn chatting&#34; src=&#34;https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-HktwjwH4saY/Tmex0_ff7cI/AAAAAAAABs4/h_zIZ5Gf_f8/s640/P1150125.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;512&#34; height=&#34;384&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; title=&#34;Ford GT&#34; src=&#34;https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-0I6AuuXdkgs/Tmex3mAisTI/AAAAAAAABtA/2lqFzGc2Iks/s640/P1150133.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;512&#34; height=&#34;384&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; title=&#34;Rear engine, with braces signed by many Ford motor sports luminaries&#34; src=&#34;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-limfW5iJdsY/Tmex8K6_NGI/AAAAAAAABtM/pKq8xSQ0oUM/s640/P1150143.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;512&#34; height=&#34;384&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, Idaho had other plans for us. We managed to bypass a big traffic jam in Spokane by visiting Gregg, but while we were in Idaho, just after going through the 4th of July pass, we ourselves were passed by three different State Troopers in a big hurry. Unfortunately the 4th of July Pass is also the last exit for six miles. Soon we passed a trooper setting out flares on the shoulder, lights flashing. And then we stopped. Eventually Dixie went walking down the road, rounding two curves, but she still couldn&amp;rsquo;t see what was stopping traffic up ahead. The word being passed back through the truckers was that a big rig had caught on fire. Great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; title=&#34;0 mph on I-90&#34; src=&#34;https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-xtBvPerBSJQ/TmeyD9qWwHI/AAAAAAAABrQ/ls1ph2QqyO8/s640/P1150207.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;512&#34; height=&#34;384&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the next hour we saw ambulances and wreckers come and go, and eventually we were moving again, slowly. Hope the driver got out in time!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; title=&#34;Looks like the entire cab behind the driver burned up&#34; src=&#34;https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-D0JqpgLsdLY/TmeyEz0yyjI/AAAAAAAABrU/WQu2R-enXgE/s640/P1150209.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;512&#34; height=&#34;384&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were obviously much later getting in to camp than we had anticipated. We had no cell phone service so I didn&amp;rsquo;t get the voice mail when the RV park tried to call us, but I later found Google Voice&amp;rsquo;s attempt to transcribe it! LOL&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; title=&#34;What kind of park???&#34; src=&#34;https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-cATaROyARC0/TmeyGrk06kI/AAAAAAAABrA/M5qe073RLKQ/IMG_0545.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; height=&#34;480&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately we made it in long before they closed the gates at 10PM. I was tired enough that we even stayed an extra night, just to recuperate. But we made it to Montana!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click the picture below to see the entire photo album!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table style=&#34;width: 194px;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td style=&#34;height: 194px; background: url(&#39;https://picasaweb.google.com/s/c/transparent_album_background.gif&#39;) no-repeat left;&#34; align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
      &lt;a href=&#34;https://picasaweb.google.com/dixonge/Washington?authuser=0&amp;feat=embedwebsite&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;margin: 1px 0 0 4px;&#34; src=&#34;https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-Kmur-ZrJODo/TmexXoCwdRE/AAAAAAAABv0/RfxPo62--q4/s160-c/Washington.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;160&#34; height=&#34;160&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: center; font-family: arial,sans-serif; font-size: 11px;&#34;&gt;
      &lt;a style=&#34;color: #4d4d4d; font-weight: bold; text-decoration: none;&#34; href=&#34;https://picasaweb.google.com/dixonge/Washington?authuser=0&amp;feat=embedwebsite&#34;&gt;Washington&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seattle</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/seattle/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/seattle/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On August 10th we departed from the Mt. St. Helens area and drove north to Seattle. It was our first time here, and our first time to see our old friends Angie and Rand in their home. We backed in to their driveway and set up the trailer which fit perfectly behind their gate. Urban incognito.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While we were there we spent most evenings enjoying some fine dining. Rand even prepared his infamous pizza made from scratch twice! We also enjoyed some wine most evenings, as best I can remember. I still blame Rand for that one night, no matter what Angie says! &lt;img src=&#34;http://v2j.vagabondians.com/wp-includes/images/smilies/simple-smile.png&#34; alt=&#34;:)&#34; class=&#34;wp-smiley&#34; style=&#34;height: 1em; max-height: 1em;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also did some sightseeing. Rand took us to a nice spot with a great view of the bay and city. He also took us to see the troll! No, seriously, a troll. Big sculpture under a bridge. I&amp;rsquo;m still not really sure why someone would create such a thing, but it seemed to be a popular spot! And of course we went downtown to the Public Market, the famous place where people out in front of the fish stands take orders and toss them back to the guys behind the counter. For every one person placing an order, there are a hundred tourists standing around with their cameras waiting to get a picture. I was one of &amp;lsquo;em.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=273114556038705&amp;amp;#038;set=a.273113942705433.89527.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=273114556038705&amp;amp;#038;set=a.273113942705433.89527.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=273113996038761&amp;amp;#038;set=a.273113942705433.89527.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=273113996038761&amp;amp;#038;set=a.273113942705433.89527.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=273115096038651&amp;amp;#038;set=a.273113942705433.89527.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=273115096038651&amp;amp;#038;set=a.273113942705433.89527.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also got to do something a bit out of the ordinary, an underground tour! We followed our tour guide through a maze of alleys and basements, exploring what was the original street level before the city raised the streets several feet. Bank vaults, massage parlors, brothels, wooden sewage pipes, speakeasies&amp;hellip;in other words, all the cool places to hang out! It was all there. Very entertaining and interesting!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; title=&#34;Seattle Underground tour&#34; src=&#34;https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-tnA7IRaztmg/TmUtWuy3k7I/AAAAAAAABl4/uWjxtTuxO4M/s912/P1150007.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;912&#34; height=&#34;513&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=273115316038629&amp;amp;#038;set=a.273113942705433.89527.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=273115316038629&amp;amp;#038;set=a.273113942705433.89527.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mt. St. Helens</title>
      <link>http://vagabondians.com/post/mt-st-helens/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vagabondians.com/post/mt-st-helens/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mount St. Helens was not on my original list of things to do or see in Washington. But as things turned out, it was a good stopping point on the way to Seattle. So hey, why not, right? I mean, it&amp;rsquo;s a huge frickin&amp;rsquo; volcano! So we parked for a couple of nights at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.silvercovervresort.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Silver Cove RV Resort&lt;/a&gt; and took a day trip in to the Mount St. Helens National Volcanic Monument.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=271218176228343&amp;amp;#038;set=a.271218136228347.89161.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=271218176228343&amp;amp;#038;set=a.271218136228347.89161.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main visitors center is at the Johnston Ridge Observatory. In May of 1980, this was just another ridge, known as &amp;lsquo;Coldwater II,&amp;rsquo; and was being used by scientists to monitor the mountain, which had seen increasing seismic activity and steam-driven explosions. The location was 5.5 miles from the mountain, and was thought to be a relatively safe distance. David Johnston was stationed here for the USGS on May 18. At Spirit Lake, two amateur volcanologists had stayed behind at their own risk to take readings, and a local resident Harry Truman had refused to leave his Mt. St. Helens lodge on the edge of the lake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=271218279561666&amp;amp;#038;set=a.271218136228347.89161.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=271218279561666&amp;amp;#038;set=a.271218136228347.89161.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On May 17, a convoy of 35 frustrated homeowners were escorted into the restricted zone to gather personal belongings. Another such convoy was scheduled for the next day at 10AM. On May 18 at 8:32AM a 5.1 magnitude earthquake happened one mile under the mountain. David Johnston saw the northern face of Mt. St. Helens, which had been bulging for several days, simply collapse. 1,300 feet of the mountain plunged into the valley below, the largest landslide in recorded history. All snow and glacial ice melted instantly and the water mixed with rock and ash began racing towards Spirit Lake. Johnston got on the radio to the USGS in Vancouver, Washington. All they heard was &amp;ldquo;Vancouver! Vancouver! This is it!&amp;rdquo; Rock, ash and trees hit his position at over 500mph. His body has never been found.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two miles north of Johnston&amp;rsquo;s position, a ham radio observer named Gerry Martin saw Johnston disappear and transmitted &amp;ldquo;The camper and the car just over to the south of me are covered. It&amp;rsquo;s going to hit me too.&amp;rdquo; In all 57 people lost their lives to the blast that day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The landslide released the trapped gas which resulted in a huge explosion that flattened every tree within a 230 square mile area in 180 seconds. The flow of debris hit Spirit Lake and forced all of the water up into the hillsides. By the time the water returned, the new bottom of the lake was actually 100 feet higher than the previous lake&amp;rsquo;s surface! To this day it still has no fish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A 25-foot wall of debris, the bulk of the initial landslide, raced down the Toutle River. It destroyed 27 bridges on its way down to the Columbia River, 75 miles away. The normally 40-foot deep channel there was reduced to 17 feet and had to be dredged just to reopen normal shipping lanes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On our visit, we watched the movie at the visitors center and took a guided tour. Young Ranger Kelly was an excellent guide. Even though she was born eleven years after the eruption, she lost four relatives that day. The mountain has always fascinated her and obviously motivated her to study and learn about it. I guess by being up here for work and walking around every day, by being near the mountain, she feels closer to those who have gone on before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=271218612894966&amp;amp;#038;set=a.271218136228347.89161.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=271218612894966&amp;amp;#038;set=a.271218136228347.89161.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hiked the trail to a better view of Spirit Lake, then returned to our car. Like so many things on this trip, you simply can not comprehend the scale of the devastation and the beauty of the mountain without seeing it in person. We really enjoyed this little side trip!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=271218769561617&amp;amp;#038;set=a.271218136228347.89161.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=271218769561617&amp;amp;#038;set=a.271218136228347.89161.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=271218919561602&amp;amp;#038;set=a.271218136228347.89161.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=271218919561602&amp;amp;#038;set=a.271218136228347.89161.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&amp;amp;#038;theater&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a wonderful overview and lots of pictures of the Mt. St. Helens eruption and victims and survivors, check out the web site of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.columbian.com/news/mount-st-helens/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Daily Columbian&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/media/set/?set=a.271218136228347.89161.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&#34;&gt;http://www.facebook.com/media/set/?set=a.271218136228347.89161.197146780302150&amp;amp;#038;type=1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>